<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.3 20210610//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-3-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" dtd-version="1.3" xml:lang="EN" article-type="rapid-communication"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//ACS//DTD ACS Journal DTD v1.02 20061031//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName ACSJournal-v102.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 1.02?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName acs2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">ACS Energy Lett</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">ACS Energy Lett</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">nz</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="coden">aelccp</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>ACS Energy Letters</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2380-8195</issn><publisher><publisher-name>American Chemical Society</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta>
<article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">11555676</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02019</article-id><article-categories><subj-group><subject>Letter</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>SEI Formation
and Lithium-Ion Electrodeposition Dynamics
in Lithium Metal Batteries via First-Principles Kinetic Monte Carlo
Modeling</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath1"><name><surname>Perez-Beltran</surname><given-names>Saul</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath2"><name><surname>Kuai</surname><given-names>Dacheng</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">&#x02021;</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes" id="ath3"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="true">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-2358-3910</contrib-id><name><surname>Balbuena</surname><given-names>Perla B.</given-names></name><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="other">*</xref><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">&#x02020;</xref><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">&#x02021;</xref><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">&#x000a7;</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>&#x02020;</label>Department
of Chemical Engineering, <institution>Texas A&#x00026;M University</institution>, College Station, Texas 77843, <country>United States</country></aff><aff id="aff2"><label>&#x02021;</label>Department
of Chemistry, <institution>Texas A&#x00026;M University</institution>, College Station, Texas 77843, <country>United States</country></aff><aff id="aff3"><label>&#x000a7;</label>Department
of Materials Science and Engineering, <institution>Texas
A&#x00026;M University</institution>, College Station, Texas 77843, <country>United States</country></aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>*</label><email>balbuena@mail.che.tamu.edu</email>.</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>07</day><month>10</month><year>2024</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>08</day><month>11</month><year>2024</year></pub-date><volume>9</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>5268</fpage><lpage>5278</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>25</day><month>07</month><year>2024</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>03</day><month>10</month><year>2024</year></date><date date-type="rev-recd"><day>28</day><month>09</month><year>2024</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; 2024 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2024</copyright-year><copyright-holder>The Authors</copyright-holder><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>Permits the broadest form of re-use including for commercial purposes, provided that author attribution and integrity are maintained (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>).</license-p></license></permissions><abstract><p content-type="toc-graphic"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_0006" id="ab-tgr1"/></p><p>The stabilization and enhanced performance of lithium
metal batteries
(LMBs) depend on the formation and evolution of the Solid Electrolyte
Interphase (SEI) layer as a critical component for regulating the
Li metal electrodeposition processes. This study employs a first-principles
kinetic Monte Carlo (kMC) model to simulate the SEI formation and
Li<sup>+</sup> electrodeposition processes on a lithium metal anode,
integrating both the electrochemical electrolyte reduction reactions
and the diffusion events giving place to the SEI aggregation processes
during battery charge and discharge processes. The model replicates
the competitive interactions between organic and inorganic SEI components,
emphasizing the influence of the cycling regime. Results indicate
that grain boundaries within the SEI facilitate faster lithium-ion
transport compared to crystalline regions, crucial for improving the
performance and stability of LMBs. The findings underscore the importance
of dynamic SEI modeling for further development of next-generation
high-energy-density batteries.</p></abstract><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution>Vehicle Technologies Office</institution><institution-id institution-id-type="doi">10.13039/100011884</institution-id></institution-wrap></funding-source><award-id>DE-AC05-76RL01830</award-id></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-old-9</meta-name><meta-value>nz4c02019</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>document-id-new-14</meta-name><meta-value>nz4c02019</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>ccc-price</meta-name><meta-value/></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><p id="sec1">There is an urgent need for
further advancements in high-energy density battery technologies to
maximize the potential of renewable energies.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">1</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref></sup> In this context,
lithium metal positions itself as the best material for anode electrodes,
as it has the lowest electrochemical potential (&#x02212;3.04 V vs
standard hydrogen electrode) and provides an exceedingly high specific
capacity (3.86 Ah/g).<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref></sup> However, the mass
commercialization of lithium metal batteries (LMB) faces significant
challenges, particularly the stabilization of lithium-ion (Li<sup>+</sup>) electrodeposition and diffusion processes that occur within
the passivation layer known as the Solid Electrolyte Interphase (SEI),<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">4</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">6</xref></sup> which inevitably forms at the lithium metal&#x02013;electrolyte interface
due to the instability of current electrolyte formulations at the
potentials at which lithium metal anodes operate.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">7</xref></sup></p><p>The engineering of the SEI aims for a chemically
and mechanically
stable, elastic, self-healing, and electronic insulating layer with
high Li<sup>+</sup> conductivity that ensures high Coulombic efficiency.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref></sup> A typical SEI is formed from a mix of organic
and inorganic compounds derived from a self-limited electrolyte decomposition
process during the initial cycles of the battery. To achieve this,
the current dominant strategy leverages on the lessons learned from
Li-ion batteries to come up with innovative electrolyte formulations
that help tune the properties of the SEI layer.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref></sup> This approach has led to the development of high concentration
electrolytes (HCEs), localized high concentration electrolytes (LHCEs),
and electrolytes with fluorinated solvents, among others.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref></sup> The enhanced salt coordination with Li<sup>+</sup> ions in HCE electrolytes
produces an inorganic-rich anion-derived SEI with suppressed dendrite
formation through reduced solvent reactivity and a broader electrochemical
stability window,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">14</xref></sup> while LHCEs combine
the benefits of HCEs with reduced viscosity and better interfacial
stability.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">15</xref></sup> Still, these electrolyte formulations
face compatibility issues with high-voltage spinel LNMO electrodes,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">16</xref></sup> encounter safety challenges,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">17</xref></sup> and are potentially expensive due to the higher salt concentrations
and/or specialized additives required. On the other hand, solvent
fluorination allows for a flame-retardant, single-solvent, low-concentration
electrolyte formulation with improved oxidative stability. This promotes
the formation of a thermally stable, LiF-enriched SEI layer with high
Li<sup>+</sup> conductivity.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">18</xref></sup> However,
the elevated ionic diffusion energy barrier in LiF (0.71 eV) does
not correlate with the high Li<sup>+</sup> conductivity observed in
LiF-enriched SEI layers,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref></sup> which has sparked
an ongoing debate on the Li<sup>+</sup> mobility mechanisms in the
SEI. Some authors suggest that grain boundaries between disparate
inorganic SEI phases, such as LiF and Li<sub>2</sub>O, play a key
role in enhancing Li<sup>+</sup> transport, rather than diffusion
mechanisms within the bulk of the inorganic phases.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref></sup></p><p>The experimental work around the SEI properties from these
innovative
electrolyte formulations is paving the way for the eventual incorporation
of LMB batteries into the basket of commercially available energy
storage technologies.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">21</xref></sup> However, even though
experiments, especially recently developed operando techniques,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">22</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">23</xref></sup> provide descriptive insights into the chemical composition and morphology
of the SEI layer based on performance metrics, challenges remain in
identifying and understanding the Li<sup>+</sup> electrodeposition
and diffusion processes across the passivated anode&#x02019;s outermost
layer. For the most part, these processes are only quantifiable through
advanced simulation approaches.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref></sup> Here, multiscale modeling
plays a critical role. By providing detailed atomic and molecular
perspectives, predictive capabilities, and a deeper understanding
of complex interactions, multiscale modeling not only addresses the
early stage and extended SEI formation and diffusion processes but
also enhances cost and time efficiency, guides more informed experimentation,
and reduces environmental and safety risks.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref24">24</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">25</xref></sup></p><p>The set of tools available for modeling the SEI dynamics encompasses
a wide range of time and space scales. First-principles methods, such
as Density Functional Theory (DFT) and ab initio Molecular Dynamics
(AIMD), work in synergy to provide an atomic-level understanding of
the fundamental bonding interactions and reactive events involved
in the early SEI formation. These methods help elucidate the initial
chemical and electrochemical mechanisms, along with their respective
energy profiles, in systems comprising a few hundred atoms within
a time scale of 10<sup>&#x02013;10</sup> seconds.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">26</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">28</xref></sup> Other methods,
such as classical reactive molecular dynamics (ReaxFF) and even coarse-grained
molecular dynamics (CGMD), leverage the insights gained from these
first-principles approaches to produce less computationally expensive
yet accurate larger representations suitable for modeling the early
SEI evolution in simulation cells containing up to hundreds of thousands
of particles on a microseconds scale.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">29</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref31">31</xref></sup> Following the same integrative
approach, the mesoscale kinetic Monte Carlo (kMC) technique benefits
from these atom-scale methods to follow the SEI dynamics over extended
cycling conditions while keeping detailed molecular information. The
kMC method is about 10<sup>6</sup> times less computationally expensive
than AIMD and handles processes over time scales ranging from seconds
to hours,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref35">35</xref></sup> with simulation cells large enough to address the three-dimensional,
dynamic, and heterogeneous SEI structure composed of inorganic and
organic phases. Previous works from our group and others have already
addressed SEI behavior using a multiscale approach that combines density
functional theory and ab initio molecular dynamics calculations with
the kMC approach. A work focused on the lithium stripping/plating
dynamics on lithium&#x02013;copper nanoalloys,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref33">33</xref></sup> uncovered a complex relationship between the nanoalloy composition
and the properties of the formed SEI interphase. Meanwhile, other
studies examined the SEI formation on a lithium metal surface resulting
from the decomposition of a 2 M lithium hexafluorophosphate (LiPF<sub>6</sub>) solution in ethylene carbonate (EC) at open circuit conditions.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref35">35</xref></sup> This modeling effort linked diffusional and kinetic effects to the
decomposition mechanisms of LiPF<sub>6</sub> and EC, respectively,
leading to a heterogeneous SEI distribution with an innermost inorganic
lithium fluoride (LiF) layer, followed by lithium carbonate, and a
porous organic film of lithium dicarbonate exposed to the electrolyte.
Another work addressed the formation dynamics and structural trends
of the SEI interphase in Li<sup>+</sup> ion batteries using a first-principles
stochastic microkinetic model.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref36">36</xref></sup> This study
demonstrated how the composition and structure of the SEI are significantly
influenced by the applied potential and the presence of electron tunneling
barriers. It provided a detailed understanding of the competitive
reduction mechanisms that drive SEI formation, highlighting the complex
interplay between organic and inorganic components in determining
the SEI&#x02019;s properties and their impact on battery performance.</p><p>The kMC method relies on a predefined set of elementary electrochemical
reactions that encompass the various processes governing SEI evolution.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref37">37</xref></sup> The comprehensiveness of this reaction set is
crucial for accurately modeling the different stages of SEI development.
These stages include <italic>the formation stage</italic>, which leads
to the deposition of the primary SEI components; <italic>the secondary
matrix formation</italic>, that contributes to the growth and densification
of the SEI; and <italic>the ultimate failure stage</italic>, characterized
by uncontrolled SEI growth. This thickening results in electrolyte
depletion, hinders effective and evenly distributed Li<sup>+</sup> electrodeposition, and ultimately degrades battery performance.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref38">38</xref></sup></p><p>This work discusses the three-dimensional
kMC modeling of the Li<sup>+</sup> electrodeposition dynamics and
simultaneous evolution of
an SEI layer formed on a lithium metal anode upon reduction of an
electrolyte formulation <italic>LiFSI-F5DEE</italic> composed of a
1.2 M lithium bis(fluorosulfonyl)imide (LiFSI) salt dissolved in a
fluorinated ether solvent, 1-(2,2-difluoroethoxy)-2-(2,2,2-trifluoroethoxy)ethane
(F5DEE).<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref></sup> This solvent belongs to the
family of fluorinated-1,2-diethoxyethane (fluorinated-DEE) molecules,
developed by Zhenan Bao&#x02019;s research group at Stanford University
under the Battery 500 Consortium.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">10</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">13</xref></sup> These molecules
are notable for their structural tunability provided by the ethyl
terminal groups of the parent DDE molecule. This tunability allows
for selective iterative fluorination, which endows the solvent with
high ionic conductivity and improved oxidative stability due to the
remarkable electron-withdrawing capability of the fluorinated groups.
This specific system is taken as an example to demonstrate the ability
of the kMC method to characterize the complex reaction/transport phenomena
taking place at an electrode/electrolyte interface during battery
cycling. The analysis provides new insights into the effects of the
interfacial events on battery performance.</p><p>A crucial result
from one of our earlier works<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref></sup> was the
elucidation of the reaction network corresponding
to the interfacial electrochemistry of the LiFSI-F5DEE electrolyte
on the lithium metal surface (<xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref>, reactions labeled a-n and b-m with n = 1 to 8, and
m = 1 to 4). The DFT calculations showed that electron transfer from
the lithium metal to the electrolyte triggered an initial defluorination
of the LiFSI (reaction <bold>a-1</bold>) and F5DEE (reaction <bold>b-1</bold>) molecules near the interface without significant activation
energy barriers (E<sub>A,i</sub>, i = LiFSI and F5DEE<italic>)</italic>. For the extended fragmentation of LiFSI, the main reduction path
involved the S&#x02013;N bond breaking, leading to the formation of
[O=S=O]<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup><sup>&#x02013;</sup> and [O=S(=O)(F)N]<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup><sup>&#x02013;</sup> (reaction <bold>a-2</bold>). The further reduction
of the remaining LiFSI fragments occurred spontaneously with negligible
energy barriers through continuous electron transfer from the lithium
metal surface without high-spin state intermediates,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref></sup> resulting in their full decomposition into single ions
(O<sup>2</sup><sup>&#x02013;</sup>, S<sup>2</sup><sup>&#x02013;</sup>, and F<sup>&#x02013;</sup>). The breakdown of [O=S(=O)(F)N]<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup><sup>&#x02013;</sup> followed reactions <bold>a-3</bold> to <bold>a-5</bold>, while the disintegration of [O=S=O]<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">2</xref></sup><sup>&#x02013;</sup> occurred through reactions <bold>a-7</bold> and <bold>a-8</bold>. The [S&#x02013;N]<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3">3</xref></sup><sup>&#x02013;</sup> fragment is the only one with a non-negligible <inline-formula id="d34e333"><inline-graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_m001.gif"/></inline-formula> barrier, but it eventually decomposes into
its constituent elements following reaction <bold>a-6</bold>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref40">40</xref></sup></p><fig id="fig1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Reaction network path for (a) LISF and (b) F5DEE on lithium
metal,
highlighting their multiple intermediate decomposition products (salt_IDP
and solv_IDP). The figure outlines the set of elementary reactions,
enclosed in light-green-colored rectangles, leading to the complete
reduction of these two molecules into their constituent species. The
dark-green-colored rectangles enclose the intermediate decomposition
products and elemental constituents, indicating which particles are
subjected to diffusion processes during the growth and densification
stage of the SEI, as discussed in the next section.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_0001" id="gr1" position="float"/></fig><p>Similarly, the further reduction of F5DEE (reactions <bold>b-2</bold> and <bold>b-3</bold>) is primarily controlled by electron
transfer
processes without significant E<sub>A,i</sub> barriers. This process
results in the accumulation of charged vinyl [CH<sub>2</sub>CH]<sup>&#x02212;</sup> and [OCH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>OCH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>3</sub>]<sup>&#x02212;</sup> anions on the surface, leading to the
formation of an organic amorphous phase. The adsorption of F5DEE on
Li<sub>2</sub>O, which is formed upon extended LiFSI decomposition,
triggers another decomposition path. This path has a <inline-formula id="d34e370"><inline-graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_m002.gif"/></inline-formula> barrier of 0.364 eV and does not involve
an external charge flow, resulting in the formation of LiOH and CF<sub>3</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>OCH<sub>2</sub>CH<sub>2</sub>OCHCH(F). Other works have attributed the presence of
LiOH to the native passivation film on lithium metal surfaces, possibly
due to water contamination, which then transforms into Li<sub>2</sub>O upon extended cycling.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref41">41</xref></sup> Our modeling strategy
in this work uses this reaction network of irreversible elementary
reactions to model the electrolyte decomposition without considering
the presence of LiOH, assuming it is present only in trace amounts
and linking its formation to the presence of impurities and crosstalk
reactions with the cathode electrode.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref35">35</xref></sup></p><p>The SEI grows continuously as the electrode cycles due to
further
electrochemical reactions occurring between the electrolyte and the
initial SEI layer, as well as with the electrodeposited Li. The newly
formed components from these ongoing reactions aggregate and integrate
into the existing SEI structure, thickening and densifying the SEI
layer into a mixture of organic and inorganic microphases. Importantly,
recent research indicates that the role of interfaces between these
microphases is crucial for ion conduction. For instance, the Li<sup>+</sup> conductivity at the LiF/Li<sub>2</sub>O interface can be
as high as 0.59 S/cm at 600 K (1.96 &#x000d7; 10<sup>&#x02013;4</sup> S/cm
at 300 K), compared to bulk Li<sub>2</sub>O (3.85 &#x000d7; 10<sup>&#x02013;5</sup> S/cm at 600 K).<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref></sup></p><p>This elevated
interfacial ionic conductivity originates from a
high carrier concentration, which corresponds to the number of Li<sup>+</sup> ions available for transport. The carrier concentration follows
a Boltzmann distribution related to the carrier formation energy (E<sub>f</sub>), which is the energy required to create a vacancy that can
act as a charge carrier; the lower the E<sub>f</sub> energy, the higher
the carrier concentration. The total bonding energy E<sub>B,i</sub>, which depends on the number of nearest sites (n<sub>j</sub>) and
the integrated crystal orbital Hamilton population parameter (E<sub>ICOHP,ij</sub>) of the binding atomic pair, is a parameter equivalent
to the E<sub>f</sub> that does not require expensive calculations
with large simulation cells,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref></sup> yet still
captures the role of the local environment on the ion mobility. In
this work, we introduce the concept of the E<sub>B,i</sub> dependency
on the local coordination environment as a suitable parameter for
quantifying ionic mobility during the thickening and consolidation
of the SEI layer.</p><p><xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref> discusses
the correlation between the total bonding energy for Li<sup>+</sup> ions (<inline-formula id="d34e433"><inline-graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_m003.gif"/></inline-formula>) and their number of bonding interactions.
The color map on <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>a displays the <inline-formula id="d34e440"><inline-graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_m004.gif"/></inline-formula> energies for the interfacial model of the
LiF and Li<sub>2</sub>O phases, with the Li<sub>2</sub>O structure
having one Li-terminated facet and one O-terminated facet, both facing
Li-terminated LiF surfaces through their (100) surfaces with a low
lattice mismatch (&#x0223c;11%). Earlier calculations demonstrate the
thermodynamic stability of this configuration with a binding energy
as low as &#x02212;84 meV/&#x000c5;<sup>2</sup>.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">19</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref></sup> The <inline-formula id="d34e455"><inline-graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_m005.gif"/></inline-formula> energy reaches its lowest values near either
interface due to the reduced coordination environment associated with
defects and vacancies, while higher values are found in the bulk of
the LiF and Li<sub>2</sub>O phases. <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>b and <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>c confirm the relationship between the Li<sup>+</sup> local coordination environment and its mobility. The total radial
distribution function (RDF) profiles for the Li<sup>+</sup> bonding
interactions, averaged for each of the 17 Li<sup>+</sup> layers parallel
to the LiF|Li<sub>2</sub>O interfaces, show that the L1 and L8 layers,
buried in the LiF and Li<sub>2</sub>O bulk phases, have higher coordination
peaks relative to the less symmetrical interfacial L6 and L11 layers.
This behavior correlates inversely with the mean square displacement
(MSD) profiles per layer shown in <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>c, where the L6 and L11 layers exhibit steeper
slopes compared to the flatter L1 and L8 profiles. The MSD parameter
measures the average square distance that Li<sup>+</sup> ions travel
over time and directly relates to their mobility,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref42">42</xref></sup> with a steeper slope indicating that interfacial Li<sup>+</sup> ions possess greater mobility.</p><fig id="fig2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Correlation between <inline-formula id="d34e495"><inline-graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_m008.gif"/></inline-formula> and its corresponding number of bonding
interactions. a) Bar color map displays bonding energies at interfaces
between Li<sub>2</sub>O and LiF. b) Total radial distribution function
profiles for the Li+ bonding interactions. Layers labeled as in a).
c) Mean square displacement for Li ions located at the indicated bulk
or interfacial layers. d and e) Cell representations for LiF and Li<sub>2</sub>O.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_0002" id="gr2" position="float"/></fig><p>The cell representations for LiF and Li<sub>2</sub>O on <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>d and <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>e help describe how
the kMC
approach leverages on variations in the Li<sup>+</sup> coordination
environment to model the role of SEI interfaces in Li<sup>+</sup> plating/stripping
dynamics. LiF crystallizes in a face-centered cubic lattice with a
rock salt structure (space group fm&#x00033;&#x00305;m), where Li<sup>+</sup> ions occupying both corner and face-centered positions bonding with
six equivalent F<sup>&#x02013;</sup> anions to create LiF<sub>6</sub> octahedra. In contrast, Li<sub>2</sub>O adopts an antifluoride configuration
(space group fm&#x00033;&#x00305;m), with Li<sup>+</sup> ions residing in tetrahedral
positions coordinating with four O<sup>2&#x02013;</sup> anions distributed
among corner and face-centered sites. This nonequivalent positioning
of Li<sup>+</sup> ions in LiF and Li<sub>2</sub>O induces a substantial
plastic deformation occurring along the LiF|Li<sub>2</sub>O interfaces,
with Li<sup>+</sup> ions frequently adopting undercoordinated off-lattice
positions, as <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>a illustrates, even though both phases share the same space group
fm &#x00033;&#x00305; m.</p><p><xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">1</xref></xref> lists the
E<sub>ICOHP,ij</sub> parameters driving the evolution of the inorganic
SEI microphases. By calculating the cumulative energy barrier for
anionic mobility (E<sub>B,i</sub> = n<sub>j</sub>E<sub>ICOHP,ij</sub>), based on the number of atomic pair interactions n<sub>j</sub>,
we can understand the factors influencing the Li<sup>+</sup> and anionic
mobility on the surface and within the SEI layer. The set of parameters
governing the pair bonding interaction with the intermediate decomposition
products (salt_IDP and solv_IDP) are chosen based on performance metrics
throughout the simulation to ensure stable SEI growth and coalescence
of the anion- and solvent-derived amorphous SEI phases.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">34</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref35">35</xref></sup></p><table-wrap id="tbl1" position="float"><label>Table 1</label><caption><title>Pair Bonding Interaction Parameters
Used in the kMC Simulation</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups" border="0"><colgroup><col align="left"/><col align="char" char="."/></colgroup><thead><tr><th style="border:none;" align="center">Atomic pair</th><th style="border:none;" align="center" char=".">E<sub>ICOHP,ij</sub> [eV]</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">Li&#x02013;Li</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.1037</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">Li&#x02013;F</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.7146</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">F&#x02013;F</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.0336</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">Li&#x02013;O</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.8027</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">O&#x02013;O</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.0615</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">Li&#x02013;S</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.7439</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">S&#x02013;S</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.0735</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">Li&#x02013;N</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.9000</td></tr><tr><td style="border:none;" align="left">N&#x02013;N</td><td style="border:none;" align="char" char=".">0.1164</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap><p>The structural framework from which the simulation
cell replicates
is a unitary cubic box with a lattice parameter a<sub>0,</sub> and
periodic boundary conditions applied in all three spatial directions
(<xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref>a). The pair-bonding
interaction energy E<sub>ICOHP,ij</sub> is independent of the magnitude
of the a<sub>0</sub> parameter; therefore, we set a<sub>0</sub> to
4.47 &#x000c5;, which is the average value between lithium metal and
the main inorganic components present in the SEI (LiF, Li<sub>2</sub>O, Li<sub>2</sub>S, and Li<sub>3</sub>N). This cubic system contains
a fixed number of lattice sites arranged in pairs along the body diagonals.
The repeating pattern hosts a face-centered cubic (FCC) lattice with
its four octahedral and eight tetrahedral interstitial sites. Additionally,
this arrangement allows for the conceptual overlay of a body-centered
cubic (BCC) lattice within the same spatial framework. This capability
enables the replication of the crystalline structures of lithium metal
and the inorganic solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) components within
our simulation cell, accurately approximating the Li<sup>+</sup> coordination
environment at the interfaces between these SEI components. <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figures <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref> illustrate the
construction of a lithium metal cell with its BCC configuration derived
from the BCC sites of the basic cubic box, and the structures of Li<sub>2</sub>O and LiF with their antifluorite and rock salt configurations,
respectively, along with the anion and Li<sup>+</sup> coordination
for each case.</p><fig id="fig3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Modeling framework used in our kMC simulations: (a) Unitary
cubic
box from which the simulation cell replicates, highlighting its lattice
sites; the BCC lattice sites overlay the FCC basis sites, including
the FCC octahedral and tetrahedral sites. (b) Metallic BCC lithium
constructed from the unitary cubic box, along with cubic representations
for (c) Li<sub>2</sub>O and (d) LiF, highlighting the anion coordination
environment in each case. (e) Generic simulation scenario with a lithium
metal slab interacting through its (001) surface with LiFSI and F5DEE
electrolyte particles randomly distributed up to their respective
molarities, assuming additive volumes. (f) Flow diagram under which
the FRM algorithm operates. The light-green loop addresses the electrolyte
reduction reactions, while the dark-green loop addresses the exchange
reactions driving the SEI aggregation processes.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_0003" id="gr3" position="float"/></fig><p><xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref>e shows
the simulation scenario with a lithium metal slab interacting with
a liquid electrolyte through its exposed (001) surfaces. The LiFSI-F5DEE
electrolyte consists of a 2 M LiFSI salt fully dissolved in a fluorinated
solvent F5DEE (6.5 M), whose particles are randomly distributed throughout
the empty space within the simulation cell. Each electrolyte particle
occupies a lattice site without accounting for the molecular volume
distinctive to each molecule. Hence, packing the solvent molecules
to the corresponding molarity, approximated from their density and
molecular weight, provides a better approximation of the collision
dynamics against the lithium metal surface.</p><p>Conversely, <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref></xref>f outlines the flow
diagram under which the first-reaction method
(FRM) operates to model the time-dependent electrochemical reaction
rates involved in the SEI evolution under discharging and charging
regimes. The list of all possible events taking place is split into
two simulation loops. The first one corresponds to the deposition
of the primary SEI components via the electrolyte reduction paths
discussed in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref> (light-green-colored), while the second loop addresses the aggregation
and integration of the released SEI components densifying the SEI
through the secondary matrix formation stage (dark-green-colored).
The diffusion processes driving the SEI aggregation proceed via exchange
reactions between neighboring lattice sites. We use the set of parameters
listed in <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">1</xref></xref> to
compute the energy barrier for ionic mobility (E<sub>B,i</sub> = n<sub>j</sub>E<sub>ICOHP,ij</sub>) whenever each of these exchange reactions
takes place.</p><p>The need for two simulation loops arises from the
disparate rates
at which the electrolyte reduction and the SEI aggregation takes place.
The elementary reactions of the electrolyte reduction processes are
spontaneous, hence significantly faster than the SEI aggregation and
integration processes that depend on local mobility constrains. Tuning
the number of iterations of the aggregation loop before another reduction
reaction takes place ensures a stable modeling of the SEI growth process.</p><p>The rate of reaction (k<sub arrange="stack">i</sub><sup arrange="stack">j</sup>) for a given i<sup>th</sup> species undergoing
a type of reaction j<sup>th</sup>, including the deposition of primary
SEI components through reduction processes and the SEI growth and
densification through diffusion reactions, abides by the transition
state theory described by an Arrhenius-type expression (<xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">eq <xref rid="eq1" ref-type="disp-formula">1</xref></xref>). The parameter &#x003bd; represents
the frequency and orientation of molecular collisions that could lead
to the reaction taking place. E<sub arrange="stack">i</sub><sup arrange="stack">j</sup> denotes the energy barrier, &#x003b1;<sub arrange="stack">i</sub><sup arrange="stack">j</sup> is the transfer
coefficient parameter that measures the effective reaction sensitivity
to an applied potential (E), E<sub arrange="stack">0,i</sub><sup arrange="stack">j</sup> corresponds to a reference potential, k<sub>B</sub> is the Boltzmann constant, and T is the absolute temperature.
In general, this expression for the rate of reaction is valid within
a temperature interval where the reaction mechanism remains invariable,
and the modeling parameters &#x003bd; and &#x003b1;<sub arrange="stack">i</sub><sup arrange="stack">j</sup> can be fitted to match the SEI
deposition rate from experiment accounting for the limited cross-sectional
area of the simulation cell. This approach helps compensate for errors
in the energy barriers assumed for the aggregation of the anion- and
solvent-derived amorphous phase.<disp-formula id="eq1"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_m006" position="anchor"/><label>1</label></disp-formula></p><p>The pseudorandom number generator (PRNG)
developed by Pierre L&#x02019;Ecuyer
operates the stochastic engine choosing the fastest reaction.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref43">43</xref></sup> In each iteration of the simulation loops, the
PRNG engine generates the random number &#x003be; needed to calculate
the time associated with every possible reaction (&#x00394;t<sub arrange="stack">i</sub><sup arrange="stack">j</sup> = &#x02212;ln &#x003be;/k<sub arrange="stack">i</sub><sup arrange="stack">j</sup>, &#x003be; &#x02208;
(0,1)). Hence, the reaction with the smallest &#x00394;<italic>t</italic><sub arrange="stack"><italic>i</italic></sub><sup arrange="stack"><italic>j</italic></sup> takes place to update the simulation cell.</p><p><xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>a shows
the tetragonal cell used in our simulation. The horizontal axes are
40a<sub>0</sub> wide and the vertical ones are 160a<sub>0</sub> high.
The lithium metal is a five layers slab, spans indefinitely along
the horizontal axes, and it faces the randomly distributed electrolyte
particles on both of its (001) surfaces. Our model does not simulate
the electrolyte liquid structure but focuses on the Li<sup>+</sup> electrochemical plating and stripping processes, the electrolyte
reduction reactions, and the subsequent SEI integration and aggregation
processes. <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>b shows the SEI layer formed after 100 h following a charging&#x02013;discharging
regime with each complete cycle lasting 2 h approximately. The simulation
subjects the lithium metal to a regime that mimics the electrolyte
reduction and Li<sup>+</sup> plating in a high-voltage environment
(4.4 V), as well as Li<sup>+</sup> stripping processes during discharge
(2.8 V).</p><fig id="fig4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>(a) Tetragonal cell used in our simulation with a five-layer lithium
metal slab facing randomly distributed electrolyte particles on both
(001) surfaces. The model focuses on Li<sup>+</sup> plating and stripping,
electrolyte reduction, and SEI integration processes. (b) Snapshot
of the kMC-predicted SEI layer formed after 100 h under a charging&#x02013;discharging
cycling regime. (c) Sequence of reactions showing early SEI formation
from LiFSI and F5DEE defluorination, and subsequent contributions
of SEI aggregation reactions. (d) Li<sup>+</sup> electrodeposition
dynamics with reduced lithium accumulating at grain boundaries between
inorganic SEI phases, highlighting greater Li<sup>+</sup> mobility
at the LiF|Li<sub>2</sub>O interface and the role of grain boundaries
in SEI structure and stability.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_0004" id="gr4" position="float"/></fig><p>The SEI aggregation proceeds through diffusion
reactions, with
multiple inorganic and organic phases building up the heterogeneous
SEI layer, as shown across both vertical directions in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>b. The sequence of reactions
is also plotted in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>c. The defluorination reactions of LiFSI and F5DEE (reactions
a-1 and b-1) drive the early SEI formation, primarily resulting from
the coalescence of lime-green-colored LiF particles viewed in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>d, along with charcoal
and light-gray-colored phases corresponding to the anion-derived and
solvent-derived amorphous phases.</p><p>The X-ray diffraction data,
combined with pair distribution function
(PDF) analysis from our earlier work on the SEI formation on lithium
metal from the LiFSI-F5DEE electrolyte,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref></sup> indicate that the fragments building up these anion- and solvent-derived
phases are predominantly made from short sulfur-based S&#x02013;N/F/O
and carbon-based C&#x02013;O/F/H bonds. The comprehensive characterization
of the bonding interactions within these phases falls beyond the scope
of the modeling strategy developed in this work, which instead focuses
on the Li<sup>+</sup> electrodeposition dynamics and the SEI morphological
evolution over extended cycling.</p><p>As the simulation progresses,
the extended FSI<sup>&#x02013;</sup> reduction (reactions a-1 to a-8)
occurs, leading to the formation
of inorganic SEI phases (Li<sub>2</sub>O, Li<sub>2</sub>S, and Li<sub>3</sub>N), which thicken the SEI layer while further consuming the
active lithium metal particles. In agreement with earlier PDF analysis,
the extended F5DEE reduction takes place simultaneously (reactions
b-2 and b-3), indicating a competitive decomposition process with
LiFSI, in which the ratio between the anion- and solvent-derived amorphous
phases varies over time.</p><p>The sequence of frames in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>d details the Li<sup>+</sup> electrodeposition dynamics
on the evolving SEI landscape. Notably, the electrochemically active
light-purple-colored reduced lithium predominantly accumulates at
the grain boundaries formed within the inorganic SEI phases. Our discussion
from <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref> highlighted
greater Li<sup>+</sup> mobility, where we observed lower binding energies <inline-formula id="d34e821"><inline-graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_m007.gif"/></inline-formula> for undercoordinated Li<sup>+</sup> ions
at the LiF|Li<sub>2</sub>O interface compared to those buried in the
bulk phases. Furthermore, the pair bonding interactions listed in <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">Table <xref rid="tbl1" ref-type="other">1</xref></xref> indicate that Li<sup>+</sup> pair bonding interactions in inorganic phases (LiF, Li<sub>2</sub>O, Li<sub>2</sub>S, Li<sub>3</sub>N) are approximately 7-fold
stronger than the metallic lithium E<sub>ICOHP,LiLi</sub> bonding
energies. This behavior justifies the Li<sup>+</sup> electrodeposition
observed in our simulation, which conforms to the grain boundaries
formed between the inorganic and organic domains upon electrolyte
decomposition. These results align with observations reported in an
earlier work focused on the lithium diffusion mechanism between the
three major inorganic SEI components: LiF, Li<sub>2</sub>O, and Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref20">20</xref></sup> where it was
demonstrated that the grain boundaries within the SEI serve as faster
pathways for lithium diffusion compared to the crystalline regions,
significantly influencing the overall ion transport and stability
of lithium-based batteries.</p><p>The surface Li<sup>+</sup>/Li<sup>0</sup> ratio plotted in <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>a (left vertical
axis) provide further insights into the overall electrochemical activity
of the passivated lithium metal slab in our simulation. The Li<sup>+</sup>/Li<sup>0</sup> ratio indicates the overall availability of
electrochemically active lithium for plating and stripping processes
from the total number of lithium particles present close to the electrode
surface. Initially, all particles making up the pristine lithium slab
surface are reduced to their metallic state (Li<sup>0</sup>) and are
readily electrochemically active. However, once the electrolyte reduction
reactions take place, the Li<sup>+</sup>/Li<sup>0</sup> ratio increases
because the slab surface undergoes an oxidation process that consumes
lithium not only from the slab itself but also from the Li<sup>+</sup> particles plating from the electrolyte. The SEI evolution pictured
in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref>d shows
a reduction in the covered area of electrochemically active light-purple-colored
lithium compared to that of the heterogeneous SEI. This indicates
that the effective lithium reduction from plating processes that occur
in the high-voltage regime (Li<sup>+</sup><sub>electrolyte</sub> &#x02192;
Li<sup>0</sup><sub>electrode</sub>) becomes less efficient over time.
The surface becomes less electrochemically active as it becomes increasingly
populated by inactive Li<sup>+</sup> ions engaged in strong bonding
interactions within the inorganic bulk phase, compared to the reduced
Li<sup>0</sup> domains conforming to the SEI grain boundaries.</p><fig id="fig5" position="float"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>(a) Surface
Li<sup>+</sup>/Li<sup>0</sup> ratio (left axis) and
Li<sub>2</sub>O/LiF ratio (right axis) over the course of the simulation.
The Li<sup>+</sup>/Li<sup>0</sup> ratio reflects the availability
of electrochemically active lithium, initially high but decreasing
due to oxidation and SEI formation. The Li<sub>2</sub>O/LiF ratio
starts low, peaking between five to 10 h, indicating dynamic anion
reduction and SEI composition changes. (b) Coulombic efficiency (CE%)
showing high values during initial cycles due to abundant Li<sup>0</sup> particles, with a decrease after 25 h as SEI thickens and Li<sup>0</sup> availability drops. (c) Distribution of Li<sup>0</sup> particles
versus deep green SEI after 100 h, illustrating Li<sup>0</sup> aggregation
near the core and diminishing toward the surface. SEI densification
leads to thicker organic and inorganic phases, thinner grain boundaries,
and reduced electrode performance.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_0005" id="gr5" position="float"/></fig><p><xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>a (right
vertical axis) overlaps the Li<sub>2</sub>O/LiF ratio during cycling,
providing further details on the anion reduction dynamics and competitive
decomposition with the F5DEE solvent. The Li<sub>2</sub>O/LiF ratio
starts with very low values during the initial cycles and then peaks
between five to 10 h of simulated cycling. This behavior qualitatively
agrees with our earlier observations via Rietveld refinement on the
SEI evolution from the LiFSI-F5DEE electrolyte on a lithium metal
surface, indicating suppressed Li<sub>2</sub>O formation in the initial
cycles.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref></sup> Later, Li<sub>2</sub>O population
increases upon further anion reduction, while the LiF growth from
simultaneous anion and solvent defluorination processes remains relatively
constant throughout the simulation.</p><p>This reduction in the electrochemical
activity becomes evident
with the estimation of the Coulombic efficiency (CE % = e<sup>&#x02013;</sup><sub>discharge</sub>/e<sup>&#x02013;</sup><sub>charge</sub> * 100)
over the course of the simulation, as plotted in <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>b, where e<sup>&#x02013;</sup><sub>discharge</sub> and e<sup>&#x02013;</sup><sub>charge</sub> are
the electrons exchanged during discharge and charge reactions, respectively.
The CE is based on the number of reaction events at high- and low-voltage
regimes and the number of electrons in each elementary reaction outlined
in <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref></xref> for both
the LiFSI and F5DEE decomposition. The CE is predominantly above 100%
during the first charging/discharging cycles within the initial 25
h of the simulation because the proportion of reduced Li<sup>0</sup> particles engaged in metallic bonding interactions and available
for stripping reactions is greater than the amount of Li<sup>+</sup> particles engaged in stronger ionic interactions within the inorganic
phases. After 25 h, the surface area covered by the heterogeneous
SEI layer overwhelms the reduced Li<sup>0</sup> particles accumulated
at the grain boundaries, hence the proportion of Li<sup>0</sup> particles
available for stripping processes dwindles, and the CE efficiency
decreases.</p><p><xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref>c shows
the distribution of Li<sup>0</sup> particles in contrast with the
deep green overall SEI formed after 100 h of simulated cycling. This
view of the simulation cell confirms the conformal aggregation of
reduced Li<sup>0</sup> particles around the heterogeneous SEI structure.
The Li<sup>0</sup> particles are predominantly close to the core of
the passivated surface where the pristine lithium slab was initially
located, while the cross-sectional area covered by Li<sup>0</sup> diminishes
closer to the surfaces exposed to the electrolyte particles. As the
SEI layer densifies, the multiple organic and inorganic SEI domains
grow thicker, the grain boundaries funneling the electrochemically
active lithium become thinner, and the electrode surface where Li<sup>0</sup> particles aggregate and are available for electrochemical
plating and stripping processes dwindles, leading to diminished electrode
performance.</p><p>An important conclusion of this work refers to
ionic transport
for Li plating and for Li stripping and its relationship to SEI growth.
Usually, the SEI phases nucleate separately, and generally inorganic
phases have a faster development than the organic ones, but the specific
details depend on the electrolyte chemistry.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref31">31</xref></sup> Depending on the electrolyte, the inorganic phases may appear first,
since they mostly originate from faster anion decompositions, although
the solvents can also contribute to the oxide phase in later stages.
The organic phases are usually much more disperse and they are formed
by fragments dissolved in unreacted solvent, or in some cases they
could form a semipolymeric structure, and usually they do not form
a crystalline phase, although it depends on the specific chemistries.
Once the SEI forms, ion transport channels arise naturally between
nucleating phases. In the initial SEI stages, the nuclei are mostly
of amorphous character, and may allow ionic transport through the
nascent nuclei structure. However, as the nuclei become more crystalline
over time, such transport through the crystalline phase becomes increasingly
difficult, and is dependent on the crystal structure and chemical
composition. Much faster is ion transport at the grain boundaries,
which may be facilitated or not depending on the chemistry and structure
of the exposed facets, as discussed in relation to <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref></xref>. In addition, changes in voltage
and charge rate affect such phenomena.</p><p>In preliminary studies,
we have varied the current density and
applied voltage in a series of tests reported in SI (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02019/suppl_file/nz4c02019_si_001.pdf">Figures S1, S2, S3</ext-link>). <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02019/suppl_file/nz4c02019_si_001.pdf">Figure S1</ext-link> depicts
how Li plating proceeds by deposition of Li atoms between SEI phases,
illustrating the importance of such ionic diffusion between grains,
along with the extent of amorphous character of the nucleating phases. <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02019/suppl_file/nz4c02019_si_001.pdf">Figures S2 and S3</ext-link> explore how the reaction decomposition
pathways, and electrodeposition reactions differ between low and high
voltage regimes. While <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02019/suppl_file/nz4c02019_si_001.pdf">Figure S2</ext-link> focuses
on changes in the plating and stripping reactions at each cycle, <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02019/suppl_file/nz4c02019_si_001.pdf">Figure S3</ext-link> shows a minimum change in the number
of solvent (organic) and salt (inorganic) decomposition reactions.
The faster inorganic rates are more affected by cycling than the organic.
The plating and stripping reactions are very dependent on the applied
voltage, and they also have an important dependence on the cycling
states. As cycling progresses, the chances of ion electrodeposition
decrease because the surface becomes blocked by the SEI and the electron
transport also becomes more difficult, becoming a trigger of the failure
mechanism. In addition to <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02019/suppl_file/nz4c02019_si_001.pdf">Figures S1 to S3</ext-link>, <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref></xref> and <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Figure <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref></xref> focus on the changes
in surface structure and the effects on Coulombic efficiency that
are very relevant for the understanding of the electrochemical cell
performance. Additional work based on systematic variations of voltage
and charge rate for a given electrolyte on Li deposition morphologies,
as well as understanding the differences in transport rates for amorphous
and crystalline phases at various interfaces will be discussed in
future reports.</p><p>One of the goals of this work is to help predicting
cell failure.
So far, no electrolyte results in a cell performance without failures.
However, it may be possible to design chemistries yielding minimum
failure and extended lifetimes. Although a thin SEI thickness is not
a necessary and sufficient condition to mitigate failure, most of
the SEI layers that grow without control exhibit a high electronic
conductance,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref44">44</xref></sup> and a sudden catastrophic
behavior. In this work we emphasize that both the SEI compositions,
morphology, and properties, and the metal electrodeposition morphology
and properties are important. From the observations of the evolution
of these phenomena during cycling, one clear conclusion is that the
cell dies when plating stops, which may be triggered by electrolyte
consumption, SEI completely covering the surface, SEI properties unfavorable
to ionic transport and favorable to electronic transport. These are
general observations, and more work is needed to outline specific
rules that can be related to categories of electrolytes.</p><p>Li
electrodeposition morphologies have an obvious impact on failure,
especially if needle-type plating structures are formed that can grow
all the way to the cathode and short-circuit the cell. Mesoscale modeling
approaches have been used to get new analyses of the effects of SEI
structure and properties and their effects on plating and stripping
phenomena. Mukherjee et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref45">45</xref></sup> provided
important insights into dendrite growth triggered by the interactions
between SEI and Li deposits. They concluded that dendrite growth may
be induced by ion depletion at the anode-SEI interfaces due to transport
limitations at high reaction rates or low temperatures. Another suggested
cause is the existence of spatial variations in reaction kinetics
at the anode/electrolyte due to SEI inhomogeneities. This view agrees
with the idea of transport limitation that we suggested because of
clogging of the grain boundaries. Zhang et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref46">46</xref></sup> evaluated local stresses and deformation in the SEI phase
due to Li growth, suggesting tuning SEI stability as a form of ion
transport regulation. Again, the idea of SEI stability and ion transport
regulation goes along with the findings in this work. Since the method
is based on a detailed analysis of the chemistry of the system, the
present kMC approach can also provide rules to complement the continuum
model discussed by Zhang et al. More recently, Mukherjee et al.,<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref47">47</xref></sup> built on these previous works and introduced
the effect of SEI heterogeneities which may induce currents and stress
hot spots during metal plating. The net effect is suggested as affecting
interfacial stress-contributions to overpotentials that may be significant
factors that lead cells into failure. In relation to this point, we
expect the current discussion to be insightful feedback to mesoscale
models that help facilitating the description of chemo-electro-mechanical
behavior of these complex interfaces.</p><p>Additional SEI dissolution
studies are also needed in this field.
Previous work studying SEI dissolution in contact with a DME solvent,
for LiF, Li<sub>2</sub>O, Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>, and LiOH<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref48">48</xref></sup> suggested that their dissolution were not thermodynamically
favorable, with LiOH the most favorable of this group to dissolve.
However, amorphous SEI nuclei or surface Li ions may perhaps dissolve
in certain electrolytes. Interestingly, we recently reported<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref39">39</xref></sup> that crystalline LiOH may become amorphous over
cycling. It is possible that the dissolution trend of amorphous LiOH
may become favorable. Thus, further analysis and incorporation of
these reactions into the kMC model should be of interest.</p><p>In
summary, this study presents a comprehensive mechanistic model
for the SEI formation and the Li<sup>+</sup> electrochemical plating
and stripping reactions on a lithium metal anode in a cycling regime
using a first-principles kMC approach. The findings highlight that
in the LiFSI-F5DEE electrolyte system, the SEI&#x02019;s composition
and structure are significantly influenced by the aggregation of the
SEI components, with organic and inorganic phases competing for dominance.
Grain boundaries between disparate inorganic SEI phases, such as LiF
and Li<sub>2</sub>O, are identified as faster pathways for lithium-ion
transport, enhancing overall SEI conductivity. It confirms the conformal
aggregation of the electrochemically active Li<sup>0</sup> particles
around the heterogeneous SEI distribution. Additionally, the efficiency
of lithium reduction during plating processes decreases over time
due to the densification of the SEI layer and the increasing prevalence
of strong ionic interactions within the inorganic bulk phase. The
simulated SEI evolution qualitatively agrees with experimental observations,
providing a predictive framework for future SEI studies and electrolyte
formulation designs. This work underscores the importance of dynamic
SEI modeling for the development of next-generation high-energy-density
batteries.</p><sec id="sec2"><title>Methods</title><p>. The C++ GNU Compiler Collection system (version
11.3.0) and the GNU Scientific Library (version 2.7) power our in-house
kMC algorithm, which is tailored for SEI modeling. This algorithm
was adapted from an earlier implementation optimized for studying
the dealloying of Pt-based nanoparticles for oxygen reduction reaction
catalysts.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">32</xref></sup></p><p>The Vienna Ab initio
Simulation Package (VASP, version 5.4.5) was
used to estimate the pair bonding interaction parameters (E<sub>ICOHP,ij</sub>), and model the interfacial LiF|Li<sub>2</sub>O structure using
the density functional theory (DFT) method for the structural optimizations
and the ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations for extended
interfacial relaxation processes.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref49">49</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref50">50</xref></sup> The crystallographic
data for lithium metal, and the inorganic SEI structures (LiF, Li<sub>2</sub>O, Li<sub>2</sub>S, Li<sub>3</sub>N) was collected from the
Materials Project Database.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref51">51</xref></sup> The generalized
gradient approximation based on the Perdew&#x02013;Burke&#x02013;Ernzerhof
functional (GGA-PBE) was used to describe the electronic exchange
and correlation effects.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref52">52</xref></sup> Conversely,
the projected augmented wave formalism was employed to model the electron&#x02013;ion
interactions using a global break condition for the self-consistent
iterative loop set to 10<sup>&#x02013;4</sup> eV.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref53">53</xref></sup></p><p>The structural optimizations were executed before
and after the
AIMD calculations using a kinetic energy cutoff set to 520 eV with
convergence criteria set to 0.05 eV/&#x000c5; and a reciprocal Monkhorst&#x02013;Pack
grid of 0.05 &#x000c5;<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>. Finally, for the extended
AIMD simulations, a temperature of 900 K was maintained using the
canonical NVT ensemble. The simulations used a time step set to 1.5
fs, an energy cutoff of 400 eV, and a computationally less expensive
gamma-point grid density. The software package Local Orbital Suited
Toward Electronic-Structure Reconstruction (LOBSTER, version 5.0.0)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref54">54</xref>&#x02212;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref59">59</xref></sup> was used for the estimation of the pair-bonding interaction parameters
(integrated crystal orbital Hamilton population parameter (E<sub>ICOHP,ij</sub>)). The calculation proceeded using Bunge&#x02019;s local basis functions
for each of the atomic species involved with an absolute charge spilling
not greater than 3.97% in each case.</p></sec></body><back><notes id="notes1" notes-type="si"><title>Supporting Information Available</title><p>The Supporting Information
is
available free of charge at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02019?goto=supporting-info">https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02019</ext-link>.<list id="silist" list-type="simple"><list-item><p>Tests for the effects of voltage and cycling on the
reactions considered in this work: Surface morphology evolution (Figure
S1), Changes in the number of Li atoms deposited or stripped on the
anode surface as a function of voltage and cycle number (Figure S2),
and Effect of voltage on main reactions (Figure S3) (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/suppl/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02019/suppl_file/nz4c02019_si_001.pdf">PDF</ext-link>)</p></list-item></list></p></notes><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="sifile1"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="nz4c02019_si_001.pdf"><caption><p>nz4c02019_si_001.pdf</p></caption></media></supplementary-material></sec><notes notes-type="COI-statement" id="NOTES-d14e1342-autogenerated"><p>The
authors declare no
competing financial interest.</p></notes><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>This work was supported by the Assistant Secretary
for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, Office of Vehicle Technologies
of the US Department of Energy through the Advanced Battery Materials
Research (BMR) Program (Battery500 Consortium phase 2) under DOE contract
No. DE-AC05-76RL01830 from the Pacific Northwest National Laboratory
(PNNL). Computational resources from the Texas A&#x00026;M University
High Performance Research Computing are gratefully acknowledged.</p></ack><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="ref1"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit1"><name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Song</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Son</surname><given-names>D.-Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ono</surname><given-names>L. K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Lithium-Ion
Batteries: Outlook on Present, Future, and Hybridized Technologies</article-title>. <source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>7</volume> (<issue>7</issue>), <fpage>2942</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2964</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C8TA10513H</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref2"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit2"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Shao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>
<article-title>High-Energy
Lithium-Ion Batteries: Recent Progress and a Promising
Future in Applications</article-title>. <source>Energy Environ. Mater.</source>
<year>2023</year>, <volume>6</volume> (<issue>5</issue>), <elocation-id>e12450</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/eem2.12450</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref3"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit3"><name><surname>Xia</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Practical Challenges
and Future Perspectives of All-Solid-State Lithium-Metal Batteries</article-title>. <source>Chem.</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>5</volume> (<issue>4</issue>), <fpage>753</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>785</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.chempr.2018.11.013</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref4"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit4"><name><surname>Peled</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The electrochemical
behavior of alkali and alkaline earth metals in nonaqueous battery
systems&#x02014;the solid electrolyte interphase model</article-title>. <source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source>
<year>1979</year>, <volume>126</volume> (<issue>12</issue>), <fpage>2047</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1149/1.2128859</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref5"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit5"><name><surname>Cresce</surname><given-names>A. v.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Russell</surname><given-names>S. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Baker</surname><given-names>D. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gaskell</surname><given-names>K. J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>In situ and
quantitative characterization of solid electrolyte interphases</article-title>. <source>Nano Lett.</source>
<year>2014</year>, <volume>14</volume> (<issue>3</issue>), <fpage>1405</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1412</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/nl404471v</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24475938</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref6"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit6"><name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qi</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hector</surname><given-names>L. G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>S. J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Direct Calculation
of Li-Ion Transport in the Solid
Electrolyte Interphase</article-title>. <source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source>
<year>2012</year>, <volume>134</volume> (<issue>37</issue>), <fpage>15476</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>15487</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ja305366r</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22909233</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref7"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit7"><name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>X.-B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>C.-Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.-G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>
<article-title>A Review of Solid Electrolyte Interphases
on Lithium Metal Anode</article-title>. <source>Adv. Sci.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>3</volume> (<issue>3</issue>), <fpage>1500213</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/advs.201500213</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref8"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit8"><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ihsan-Ul-Haq</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.-K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Understanding Solid
Electrolyte Interphases: Advanced CharacterizationTechniques and Theoretical
Simulations</article-title>. <source>Nano Energy</source>
<year>2021</year>, <volume>89</volume>, <fpage>106489</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2021.106489</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref9"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit9"><name><surname>Flamme</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Garcia</surname><given-names>G. R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Weil</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Haddad</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Phansavath</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ratovelomanana-Vidal</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chagnes</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Guidelines
to design organic electrolytes
for lithium-ion batteries: environmental impact, physicochemical and
electrochemical properties</article-title>. <source>Green Chem.</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>19</volume> (<issue>8</issue>), <fpage>1828</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1849</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C7GC00252A</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref10"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit10"><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>S.-L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; et al. <article-title>Impact
of the fluorination degree of ether-based electrolyte solvents
on Li-metal battery performance</article-title>. <source>J. Mater. Chem.
A</source>
<year>2024</year>, <volume>12</volume> (<issue>5</issue>), <fpage>2986</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2993</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/D3TA05535C</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref11"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit11"><name><surname>Perez
Beltran</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.-G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Balbuena</surname><given-names>P. B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Localized
High Concentration Electrolytes for High Voltage Lithium-Metal Batteries:
Correlation between the Electrolyte Composition and its Reductive/Oxidative
Stability</article-title>. <source>Chem. Mater.</source>
<year>2020</year>, <volume>32</volume> (<issue>14</issue>), <fpage>5973</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5984</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.0c00987</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref12"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit12"><name><surname>Perez-Beltran</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.-G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>El-Khoury</surname><given-names>P. Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Balbuena</surname><given-names>P. B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Influence of Diluent
Concentration in Localized High Concentration Electrolytes: Elucidation
of Hidden Diluent-Li+ Interactions and Li+ Transport Mechanism</article-title>. <source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source>
<year>2021</year>, <volume>9</volume> (<issue>32</issue>), <fpage>17459</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>17473</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/D1TA04737J</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref13"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit13"><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Rudnicki</surname><given-names>P. E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Celik</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Oyakhire</surname><given-names>S. T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kong</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>S. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; et al. <article-title>Rational
Solvent Molecule Tuning for High-Performance
Lithium Metal Battery Electrolytes</article-title>. <source>Nat. Energy</source>
<year>2022</year>, <volume>7</volume> (<issue>1</issue>), <fpage>94</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>106</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41560-021-00962-y</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref14"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit14"><name><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mei</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Engelhard</surname><given-names>M. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Burton</surname><given-names>S. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>M. S.</given-names></name>; et al. <article-title>Localized
High-Concentration Sulfone Electrolytes for
High-Efficiency Lithium-Metal Batteries</article-title>. <source>Chem.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>4</volume> (<issue>8</issue>), <fpage>1877</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1892</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.chempr.2018.05.002</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref15"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit15"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mei</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>K. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Engelhard</surname><given-names>M. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.-G.</given-names></name>
<article-title>High-Voltage
Lithium-Metal Batteries Enabled by Localized High-Concentration Electrolytes</article-title>. <source>Adv. Mater.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>30</volume> (<issue>21</issue>), <fpage>1706102</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adma.201706102</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref16"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit16"><name><surname>Aktekin</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hern&#x000e1;ndez</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Younesi</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Brandell</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Edstr&#x000f6;m</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Concentrated
LiFSI&#x02013;Ethylene Carbonate Electrolytes and Their Compatibility
with High-Capacity and High-Voltage Electrodes</article-title>. <source>ACS Appl. Energy Mater.</source>
<year>2022</year>, <volume>5</volume> (<issue>1</issue>), <fpage>585</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>595</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsaem.1c03096</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35098043</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref17"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit17"><name><surname>Buyuker</surname><given-names>I. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Pei</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.-G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bao</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; et al. <article-title>Voltage and Temperature
Limits of Advanced Electrolytes for Lithium-Metal
Batteries</article-title>. <source>ACS Energy Lett.</source>
<year>2023</year>, <volume>8</volume> (<issue>4</issue>), <fpage>1735</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1743</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.3c00235</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref18"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit18"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Atomic insights into
the fundamental interactions in lithium battery
electrolytes</article-title>. <source>Acc. Chem. Res.</source>
<year>2020</year>, <volume>53</volume> (<issue>9</issue>), <fpage>1992</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2002</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.accounts.0c00412</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32883067</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref19"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit19"><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>X.-X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>Z.-H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The Origin of Fast Lithium-Ion Transport
in the Inorganic Solid Electrolyte Interphase on Lithium Metal Anodes</article-title>. <source>Small Structures</source>
<year>2022</year>, <volume>3</volume> (<issue>8</issue>), <fpage>2200071</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/sstr.202200071</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref20"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit20"><name><surname>Ramasubramanian</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yurkiv</surname><given-names>V.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Foroozan</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ragone</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Shahbazian-Yassar</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mashayek</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Lithium Diffusion Mechanism through Solid&#x02013;Electrolyte
Interphase in Rechargeable Lithium Batteries</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>123</volume> (<issue>16</issue>), <fpage>10237</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>10245</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.9b00436</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref21"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit21"><name><surname>Jie</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jia</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; et al. <article-title>Progress and Perspectives
on the Development of Pouch-Type
Lithium Metal Batteries</article-title>. <source>Angew. Chem., Int.
Ed. Engl.</source>
<year>2023</year>, <volume>63</volume> (<issue>7</issue>), <elocation-id>e202307802</elocation-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.202307802</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37515479</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref22"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit22"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Shadike</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Qian</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ganapathy</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; et al. <article-title>Review of recent development of in situ/operando characterization
techniques for lithium battery research</article-title>. <source>Adv.
Mater.</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>31</volume> (<issue>28</issue>), <fpage>1806620</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adma.201806620</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref23"><mixed-citation publication-type="book" id="cit23"><person-group person-group-type="allauthors"><name><surname>Tarascon</surname><given-names>J. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Armand</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Issues and Challenges
Facing Rechargeable Lithium Batteries</article-title>. In <source>Materials for Sustainable Energy</source>; <publisher-name>Co-Published
with Macmillan Publishers Ltd</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>UK</publisher-loc>, <year>2010</year>; pp <fpage>171</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>179</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref24"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit24"><name><surname>Xi</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Lifetime prediction
of rechargeable lithium-ion battery using multi-physics and multiscale
model</article-title>. <source>J. Power Sources</source>
<year>2024</year>, <volume>608</volume>, <fpage>234622</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234622</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref25"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit25"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Monroe</surname><given-names>C. W.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Multiscale lithium-battery
modeling from materials
to cells</article-title>. <source>Annu. Rev. Chem. Biomol. Eng.</source>
<year>2020</year>, <volume>11</volume>, <fpage>277</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>310</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1146/annurev-chembioeng-012120-083016</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32212821</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref26"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit26"><name><surname>Kresse</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hafner</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Ab Initio Molecular-Dynamics
Simulation of the Liquid-Metal--Amorphous-Semiconductor
Transition in Germanium</article-title>. <source>Phys. Rev. B</source>
<year>1994</year>, <volume>49</volume> (<issue>20</issue>), <fpage>14251</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>14269</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.49.14251</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref27"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit27"><name><surname>Kresse</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hafner</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Ab initio molecular dynamics for liquid metals</article-title>. <source>Phys. Rev. B</source>
<year>1993</year>, <volume>47</volume> (<issue>1</issue>), <fpage>558</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.47.558</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref28"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit28"><name><surname>Hafner</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Ab-initio
simulations of materials using VASP: density-functional theory and
beyond</article-title>. <source>J. Comput. Chem.</source>
<year>2008</year>, <volume>29</volume> (<issue>13</issue>), <fpage>2044</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2078</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jcc.21057</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18623101</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref29"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit29"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Huai</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Goddard</surname><given-names>W. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The DFT-ReaxFF Hybrid Reactive Dynamics
Method with Application to the Reductive Decomposition Reaction of
the TFSI and DOL Electrolyte at a Lithium&#x02013;Metal Anode Surface</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. Lett.</source>
<year>2021</year>, <volume>12</volume> (<issue>4</issue>), <fpage>1300</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1306</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.0c03720</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33502211</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref30"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit30"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Goddard</surname><given-names>W. A.</given-names><suffix>III</suffix></name>
<article-title>Effects of High
and Low Salt Concentrations in Electrolytes at Lithium&#x02013;Metal
Anode Surfaces Using DFT-ReaxFF Hybrid Molecular Dynamics Method</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. Lett.</source>
<year>2021</year>, <volume>12</volume> (<issue>11</issue>), <fpage>2922</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2929</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.1c00279</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33725449</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref31"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit31"><name><surname>Perez
Beltran</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Balbuena</surname><given-names>P. B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>SEI Formation Mechanisms and Li+
Dissolution in Lithium Metal Anodes: Impact of the Electrolyte Composition
and the Electrolyte-to-Anode Ratio</article-title>. <source>J. Power
Sources</source>
<year>2022</year>, <volume>551</volume>, <fpage>232203</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2022.232203</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref32"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit32"><name><surname>Callejas-Tovar</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Diaz</surname><given-names>C. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>de la
Hoz</surname><given-names>J. M. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Balbuena</surname><given-names>P. B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Dealloying of platinum-based
alloy catalysts: kinetic Monte Carlo simulations</article-title>. <source>Electrochim. Acta</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>101</volume>, <fpage>326</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>333</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2013.01.053</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref33"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit33"><name><surname>Hankins</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kamphaus</surname><given-names>E. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Balbuena</surname><given-names>P. B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Combined
density functional theory/kinetic
Monte Carlo investigation of surface morphology during cycling of
Li-Cu electrodes</article-title>. <source>Electrochim. Acta</source>
<year>2021</year>, <volume>397</volume>, <fpage>139272</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2021.139272</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref34"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit34"><name><surname>Wagner-Henke</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kuai</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gerasimov</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>R&#x000f6;der</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Balbuena</surname><given-names>P. B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Krewer</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Knowledge-driven design
of solid-electrolyte
interphases on lithium metal via multiscale modelling</article-title>. <source>Nat. Commun.</source>
<year>2023</year>, <volume>14</volume> (<issue>1</issue>), <fpage>6823</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-42212-7</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37884517</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref35"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit35"><name><surname>Gerasimov</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Soto</surname><given-names>F. A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Baakes</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ospina-Acevedo</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>R&#x000f6;der</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Balbuena</surname><given-names>P. B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Krewer</surname><given-names>U.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Species distribution
during solid electrolyte interphase formation on lithium using MD/DFT-parameterized
kinetic Monte Carlo simulations</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem.
C</source>
<year>2023</year>, <volume>127</volume> (<issue>10</issue>), <fpage>4872</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>4886</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.2c05898</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref36"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit36"><name><surname>Spotte-Smith</surname><given-names>E. W. C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kam</surname><given-names>R. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Barter</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xie</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hou</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dwaraknath</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Blau</surname><given-names>S. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Persson</surname><given-names>K. A.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Toward a Mechanistic
Model of Solid&#x02013;Electrolyte Interphase Formation and Evolution
in Lithium-Ion Batteries</article-title>. <source>ACS Energy Letters</source>
<year>2022</year>, <volume>7</volume> (<issue>4</issue>), <fpage>1446</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1453</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.2c00517</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref37"><mixed-citation publication-type="book" id="cit37"><person-group person-group-type="allauthors"><name><surname>Jansen</surname><given-names>A. P. J.</given-names></name></person-group><source>An introduction
to kinetic Monte Carlo simulations of surface reactions</source>; <publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name>, <year>2012</year>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref38"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit38"><name><surname>Niu</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J.-G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Whittingham</surname><given-names>M. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>High-energy
lithium metal pouch cells with limited anode swelling and long stable
cycles</article-title>. <source>Nat. Energy</source>
<year>2019</year>, <volume>4</volume> (<issue>7</issue>), <fpage>551</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>559</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41560-019-0390-6</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref39"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit39"><name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Kuai</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Perez-Beltran</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Rahman</surname><given-names>M. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xia</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>X.-Q.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; et al. <article-title>Evolution
and Interplay
of Lithium Metal Interphase Components Revealed by Experimental and
Theoretical Studies</article-title>. <source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source>
<year>2024</year>, <volume>146</volume> (<issue>17</issue>), <fpage>11711</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>11718</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jacs.3c14232</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38632847</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref40"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit40"><name><surname>Camacho-Forero</surname><given-names>L. E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>T. W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Balbuena</surname><given-names>P. B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Effects of High and Low Salt Concentration
in Electrolytes at Lithium&#x02013;Metal Anode Surfaces</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>121</volume> (<issue>1</issue>), <fpage>182</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>194</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b10774</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref41"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit41"><name><surname>Shadike</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Borodin</surname><given-names>O.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bak</surname><given-names>S.-M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ghose</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; et al. <article-title>Identification
of LiH and Nanocrystalline LiF in the Solid&#x02013;Electrolyte Interphase
of Lithium Metal Anodes</article-title>. <source>Nat. Nanotechnol.</source>
<year>2021</year>, <volume>16</volume> (<issue>5</issue>), <fpage>549</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>554</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41565-020-00845-5</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33510453</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref42"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit42"><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Epstein</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mo</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Statistical variances of diffusional
properties from ab initio molecular dynamics simulations</article-title>. <source>npj Comput. Mater.</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>4</volume> (<issue>1</issue>), <fpage>18</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41524-018-0074-y</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref43"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit43"><name><surname>L&#x02019;ecuyer</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Maximally
equidistributed combined Tausworthe generators</article-title>. <source>Math. Comput.</source>
<year>1996</year>, <volume>65</volume> (<issue>213</issue>), <fpage>203</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>213</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1090/S0025-5718-96-00696-5</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref44"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit44"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Jia</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Galvez-Aranda</surname><given-names>D. E.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Beltran</surname><given-names>S. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Le</surname><given-names>P. M. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Engelhard</surname><given-names>M. H.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; et al. <article-title>Direct
in situ measurements of electrical properties
of solid&#x02013;electrolyte interphase on lithium metal anodes</article-title>. <source>Nature Energy</source>
<year>2023</year>, <volume>8</volume> (<issue>12</issue>), <fpage>1345</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1354</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41560-023-01361-1</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38249622</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref45"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit45"><name><surname>Hao</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Verma</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mukherjee</surname><given-names>P. P.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Mechanistic
insight into dendrite&#x02013;SEI
interactions for lithium metal electrodes</article-title>. <source>Journal
of Materials Chemistry A</source>
<year>2018</year>, <volume>6</volume> (<issue>40</issue>), <fpage>19664</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>19671</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C8TA07997H</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref46"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit46"><name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>X.-B.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name>
<article-title>The Failure of Solid
Electrolyte Interphase on Li Metal Anode: Structural
Uniformity or Mechanical Strength?</article-title>. <source>Adv. Energy
Mater.</source>
<year>2020</year>, <volume>10</volume> (<issue>10</issue>), <fpage>1903645</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/aenm.201903645</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref47"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit47"><name><surname>Singla</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Naik</surname><given-names>K. G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Vishnugopi</surname><given-names>B. S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Mukherjee</surname><given-names>P. P.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Heterogeneous
Solid Electrolyte Interphase Interactions Dictate Interface Instability
in Sodium Metal Electrodes</article-title>. <source>Advanced Science</source>
<year>2024</year>, <volume>11</volume> (<issue>36</issue>), <fpage>2404887</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/advs.202404887</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39076123</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref48"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit48"><name><surname>Kamphaus</surname><given-names>E. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Balbuena</surname><given-names>P. B.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Liquid state properties
of SEI components in dimethoxyethane</article-title>. <source>J. Chem.
Phys.</source>
<year>2021</year>, <volume>155</volume> (<issue>12</issue>), <fpage>124701</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/5.0059246</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34598576</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref49"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit49"><name><surname>Kresse</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hafner</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Ab initio molecular
dynamics for open-shell transition
metals</article-title>. <source>Phys. Rev. B</source>
<year>1993</year>, <volume>48</volume> (<issue>17</issue>), <fpage>13115</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>13118</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.48.13115</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref50"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit50"><name><surname>Kresse</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Furthm&#x000fc;ller</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Efficient
Iterative Schemes for Ab Initio Total-Energy
Calculations Using a Plane-Wave Basis Set</article-title>. <source>Phys.
Rev. B</source>
<year>1996</year>, <volume>54</volume> (<issue>16</issue>), <fpage>11169</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>11186</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.54.11169</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref51"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit51"><name><surname>Jain</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ong</surname><given-names>S. P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hautier</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Richards</surname><given-names>W. D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dacek</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Cholia</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Gunter</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Skinner</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ceder</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; et al. <article-title>Commentary: The Materials
Project: A materials genome
approach to accelerating materials innovation</article-title>. <source>APL Mater.</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>1</volume> (<issue>1</issue>), <fpage>011002</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1063/1.4812323</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref52"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit52"><name><surname>Perdew</surname><given-names>J.
P.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Burke</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ernzerhof</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Generalized gradient approximation
made simple</article-title>. <source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source>
<year>1996</year>, <volume>77</volume> (<issue>18</issue>), <fpage>3865</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>3868</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.77.3865</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10062328</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref53"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit53"><name><surname>Kresse</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Joubert</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name>
<article-title>From ultrasoft pseudopotentials to the projector augmented-wave
method</article-title>. <source>Phys. Rev. B</source>
<year>1999</year>, <volume>59</volume> (<issue>3</issue>), <fpage>1758</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1775</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.59.1758</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref54"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit54"><name><surname>Nelson</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Konze</surname><given-names>P. M.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dronskowski</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>First-Principles
Chemical Bonding
Study of Manganese Carbodiimide, MnNCN, As Compared to Manganese Oxide,
MnO</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. A</source>
<year>2017</year>, <volume>121</volume> (<issue>40</issue>), <fpage>7778</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>7786</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpca.7b08218</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28933545</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref55"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit55"><name><surname>Nelson</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Ertural</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>George</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Deringer</surname><given-names>V. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Hautier</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dronskowski</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>LOBSTER: Local
Orbital Projections, Atomic Charges,
and Chemical-Bonding Analysis from Projector-Augmented-Wave-Based
Density-Functional Theory</article-title>. <source>J. Comput. Chem.</source>
<year>2020</year>, <volume>41</volume> (<issue>21</issue>), <fpage>1931</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1940</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jcc.26353</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32531113</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref56"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit56"><name><surname>Maintz</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Deringer</surname><given-names>V. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tchougr&#x000e9;eff</surname><given-names>A.
L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dronskowski</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>LOBSTER: A
tool to extract chemical bonding from plane-wave based DFT</article-title>. <source>J. Comput. Chem.</source>
<year>2016</year>, <volume>37</volume> (<issue>11</issue>), <fpage>1030</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>1035</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jcc.24300</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26914535</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref57"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit57"><name><surname>Maintz</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Deringer</surname><given-names>V. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tchougr&#x000e9;eff</surname><given-names>A.
L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dronskowski</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Analytic projection
from plane-wave and PAW wavefunctions and Application to chemical-bonding
analysis in solids</article-title>. <source>J. Comput. Chem.</source>
<year>2013</year>, <volume>34</volume> (<issue>29</issue>), <fpage>2557</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>2567</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/jcc.23424</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24022911</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref58"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit58"><name><surname>Dronskowski</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Bloechl</surname><given-names>P. E.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Crystal
orbital Hamilton populations (COHP): energy-resolved
visualization of chemical bonding in solids based on density-functional
calculations</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem.</source>
<year>1993</year>, <volume>97</volume> (<issue>33</issue>), <fpage>8617</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>8624</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/j100135a014</pub-id>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref59"><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" id="cit59"><name><surname>Deringer</surname><given-names>V. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Tchougr&#x000e9;eff</surname><given-names>A. L.</given-names></name>; <name><surname>Dronskowski</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name>
<article-title>Crystal orbital
Hamilton population (COHP) analysis as projected from plane-wave basis
sets</article-title>. <source>J. Phys. Chem. A</source>
<year>2011</year>, <volume>115</volume> (<issue>21</issue>), <fpage>5461</fpage>&#x02013;<lpage>5466</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/jp202489s</pub-id>.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21548594</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>