<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.3 20210610//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-3-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.3"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//Springer-Verlag//DTD A++ V2.4//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName A++V2.4.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.4?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName springer2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Nat Commun</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Nat Commun</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Nature Communications</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2041-1723</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Nature Publishing Group UK</publisher-name><publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">10328938</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">39636</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-39636-6</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Dynamic gel as artificial interphase layer for ultrahigh-rate and large-capacity lithium metal anode</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Chao</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Jiaming</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>Benrui</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>Qianwen</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-5858-9247</contrib-id><name><surname>Xiong</surname><given-names>Xunhui</given-names></name><address><email>esxxiong@scut.edu.cn</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.79703.3a</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1764 3838</institution-id><institution>School of Environment and Energy, Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Advanced Energy Storage Materials, </institution><institution>South China University of Technology, </institution></institution-wrap>Guangzhou, 510640 P. R. China </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>7</day><month>7</month><year>2023</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="pmc-release"><day>7</day><month>7</month><year>2023</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2023</year></pub-date><volume>14</volume><elocation-id>4018</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>27</day><month>9</month><year>2022</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>21</day><month>6</month><year>2023</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2023</copyright-statement><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract id="Abs1"><p id="Par1">Constructing a stable artificial solid-electrolyte interphase has become one of the most effective strategies to overcome the poor reversibility of lithium metal anode, yet the protection role is still insufficient at elevated current densities over 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and large areal capacities over 10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>. Herein, we propose a dynamic gel with reversible imine groups, which is prepared <italic>via</italic> a cross linking reaction between flexible dibenzaldehyde-terminated telechelic poly(ethylene glycol) and rigid chitosan, to fabricate a protective layer for Li metal anode. The as-prepared artificial film shows combined merits of high Young&#x02019;s modulus, strong ductility and high ionic conductivity. When the artificial film is fabricated on a lithium metal anode, the thin protective layer shows a dense and uniform surface owing to the interactions between the abundant polar groups and lithium metal. Besides, the polar groups in the artificial film can homogenize the distribution of Li<sup>+</sup> at the electrode/electrolyte interface. As a result, cycle stability over 3200&#x02009;h under an areal capacity of 10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and a current density of 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> has been obtained for the protected lithium metal anodes. Moreover, cycling stability and rate capability has been also improved in the full cells.</p></abstract><abstract id="Abs2" abstract-type="web-summary"><p id="Par2">Achieving stable lithium metal anodes under large current densities over 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and area capacities over 10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> remains a critical challenge. Here, authors propose a dynamic gel as protect layer for lithium metal anode to facilitate with the Young&#x02019;s modulus, flexibility and ionic conductivity, thus to stabilize the lithium metal anode.</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="npg-subject"><title>Subject terms</title><kwd>Batteries</kwd><kwd>Batteries</kwd><kwd>Batteries</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="FundRef">https://doi.org/10.13039/501100001809</institution-id><institution>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source><award-id>51874142</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name><surname>Xiong</surname><given-names>Xunhui</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#x000a9; Springer Nature Limited 2023</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1" sec-type="introduction"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par3">The rapid development of electric vehicles in the recent years imposes increasing researches on high-energy-density lithium-ion batteries (LIBs). Among different anode candidates, Li metal has attracted numerous attentions due to its high theoretical specific capacity (3860&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) and the lowest redox potential (&#x02212;3.04&#x02009;V)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref></sup>. However, the poor reversibility and Li dendrite growth hinder the commercial applications of Li metal anode. Because of the active chemical properties, Li metal can react with solvents and Li salts in the organic electrolytes to form a thin solid electrolyte interface (SEI) layer on surface to prevent the continuous side reactions<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref></sup>. However, the fragile SEI film cannot accommodate the huge volume changes during the charge/discharge processes, and the cracks in the SEI will aggravate the parasitic reactions between the fresh Li metal and electrolyte, resulting in the rapid deterioration of Coulombic efficiency (CE) and cycle life of the Li metal batteries (LMBs). Besides, the non-uniformity of the native SEI film in structure and composition will induce the uneven deposition of Li ions, which will lead to the generation of Li dendrites and even safety hazards<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref></sup>. These concerns can be accelerated when the LMBs are operated at elevated current densities and areal capacities. Therefore, constructing an artificial SEI layer to replace the native SEI has been proposed to stabilize the Li metal anode.</p><p id="Par4">An ideal artificial SEI layer has been emphasized to possess excellent chemical stability to prevent the reaction between Li metal and electrolyte, high ionic conductivity to homogenize the Li ions transfer<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref></sup>. Besides, the mechanical properties of the artificial SEI layer, especially the Young&#x02019;s modulus and flexibility, also play a critical role in stabilizing the Li metal anode<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref></sup>. A high Young&#x02019;s modulus is desirable to block the continually growth of Li dendrites, while a superior flexibility is indispensable to accommodate the severe volumetric variations and avoid the generation of cracks in the SEI layer during the repetitive cycles. However, it remains a critical challenge to simultaneously achieve high Young&#x02019;s modulus and strong flexibility for artificial SEI layers. An inorganic SEI layers has ultrahigh Young&#x02019;s modulus, while the brittleness nature and poor contact with Li metal cannot guarantee a long-term stable cycling at large areal capacities<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref></sup>. The polymer SEI layers can effectively buffer the volume changes than inorganic SEI layers during the stripping/plating processes. However, they suffer from insufficient mechanical modulus and cannot suppress the growth of Li dendrite. Besides, the poor ionic conductivity of polymer SEI layers results in nonuniform Li<sup>+</sup> diffusion and uneven Li deposition<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref></sup>. To overcome these problems, incorporating the inorganic components into polymer matrixes to fabricate hybrid SEI layers has been proposed<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref></sup>. The hybrid SEI layers inherit the individual advantages of two components and demonstrate suitable mechanical strength and flexibility to stabilize the Li metal anode. However, the nanostructured inorganic components in the hybrid SEI layers show notable tendencies to agglomerate because of the high surface energy as well as the inferior compatibility with polymers<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref></sup>, which will induce the uneven distribution of Li<sup>+</sup> flux and the inhomogeneous Li deposition. Accordingly, most of the Li anodes protected by the hybrid SEI layers cannot deliver satisfactory stability at high current density (&#x02265;10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) and large areal capacity (&#x02265;10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>). Therefore, it remains a critical challenge to develop advanced SEI layers that simultaneously possess adequate mechanical properties as well as high ionic conductivity to achieve stable Li metal anode under high current density and areal capacity.</p><p id="Par5">Herein, we propose a dynamic gel to fabricate a robust artificial layer to achieve stable Li metal anode under both ultrahigh current densities and areal capacity. The dynamic gel is prepared through a cross-linking reaction between chitosan (CS) and dibenzaldehyde-terminated telechelic poly(ethylene glycol) (DF-PEG-DF) in dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO) solvent. Benefiting from the flexible polyethylene glycol (PEG) backbone and the ionic-conductive, rigid chitosan component, the CS/DF-PEG-DF SEI layer is endowed with adequate ductility, favorable mechanical strength and high ionic conductivity. Furthermore, the rich polar groups in the CS provide a large number of interaction sites for the efficient adhesion to Li metal and homogeneous distribution of Li<sup>+</sup> at the Li/electrolyte interface. As a result, the CS/DF-PEG-DF coated Li anode (CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li) shows an unprecedented plating/stripping cyclability more than 3200 h at both high current density of 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and large areal capacity of 10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> in symmetrical cells. Besides, even under ultrahigh current density of 50&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and areal capacity of 50&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>, the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode delivers a long-term stability over 600&#x02009;h. Furthermore, when coupled with high-loading LiFePO<sub>4</sub> (LFP) cathode (~20&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>), the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode demonstrates dramatically enhanced cycle performance and rate capability than the bare Li counterpart.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2" sec-type="results"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Preparation and characterization of the dynamic gel</title><p id="Par6">As shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref>, the CS/DF-PEG-DF dynamic gel was prepared by cross linking the chitosan and DF-PEG-DF <italic>via</italic> a rapid Schiff reaction in DMSO solvent. The solvent forms a gel solid after mixing for two minutes (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref>), which is caused by the reaction between the amino group in chitosan and the benzaldehyde group in DF-PEG-DF. To verify the speculation, <sup>1</sup>H NMR spectra of DF-PEG-DF and CS/DF-PEG-DF were studied. Compared with DF-PEG-DF, CS/DF-PEG-DF shows an obvious peak of Schiff base at the chemical shift of 8.37&#x02009;ppm (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1c</xref> and Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>. The existence of reversible imine bonds in Schiff base endows the CS/DF-PEG-DF with excellent self-healing ability, which can be observed from the gradual closing hole in the center of the gel (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1d</xref>). The superior self-healing ability of CS/DF-PEG-DF gels is also demonstrated by testing the rheological properties of the CS/DF-PEG-DF gels (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref>). When the CS/DF-PEG-DF gel was dried at 30&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 12&#x02009;h in a glove box, CS/DF-PEG-DF film with DMSO content of 5.1&#x02009;wt.% was obtained (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref>), and then the physicochemical properties of as-obtained film were evaluated. Arising from the high Young&#x02019;s modulus of CS (2.3&#x02009;GPa, Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4a</xref>), CS/DF-PEG-DF film shows a high mechanical strength of 1.0&#x02009;GPa (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1e</xref>), much higher than that of DF-PEG-DF (164&#x02009;MPa, Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4b</xref>). Tensile tests were also performed to study the ductility of CS/DF-PEG-DF film (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1f</xref>). Compared with the brittle nature of CS, the elongation at break of CS/DF-PEG-DF can reach up to 18.5%. Obviously, CS/DF-PEG-DF film displays a combined merit of superior ductility and high mechanical strength, which is desired for the protective layer for Li metal anode.<fig id="Fig1"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><title>The design and mechanical property of CS/DF-PEG-DF film.</title><p><bold>a</bold> Schematic diagram of the cross-linking reaction between DF-PEG-DF and CS to form gel. <bold>b</bold> Photographs of the CS/DF-PEG-DF gel formation process. <bold>c</bold>
<sup>1</sup>H NMR spectrum of DF-PEG-DF and DF-PEG-DF with CS in CDCl<sub>3</sub>. <bold>d</bold> The images of self-healing process of CS/DF-PEG-DF at room temperature. <bold>e</bold> Young&#x02019;s modulus mapping of CS/DF-PEG-DF film. <bold>f</bold> Stress-strain curves of CS and CS/DF-PEG-DF film.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_Fig1_HTML" id="d32e463"/></fig></p><p id="Par7">Meanwhile, the electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) measurements show that the CS/DF-PEG-DF film exhibits a high ion conductivity of 9.33&#x02009;&#x000d7;&#x02009;10<sup>&#x02212;5</sup>&#x02009;S&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> at room temperature (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">5</xref>), which is much higher than that of PEO (10<sup>&#x02212;10</sup>&#x02009;S&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref></sup>, as well as 4&#x02212;5 orders of magnitude higher than the natural SEI components LiF (10<sup>&#x02212;9</sup>&#x02009;S&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) and Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> (10<sup>&#x02212;8</sup>&#x02009;S&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref></sup>. The ultra-high ionic conductivity of the CS/DF-PEG-DF film is attributed to the hydroxyl group on CS, which can facilitate Li<sup>+</sup> transfer by forming a continuous hopping pathway for Li<sup>+</sup> and prevent the migration of PF<sub>6</sub><sup>-</sup> anions <italic>via</italic> hydrogen bonds<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref></sup>. Besides, the PEG grafting can break the hydrogen bonds in the CS molecule, releasing more amino and hydroxyl groups on the chitosan backbone to interact with the anion and then accelerate the Li<sup>+</sup> transfer<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref></sup>. This phenomenon is also confirmed by the effect of PEG grafting on the Li-ion transference number (<italic>t</italic><sub><italic>Li+</italic></sub>) of CS/DF-PEG-DF. As shown in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">6</xref>, the <italic>t</italic><sub><italic>Li+</italic></sub> of CS/DF-PEG-DF is calculated to be 0.76, much higher than that of PEO (0.48)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref></sup>. When CS/DF-PEG-DF is proposed as an artificial layer for Li metal anode, the superior ionic conductivity with high Li-ion transference number can effectively reduce the interface impedance and alleviate the uneven ion flux.</p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Characterization of the artificial SEI layer</title><p id="Par8">To further clarify whether the CS/DF-PEG-DF film is suitable for artificial SEI layer for Li metal anode, the chemical stability of CS/DF-PEG-DF film was also investigated. As shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2a</xref> and Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">7</xref> and <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">8</xref>, DF-PEG-DF is soluble in both ester and ether electrolyte, however, CS/DF-PEG-DF film demonstrates excellent chemical stability in both of two electrolytes. Therefore, the cross-linking reaction can also remarkably change the chemical properties of individual components. Then the chemical stability of CS/DF-PEG-DF film with Li metal was evaluated. After sandwiched by two Li foils, the chemical-structure change of the as-obtained film (CS/DF-PEG-DF/Li) was studied with the solid-state <sup>1</sup>H nuclear magnetic resonance (<sup>1</sup>H SSNMR) and Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FT-IR). As shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2b</xref>, the peak at 4.0&#x02009;ppm in CS/DF-PEG-DF film can be assigned to the -OH in CS<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref></sup>, and the absence of this peak in CS/DF-PEG-DF-Li film suggests that the hydroxyl group in CS is consumed by the Li metal. The FT-IR spectroscopy in CS/DF-PEG-DF film shows strong intensity of the -NH<sub>2</sub> and -OH groups, which are located at 1569 and 3365&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2c</xref>), respectively<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref></sup>, while a great decrease of these two groups can be observed in the CS/DF-PEG-DF/Li film. Meanwhile, the characteristic peak at 1636&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> in CS/DF-PEG-DF/Li film, which can be indexed to the -C&#x02009;=&#x02009;<italic>N</italic> group<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref></sup>, is well maintained and experiences no obvious changes. Therefore, the <sup>1</sup>H SSNMR and FT-IR results demonstrate that the chemical reaction with Li metal is mainly occurred at -OH and -NH<sub>2</sub> groups in CS/DF-PEG-DF film.<fig id="Fig2"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><title>Reaction mechanism and chemical stability of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li.</title><p><bold>a</bold> The chemical stability of CS/DF-PEG-DF film in different electrolytes. <bold>b</bold>
<sup>1</sup>H SSNMR spectra and (<bold>c</bold>) FTIR spectra of CS/DF-PEG-DF and CS/DF-PEG-DF/Li. <bold>d</bold> Cross-section SEM image and (<bold>e</bold>) AFM image of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li formed by adding 50&#x02009;&#x003bc;L CS/DF-PEG-DF/DMSO solution. <bold>f</bold> Linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) curves of Li||PEG or CS/DF-PEG-DF||stainless steel (SS) batteries. <bold>g</bold> Photographs of the bare Li and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode exposed in ambient air for different minutes.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_Fig2_HTML" id="d32e659"/></fig></p><p id="Par9">The high Young&#x02019;s modulus, superior ductility, ultrahigh ionic conductivity and excellent chemical stability in the electrolyte enable CS/DF-PEG-DF film to be a promising protective layer for Li metal anode. To fabricate a thin CS/DF-PEG-DF film on surface of Li metal, CS solution and DF-PEG-DF solution in DMSO were mixed with a volume ratio of 1:1 by magnetic stirring for tens of seconds and then drop-coated on a Li foil immediately. The solution on Li metal becomes a transparent gel within two minutes, and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode is obtained after DMSO evaporation at 30&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 12&#x02009;h. Benefiting from the abundant polar groups in CS/DF-PEG-DF, the protective layers in various thicknesses from 180 to 1230&#x02009;nm are strongly adhered to the Li metal and show smooth and dense surface morphology (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2d</xref> and Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">9</xref> and <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">10</xref>), which can be confirmed by the atomic force microscope (AFM) analysis. As exhibited in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2e</xref>, the thin CS/DF-PEG-DF protection layer on Li metal shows the root mean square roughness (Rq) and average roughness (Ra) are as low as 20.2 and 16.1&#x02009;nm, respectively. Besides, the dense feature of the protective layer can be verified by enhanced air stability of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode. When bare Li and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode are exposed in air with a humidity of about 40%, the bare Li turns to black after 1&#x02009;min (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2g</xref>). However, the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode can keep the metallic luster for 20&#x02009;min under the same condition. Furthermore, the CS/DF-PEG-DF protective layer with DMSO content of 0.6&#x02009;wt.% retains a high mechanical strength of 1.1&#x02009;GPa after reaction with Li metal (Supplementary Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3b</xref> and Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">11a</xref>). After immersion in the electrolyte for 24&#x02009;h, the mechanical strength of protective layer experiences a slight drop to 810&#x02009;MPa (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">11b</xref>). Nevertheless, the ductility of CS/DF-PEG-DF film is well maintained after reaction with Li and even undergoes an obvious increase after immersed in electrolyte, as shown in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">12</xref>. Linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) curve indicates that the electrochemical stability of CS/DF-PEG-DF artificial layer is increased to 4.2 V (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2f</xref>), much higher than that of PEG layer (3.8 V), suggesting that CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode can be paired with high-voltage cathode to achieve high energy density.</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Li plating/stripping performance of symmetric cells</title><p id="Par10">To demonstrate the capability of CS/DF-PEG-DF protective layer in enhancing the interfacial stability of Li metal anode, the stripping/plating cycling in the symmetric cells in ether electrolyte were studied. The symmetric cells employing CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode with different thicknesses of protective layers were fabricated to achieve the best electrochemical performances. As shown in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">13</xref>, DMSO has been demonstrated to react with Li metal, however, the reaction products on Li metal cannot improve the electrochemical performances of Li metal anode (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">14</xref>). Meanwhile, CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode with too thin or too thick artificial layers cannot deliver desirable cycling performances (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">15</xref>). When the thickness of protective layer was set at 180&#x02009;nm, CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode demonstrates the longest cycle life. Specifically, the symmetric cell with CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode exhibits an unprecedented cycle stability over 3200&#x02009;h under a high areal capacity of 10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> at 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3a</xref>). The regular yet flat voltage profiles as well as the stable overpotential in the whole cycling processes illustrate the rapid Li<sup>+</sup> transfer kinetics and favorable interfacial stabilities (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3b</xref>). In vast contrast, the cells with bare Li anode show higher overpotentials over 500&#x02009;mV with severe voltage oscillation, and internal short-circuit is observed after cycling for 54&#x02009;h owing to the growth of Li dendrites. The substantially enhanced interfacial stability of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode is also proved by the electrochemical impedance spectroscopy during the cycling (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">16</xref>), which shows the interfacial impedance of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li electrode remains stable after 10 cycles.<fig id="Fig3"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><title>Electrochemical performance of symmetric Li||Li cells.</title><p><bold>a</bold> Voltage profiles of bare Li and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode in symmetric cell at 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> under a fixed capacity of 10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>. <bold>b</bold> The corresponding enlarged voltage profiles of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode for different cycles. <bold>c</bold> Voltage profiles of bare Li and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode in symmetric cell at current density of 50&#x02009;mA cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and high capacity of 50&#x02009;mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>. <bold>d</bold> Cycle stability of symmetrical cells employing bare Li and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li with thickness of 50&#x02009;&#x003bc;m at 4&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> under a fixed capacity of 8&#x02009;mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>. <bold>e</bold> Comparison of maximum current density and the corresponding cycle life of the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li with the representative protected Li metal anode (Data is obtained from Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1</xref> in Supporting Information).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_Fig3_HTML" id="d32e772"/></fig></p><p id="Par11">Except for the exceptional cycling stability, the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode also delivers extraordinary rate capabilities. When the current density was dramatically increased to 50&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>, the symmetrical cell with CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode can maintain a low and steady overpotential at 276.2&#x02009;mV for 800&#x02009;h (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">17</xref>). Furthermore, the cell with CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode can even run for 600&#x02009;h with a steady overpotential of 400.4&#x02009;mV at a large areal capacity of 50&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> at 50&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3c</xref>). In striking contrast, huge fluctuations are emerged in voltage curves for the cell with bare Li anode in the initial cycles and the cell failure happens within 11&#x02009;h. To verify the protection role of CS/DF-PEG-DF layer, the electrochemical performances of a thin Li foil (~50&#x02009;&#x003bc;m) protected by CS/DF-PEG-DF layer were also investigated. Impressively, stable Li plating/stripping for 380&#x02009;h is achieved at a fixed capacity of 8&#x02009;mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and a current density of 4&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3d</xref>). Considering the thin Li anode shows a capacity of 9.09&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">18</xref>), the utilization ratio of metallic Li can reach up to 88.0%. To the best of our knowledge, the cycle stability and utilization rate of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode stands at the highest level compared with the reported Li anodes protected by different artificial layers (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3e</xref>, Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref>).</p><p id="Par12">To clarify the role of the unique physicochemical properties of CS/DF-PEG-DF protection layer, the electrochemical performances of symmetric cells with DF-PEG-DF@Li or CS@Li anode were also studied. As shown in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">19</xref>, DF-PEG-DF@Li and CS@Li anodes can only maintain stable plating/stripping cycling for 150&#x02009;h and 400&#x02009;h under a capacity of 10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> at 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>, respectively, which are much poorer than that of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode. Besides, top-view SEM images in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">20</xref> show that numerous cracks are observed on both DF-PEG-DF@Li and CS@Li anodes after 50 cycles. For DF-PEG-DF@Li anode, the DF-PEG-DF layer was firstly dissolved in the electrolyte, and then the complex reaction between Li<sup>+</sup> and DF-PEG-DF can reform a protective layer <italic>via</italic> absorbing on the surface of Li metal<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref></sup>. The DF-PEG-DF-based artificial layer cannot effectively regulate the deposition of Li<sup>+</sup> owing to the poor ionic conductivity, leading to the formation of Li dendrites at high current density. Meanwhile, the DF-PEG-DF-based layer has no adequate mechanical strength to withstand the high stress generated by the Li dendrites, and then a large number of dendrites appear at the cracks, (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">20a</xref>). For CS@Li anode, the high ionic conductivity of CS (10<sup>&#x02212;4</sup>&#x02009;S&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref></sup> can increase the uniformity of Li deposition, however, the rigid CS protective layer is still fractured (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">20b</xref>), which is attributed to the huge volume expansion at high areal capacity of 10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>. In sharp contrast, CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li still keeps a very smooth and dense surface without any protrusions or cracks (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">20c</xref>). It can be observed that the high ionic conductivity of protective layer can promote uniform deposition of Li<sup>+</sup>, however, the lack of flexibility will still cause fracture of artificial SEI due to volume expansion during cycling, especially at a large deposition capacity. Besides, the high mechanical strength is also highly desirable for protective layer to block the continuous growth of Li dendrites. Therefore, the combined merits of high mechanical strength, strong ductility and ultrahigh ionic conductivity of the CS/DF-PEG-DF artificial layer have made a critical role in improving the stability of Li metal anode.</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>The role of artificial SEI layer in stabilizing Li metal anode</title><p id="Par13">To gain more reason for the enhanced interfacial stability of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode, in-situ optical microscopy was used to monitor the Li deposition process at a high current density of 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> (Supplementary information Movie&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">S1</xref>). As shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4a</xref>, Li dendrites are observed on the bare Cu foil after deposition for 1 min, and the Li dendrites keep gradual growth during the following 20&#x02009;min. Notably, the Li deposition on the Cu foil coated by CS/DF-PEG-DF layer is homogenized. The CS/DF-PEG-DF@Cu electrode maintains a very smooth and uniform surface, and no dendrites are found in the whole deposition process (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4b</xref>). The regulated Li deposition can be attributed to the abundant hydroxyl groups in the CS/DF-PEG-DF. It has been reported that the interaction between the hydroxyl groups and Li<sup>+</sup> can homogenize the distribution of Li<sup>+</sup> at the molecular level and facilitate the layer-by-layer deposition of Li<sup>+</sup><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref></sup>. Besides, the surface chemistries of cycled Li metal anodes were also studied <italic>via</italic> X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analysis to illustrate the advantage of CS/DF-PEG-DF layer. In the C 1<italic>s</italic> spectrum of bare Li after cycling in symmetric cells (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4c, d</xref>), the peak at 289.9 eV corresponds to CO<sub>3</sub><sup>2&#x02212;</sup>, which mainly comes from the decomposition product of solvent through the side reactions<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref></sup>. Obviously, the peak intensity of CO<sub>3</sub><sup>2&#x02212;</sup> for bare Li is much stronger than that of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode, indicating that the stable CS/DF-PEG-DF protective layer effectively can inhibit the penetration of the electrolyte and reduce the decomposition of the solvents. In the F 1<italic>s</italic> spectra in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4e, f</xref>, the peaks at 684.9 and 688.7&#x02009;eV can be attributed to LiF from the decomposition of Bis(trifluoromethane)sulfonimide (LiTFSI) and -CF<sub>3</sub> in LiTFSI<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref></sup>, respectively. It has been reported that the naturally generated SEI on Li metal contains two layers, including the inner inorganic layer and outer organic layer<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref></sup>. Owing to the continuous side reaction between the electrolyte and the bare Li metal, the cycled bare Li is covered by a thick layer of organic components, very weak signal of LiF can be observed in the F 1<italic>s</italic> XPS spectrum. Meanwhile, prior to XPS characterization, the cycled Li metal was rinsed with DOL solvent to remove the residual LiTFSI, resulting in a low amount of -CF<sub>3</sub> on the cycled Li metal anode. However, a high content of LiF is observed on surface of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode. According to the previous reports<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref></sup>, the remaining polar groups in CS/DF-PEG-DF layer can induce the break of C-F bond in LiTFSI <italic>via</italic> forming hydrogen bonds with LiTFSI, therefore forming a thin LiF layer on top surface CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode. The formed thin LiF layer during the initial cycles in the initial cycles can further enhance the chemical and structural stability of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode in the following long-term cycles, which can be attributed to the ultra-high shear modulus, low surface diffusion barrier and high surface energy of LiF<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref></sup>. In the S 2<italic>p</italic> XPS spectra, the peak at 167.1&#x02009;eV can be ascribed to Li<sub><italic>x</italic></sub>SO<sub><italic>y</italic></sub> (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">21</xref>), a typical decomposition product of the LiTFSI, while the peak at 169.1&#x02009;eV comes from the residual LiTFSI<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref></sup>. Similar with F 1<italic>s</italic> XPS spectra, the S 2<italic>p</italic> XPS spectra on the cycled bare Li metal anode are very weak. Therefore, XPS results show that the CS/DF-PEG-DF protective layer effectively reduces the consumption of electrolyte and enhances the stability of Li metal anode.<fig id="Fig4"><label>Fig. 4</label><caption><title>In situ Optical microscopy and SEI compositions of bare Li and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li electrode.</title><p>In-situ optical images of Li deposition on (<bold>a</bold>) bare Cu and (<bold>b</bold>) CS/DF-PEG-DF@Cu in Li||Cu cells at different minutes (Scale bar, 100&#x02009;&#x003bc;m); C 1<italic>s</italic> XPS spectra of (<bold>c</bold>) bare Li and (<bold>d</bold>) CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anodes after 10 cycles at 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> under a capacity of 10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>; F 1<italic>s</italic> XPS spectra of (<bold>e</bold>) bare Li and (<bold>f</bold>) CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anodes after 10 cycles at 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> under a capacity of 10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>. <bold>g</bold> Schematic diagram of Li plating/stripping behaviors for the bare Li and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_Fig4_HTML" id="d32e1042"/></fig></p><p id="Par14">According to the above discussions, the unprecedented cycle stability at high current density of 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and large areal capacity of 10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> can be summarized as following aspects (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4g</xref>). Firstly, the cross-linking reaction between CS and DF-PEG-DF achieves a balance between mechanical strength and ductility for the protective layer, which can block the continuous growth of Li dendrites and accommodate the volume changes during the stripping/plating processes. Secondly, the CS/DF-PEG-DF layer shows dense feature and strong interaction with Li metal owing to the rich polar groups, which can effectively prevent the side reaction at the Li/electrolyte interface. Besides, the abundant polar groups in CS/DF-PEG-DF layer can homogenize the distribution of Li<sup>+</sup> at the interface <italic>via</italic> their interactions. Lastly, the ultrahigh ionic conductivity as well as high Li<sup>+</sup> transference number can provide fast Li<sup>+</sup> transfer path in the CS/DF-PEG-DF artificial layer. These synergetic effects can thereby uniform the Li deposition and enhance the interfacial stability of Li metal anode.</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Coulombic efficiency and full cells performance</title><p id="Par15">Encouraged by the significantly enhanced interfacial stability, the reversibility of CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode was also investigated by the CE test in Li||Cu cells, in which Cu foil coated by CS/DF-PEG-DF layer (~180&#x02009;nm) was utilized as work electrode. The Aurbach method was used to simulate the behavior of Li plating/stripping under actual working conditions<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref></sup>, in which 5&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> Li was firstly deposited on Cu foil or CS/DF-PEG-DF@Cu, and then the cells were cycled at a current density of 1&#x02009;mA cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and a plating/stripping amount of 1&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5a</xref>). For CS/DF-PEG-DF@Cu, the irreversible Li capacity of 1.01&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> is consumed after 60 cycles, and the average CE is 98.5%. On the other hand, the deposited Li on bare Cu was completely consumed at the 13th cycle, and the charge potential reaches to 1.0&#x02009;V, with an average CE of 77.7%. The long-term reversibility of Li plating/stripping in Li&#x001c1;Cu batteries under extreme conditions was further analyzed. As shown in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">22a</xref>, the Li||CS/DF-PEG-DF@Cu battery maintains an average CE about 94.8% for 180 cycles at a current density of 1&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and a fixed capacity of 1&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>. Besides, the Li||CS/DF-PEG-DF@Cu battery exhibits an almost constant voltage distribution with an overpotential of ~50&#x02009;mV during 100 cycles (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">23</xref>). Even at higher current density and areal capacity, the Li||CS/DF-PEG-DF@Cu battery can keep a stable CE above 95.0% for 100 cycles (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">22b</xref>). In contrast, the CE of the Li||Cu battery with pristine Cu foil has dropped to 80% within 50 cycles, which shows that the Li metal without the protection of CS/DF-PEG-DF protective layer can continuously react with the electrolyte. The cycling CE results show that the CS/DF-PEG-DF protective layer on Li metal surface can suppress the side reactions between Li metal and electrolyte during the long-term cycling.<fig id="Fig5"><label>Fig. 5</label><caption><title>Electrochemical performance of Li||Cu half cells and Li||S/Li||LFP full cells.</title><p><bold>a</bold> CEs measured by Aurbach method of different electrodes in Li||Cu cells in ester electrolyte. <bold>b</bold> Cycle performances of Li||S and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li||S cells at 0.2 C. <bold>c</bold> Rate performances at various C-rates of the Li||S and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li||S cells. <bold>d</bold> Cycle performances of Li||LFP and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li||LFP cells at 0.5 C. <bold>e</bold> Rate performances at various C-rates of the Li||LFP and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li||LFP cells.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_Fig5_HTML" id="d32e1132"/></fig></p><p id="Par16">To investigate the potential application of the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode in practical batteries, the protected Li metal anode was paired with different cathodes to assemble the full cells. The electrochemical performances of full cells constructed by self-made sulfur/carbon cathode (~7&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode (600&#x02009;&#x003bc;m) were firstly investigated. As shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5b</xref> and Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">24a</xref>, the full cell with CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode delivers a capacity of 426.2&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> after 400 cycles at 0.2 C, with a capacity retention rate of 61.6%. However, the full cell with bare Li shows a similar capacity at the initial cycles and shows a rapid decrease after 100 cycles. Under the protection of CS/DF-PEG-DF layer, the Li-S full cell also shows much higher capacities than that with bare Li anode at high current densities from 0.5 to 2 C (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5c</xref>). To demonstrate the protection role of artificial SEI layer at a more practical addition, the electrochemical performances of a thin CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode (50&#x02009;&#x003bc;m) were also evaluated by coupling with a commercial high-loaded LiFePO<sub>4</sub> electrode (20&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>). As shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5d</xref> and Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">24b</xref>, Li||LFP cells assembled using bare Li and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li electrodes in the ester electrolyte also display similar capacities in the initial cycles. However, the capacity of the full cell with bare Li experiences a rapid drop from the 30<sup>th</sup> cycle, which can be attributed to the gradual consumption of electrolyte by the Li dendrites. The full cell with CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li can still delivers a high capacity of 82.9&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> after 100 cycles, with a capacity retention rate of 60.1%. Furthermore, the Li||LFP cells with CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode show enhanced rate performances at high rates of 1 C and 2 C (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5e</xref>). These results confirm that the cross-linked polymer protective layer can not only effectively stabilize the Li metal anode, but also boost the charge transfer and ionic transport kinetics.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec8" sec-type="discussion"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par17">In summary, the CS/DF-PEG-DF gel prepared by cross-linking reaction between CS and DF-PEG-DF has been proposed to fabricate a protective layer for dendrite-free Li metal anode. The CS/DF-PEG-DF protective layer provides adequate ductility and mechanical strength <italic>via</italic> combining the flexibility of PEG molecules and the rigidity of chitosan molecules, which can adapt to the volume changes and stress changes caused by Li dendrite growth during the intensive cycling processes. Besides, the abundant polar groups in the CS/DF-PEG-DF protective layer can not only ensure a strong adhesion to Li metal, but also homogenize the distribution of Li<sup>+</sup> at the Li/electrolyte interface. Furthermore, the ultrahigh ionic conductivity with high Li-ions transference number of CS/DF-PEG-DF SEI layer can alleviate the concentration gradients and enable rapid and homogeneous ion diffusion in the SEI layer. As a result, the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode demonstrates an unprecedented cycle stability over 3200&#x02009;h under a high areal capacity of 10&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> at 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>. A superior cycling stability is also achieved with an ultra-high Li utilization rate of 88.0%. When paired with high-loading cathodes, CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode also shows enhanced cycle stability and rate performance. We believe the principle of simultaneous superior mechanical properties and high ionic conductivity will be key factors of stable SEIs, which can shed light on interfacial design to stabilize Li metal anodes.</p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Methods</title><sec id="Sec10"><title>Materials</title><p id="Par18">All the materials were purchased from commercial sources and used as received. dibenzaldehyde-terminated telechelic poly(ethylene glycol) (DF-PEG-DF, Mw&#x02009;=&#x02009;2000, &#x0003e;95 %), Chitosan (CS, Macklin, Deacetylation 90%, Mw&#x02009;=&#x02009;200000), Salicylic acid (SA, Aldrich, AR), Dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO, Aldrich, Anhydrous Grade).</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Fabrication of the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode</title><p id="Par19">The fabrication of the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode was conducted in an argon-filled glove box, where the contents of both oxygen and H<sub>2</sub>O are less than 0.1&#x02009;ppm. The CS/DMSO solution (concentration of 1 wt%) was prepared by dissolving 0.1&#x02009;g Chitosan and 0.05&#x02009;g Salicylic acid in 10 g DMSO under agitated stirring for 1&#x02009;h. Similarly, a certain amount of DF-PEG-DF dissolved in DMSO was configured to be a 1&#x02009;wt% DF-PEG-DF/DMSO solution. Subsequently, the above two solutions were mixed with 1:1 volume ratio and strongly stirred for tens of seconds to obtain CS/DF-PEG-DF/DMSO solution. Finally, different volumes of CS/DF-PEG-DF/DMSO solution were dropped onto the surface of lithium metal within 2&#x02009;min, and the DMSO was evaporated after 12&#x02009;h at 30&#x02009;&#x000b0;C, the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode was obtained.</p><p id="Par20">For comparison, CS@Li, DF-PEG-DF@Li anodes were also fabricated under the same conditions except for using CS/DMSO, DF-PEG-DF/DMSO solution, respectively. CS, DF-PEG-DF and CS/DF-PEG-DF films have been also prepared by drop coating CS/DMSO, DF-PEG-DF/DMSO and CS/DF-PEG-DF/DMSO solutions on glass slides, followed by drying at 30&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 12&#x02009;h and a peeling process from glass slides. The CS/DF-PEG-DF/Li film was obtained by sandwiching the CS/DF-PEG-DF film between two Li foil for 12&#x02009;h. In addition, DMSO@Li was prepared by dropping DMSO (50&#x02009;&#x003bc;L) onto the Li foil under the same preparation conditions.</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Material characterization</title><p id="Par21">Rheology analyses were performed on a Haake Mars40 rheometer with parallel plate geometry (60&#x02009;mm in diameter) at 25&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. The mechanical properties of the materials were measured by MTS Exceed E44 multi-parameter testing machine. <sup>1</sup>H NMR spectra were recorded on a BRUKER ADVANCE III 600MHz/400M spectrometer. The morphology and structure of all electrodes were characterized by a field-emission scanning electron microscope (FE-SEM, Hitachi SU8010). Before testing, the cycled batteries were disassembled and rinsed with anhydrous 1,3-dioxolane (DOL) to remove the residual organic electrolyte and Li salts. Atomic Force Microscopy (AFM, Bruker DIMENSION ICON with a Nanoscope V controller) was performed to examine the roughness of Li metal anodes. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS, ESCALab220i-XL) with 300&#x02009;W Al K&#x003b1; radiations was carried out to confirm the composition of the sample surface. TGA measurement was performed under N<sub>2</sub> or Ar atmosphere on a NETZSCH STA 449F3 Jupiter in the temperature range of 30&#x02013;800&#x02009;&#x000b0;C or 25&#x02013;350&#x02009;&#x000b0;C (heating rate: 10&#x02009;&#x000b0;C&#x02009;min<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>). Fourier-transform infrared (FT-IR) spectra were recorded on a Nicolet IS50 FT-IR spectrometer. <sup>1</sup>H solid-state nuclear magnetic resonance (SSNMR) for CS/DF-PEG-DF and CS/DF-PEG-DF/Li film was conducted by JEOL JNM-ECZ600R 600 MHz NMR spectrometer.</p></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Electrochemical measurements</title><p id="Par22">2032 or 2025 type coin cells were used to investigate the electrochemical performances of the electrode. 1 M LiTFSI was dissolved in a mixture of DOL and 1,2-dimethoxyethane (DME, volume ratio 1:1) with 2 wt% LiNO<sub>3</sub> additive was selected as the electrolyte and <italic>&#x003a6;</italic> 19&#x02009;mm Celgard 2400 was served as the separator. For the symmetric Li||Li cell testing, two identical bare Li or CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li electrodes (thickness of 50&#x02009;&#x003bc;m, <italic>&#x003a6;</italic> 13&#x02009;mm or thickness of 600&#x02009;&#x003bc;m, <italic>&#x003a6;</italic> 16&#x02009;mm) were performed at various current density-capacity conditions to survey the Li stripping/plating behavior. To prepare the CS/DF-PEG-DF @Cu electrode, 50&#x02009;&#x003bc;L of CS/DF-PEG-DF/DMSO solution was dripped onto the surface of <italic>&#x003a6;</italic> 13&#x02009;&#x003bc;m single-sided Li/Cu anode (China Energy Lithium Co., Ltd. 50&#x02009;&#x003bc;m Li foil was calendered onto a 10&#x02009;&#x003bc;m Cu foil) after placing for 12 h to allow the evaporation of DMSO, the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Cu electrode was obtained. For the Li||Cu cell testing, the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Cu electrode was fully stripped Li metal up to 0.5 V (vs Li<sup>+</sup>/Li) under 0.5&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and then disassembled in the symmetric coin cell to obtain CS/DF-PEG-DF@Cu foil. To measure the cycling Coulombic efficiency, the CS/DF-PEG-DF@Cu or Cu foil was used as the working electrode and Li metal as the counter electrode. The fixed amount of Li was deposited on CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li or bare Cu foil, followed by stripping Li until the voltage reached up to 0.5&#x02009;V at the same current density. Aurbach tests<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref></sup> of Li||Cu cell CE were operated at 1&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> with the pre-plating Li of 5&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>, followed by reversible plating/stripping with 1.0&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>, 1.0&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>, and finally stripping to 1.0 V. This CE was calculated by this equation:<disp-formula id="Equ1"><label>1</label><alternatives><tex-math id="M1">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$${CE}=\frac{{Q}_{s}+{Q}_{c}\times n}{{Q}_{p}+{Q}_{c}\times n}$$\end{document}</tex-math><mml:math id="M2"><mml:mi>C</mml:mi><mml:mi>E</mml:mi><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>Q</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>s</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>Q</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>c</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mo>&#x000d7;</mml:mo><mml:mi>n</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>Q</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>p</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mo>+</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>Q</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>c</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mo>&#x000d7;</mml:mo><mml:mi>n</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac></mml:math><graphic xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_Article_Equ1.gif" position="anchor"/></alternatives></disp-formula>where <italic>Q</italic><sub><italic>s</italic></sub> is the stripping capacity at final, <italic>Q</italic><sub><italic>p</italic></sub> is the plating capacity at initial, <italic>Q</italic><sub><italic>c</italic></sub> is the constant plating/stripping capacity for each cycle, and <italic>n</italic> is the cycle number. For the Li||Li and Li||Cu cells, a fixed amount (50&#x02009;&#x003bc;L) of electrolyte was used in each coin battery. For the full cell systems, the <italic>&#x003a6;</italic> 10&#x02009;mm LiFePO<sub>4</sub> cathode electrode comes from commercial purchase, and its active substance load is 20 mg cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>. The cells composed of the as-prepared cathode and Li or CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li (50&#x02009;&#x003bc;m in thickness, <italic>&#x003a6;</italic> 13&#x02009;mm) were cycled in carbonate-based electrolyte (1.0 M LiPF<sub>6</sub> in EC:DMC:EMC=1:1:1 Vol%) at 0.5 C after 5 cycles of activation at 0.1 C in a voltage range of 2.0&#x02013;4.0 V. For the lithium-sulfur battery systems, the cathode electrode was fabricated by mixing the sulfur/mesoporous carbon composite<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref></sup>, polyvinylidene fluoride (PVDF), and acetylene black with a mass ratio of 90:3:7 dissolved in N-methyl-2-pyrrolidone (NMP). The gained slurry was coated onto Carbon coated Al foil and dried at 80&#x02009;&#x000b0;C under vacuum overnight. The sulfur loading of each <italic>&#x003a6;</italic> 10&#x02009;mm electrode is ~7 mg cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> in this work. The electrolyte consisted of 1 M LiTFSI and 2&#x02009;wt% LiNO<sub>3</sub> in the mixture of DOL and DME (1:1, v/v). The dosage of electrolyte is based on the proportion of adding 20&#x02009;&#x003bc;L electrolyte per 1 mg of active substance. The cells composed of the as-prepared cathode and Li or CS/DF-PEG-DF@Li anode (600&#x02009;&#x003bc;m in thickness, <italic>&#x003a6;</italic> 16&#x02009;mm) were cycled at 0.2 C after 5 cycles of activation at 0.1 C in a voltage range of 1.7&#x02013;2.8 V. All the above batteries were tested at 25&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. The electrochemical stability was evaluated through assembling the battery (Li||film||SS) by linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) from an open circuit state to 5.0&#x02009;V. The LSV was carried out at a scan rate of 0.1&#x02009;mV&#x02009;s<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) tests were measured on an electrochemical workstation (CHI660a, Shanghai Chenhua) in a frequency range between 10<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and 10<sup>5</sup>&#x02009;Hz. The ionic conductivity of CS/DF-PEG-DF was measured by a complex impedance method with a perturbation of 50&#x02009;mV in the frequency range of 0.1&#x02013;10<sup>5</sup>&#x02009;Hz at 25&#x02013;85&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. Symmetrical stainless-steel (SS)||CS/DF-PEG-DF (swollen by 3&#x02009;&#x003bc;L liquid electrolyte) ||SS cells were assembled to test the resistance value, and the corresponding ionic conductivity (&#x003c3;, in S&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) was calculated using the Equation:<disp-formula id="Equ2"><label>2</label><alternatives><tex-math id="M3">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\sigma=\frac{L}{{RS}}$$\end{document}</tex-math><mml:math id="M4"><mml:mi>&#x003c3;</mml:mi><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mi>L</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>R</mml:mi><mml:mi>S</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac></mml:math><graphic xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_Article_Equ2.gif" position="anchor"/></alternatives></disp-formula>Where the L, R, and S represent the thickness (0.1&#x02009;mm), ohmic resistance and area (16&#x02009;mm in diameter) of CS/DF-PEG-DF, respectively. Using Li||CS/DF-PEG-DF||Li cells the lithium-ion transference number (<inline-formula id="IEq1"><alternatives><tex-math id="M5">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$${t}_{{{Li}}^{+}}$$\end{document}</tex-math><mml:math id="M6"><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>t</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msup><mml:mrow><mml:mi>L</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>+</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:msup></mml:mrow></mml:msub></mml:math><inline-graphic xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_Article_IEq1.gif"/></alternatives></inline-formula>) was calculated by the method of Bruce and Vincent methode, according to the following equation:<disp-formula id="Equ3"><label>3</label><alternatives><tex-math id="M7">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$${t}_{{{Li}}^{+}}=\frac{{I}_{s}\left(\Delta V-{R}_{0}{I}_{0}\right)}{{I}_{0}\left(\Delta V-{R}_{s}{I}_{s}\right)}$$\end{document}</tex-math><mml:math id="M8"><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>t</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msup><mml:mrow><mml:mi>L</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo>+</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:msup></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>I</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>s</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mfenced close=")" open="("><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">&#x00394;</mml:mi><mml:mi>V</mml:mi><mml:mo>&#x02212;</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>R</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>0</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>I</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>0</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msub></mml:mrow></mml:mfenced></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>I</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mn>0</mml:mn></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:mfenced close=")" open="("><mml:mrow><mml:mi mathvariant="normal">&#x00394;</mml:mi><mml:mi>V</mml:mi><mml:mo>&#x02212;</mml:mo><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>R</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>s</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:msub><mml:msub><mml:mrow><mml:mi>I</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>s</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:msub></mml:mrow></mml:mfenced></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac></mml:math><graphic xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_Article_Equ3.gif" position="anchor"/></alternatives></disp-formula>Here, <italic>R</italic><sub>0</sub> is the interfacial resistance of the lithium electrode before the polarization, <italic>R</italic><sub>s</sub> is the interfacial resistance of the lithium electrode after the polarization, <italic>I</italic><sub>0</sub> is the current at the start of the polarization, and <italic>I</italic><sub>s</sub> is the steady-state current through the electrode during the polarization. &#x00394;<italic>V</italic> is the polarization potential (10&#x02009;mV). In-situ optical observation is performed by assembling the bare Li and CS/DF-PEG-DF@Cu anodes (the thickness of 50&#x02009;&#x003bc;m) into a quartz cell with a transparent quartz window (Kejing, STC-Q) in a glove box. The deposition process of Li was observed and recorded with a Wi-Fi box optical microscope camera (Belona, 100X-1000X). The current density is fixed at 10&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary information</title><sec id="Sec14"><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1"><media xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_MOESM1_ESM.pdf"><caption><p>Supplementary Information</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM2"><media xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_MOESM2_ESM.pdf"><caption><p>Description of Additional Supplementary Files</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM3"><media xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_MOESM3_ESM.mp4"><caption><p>Supplementary Movie 1</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></sec></body><back><app-group><app id="App1"><sec id="Sec15"><title>Source data</title><p id="Par26">
<media position="anchor" xlink:href="41467_2023_39636_MOESM4_ESM.xlsx" id="MOESM4"><caption><p>Source Data</p></caption></media>
</p></sec></app></app-group><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher&#x02019;s note</bold> Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><sec><title>Supplementary information</title><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41467-023-39636-6.</p></sec><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>We gratefully acknowledge the financial support from National Natural Science Foundation of China (51874142), Tip-top Scientific and Technical Innovative Youth Talents of Guangdong Special Support Program (2019TQ05L903) and Young Elite Scientists Sponsorship Program by CAST (2019QNRC001).</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>C.C. and X.X. conducted the experiments and designed the project and wrote the manuscript. J.Z., B.H. and Q.L. analyzed the results.</p></notes><notes notes-type="peer-review"><title>Peer review</title><sec id="FPar1"><title>Peer review information</title><p id="Par23"><italic>Nature Communications</italic> thanks the anonymous reviewer(s) for their contribution to the peer review of this work.</p></sec></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>The data generated in this study are provided in the Source Data file.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Sec15" ref-type="sec">Source data</xref> are provided with this paper.</p></notes><notes id="FPar2" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par24">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tarascon</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Is lithium the new gold?</article-title><source>Nat. Chem.</source><year>2010</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>510</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nchem.680</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 20489722?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20489722</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Self-stabilized and strongly adhesive supramolecular polymer protective layer enables ultrahigh-rate and large-capacity lithium-metal anode</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. -Int. Ed.</source><year>2020</year><volume>59</volume><fpage>2055</fpage><lpage>2060</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.201913351</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Suppressing dendrite growth by a functional electrolyte additive for robust Li metal anodes</article-title><source>Energy Storage Mater.</source><year>2019</year><volume>23</volume><fpage>701</fpage><lpage>706</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ensm.2019.02.026</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiong</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Grain-boundary-rich artificial sei layer for high-rate lithium metal anodes</article-title><source>Adv. Funct. Mater.</source><year>2022</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>2107249</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adfm.202107249</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Choudhury</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Mangal</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Agrawal</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Archer</surname><given-names>LA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A highly reversible room-temperature lithium metal battery based on crosslinked hairy nanoparticles</article-title><source>Nat. Commun.</source><year>2015</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>10101</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/ncomms10101</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 26634644?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26634644</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Quantifying inactive lithium in lithium metal batteries</article-title><source>Nature</source><year>2019</year><volume>572</volume><fpage>511</fpage><lpage>515</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41586-019-1481-z</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 31435056?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31435056</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Reviving the lithium metal anode for high-energy batteries</article-title><source>Nat. Nanotechnol.</source><year>2017</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>194</fpage><lpage>206</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nnano.2017.16</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 28265117?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28265117</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Electrolytes and interphases in li-ion batteries and beyond</article-title><source>Chem. Rev.</source><year>2014</year><volume>114</volume><fpage>11503</fpage><lpage>11618</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/cr500003w</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 25351820?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25351820</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Lithium metal anodes for rechargeable batteries</article-title><source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source><year>2014</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>513</fpage><lpage>537</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/C3EE40795K</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>An artificial solid electrolyte interphase with high li-ion conductivity, mechanical strength, and flexibility for stable lithium metal anodes</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2017</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>1605531</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adma.201605531</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Langdon</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Manthiram</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Crossover effects in batteries with high-nickel cathodes and lithium-metal anodes</article-title><source>Adv. Funct. Mater.</source><year>2021</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>2010267</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adfm.202010267</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Uniform high ionic conducting lithium sulfide protection layer for stable lithium metal anode</article-title><source>Adv. Energy Mater.</source><year>2019</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>1900858</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/aenm.201900858</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Bao</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Design principles of artificial solid electrolyte interphases for lithium-metal anodes</article-title><source>Cell Rep. Phys. Sci.</source><year>2020</year><volume>1</volume><fpage>100119</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.xcrp.2020.100119</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A robust li-intercalated interlayer with strong electron withdrawing ability enables durable and high-rate li metal anode</article-title><source>ACS Energy Lett.</source><year>2022</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>1594</fpage><lpage>1603</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.2c00395</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Mauger</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Armand</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Julien</surname><given-names>CM</given-names></name><name><surname>Zaghib</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Challenges and issues facing lithium metal for solid-state rechargeable batteries</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2017</year><volume>353</volume><fpage>333</fpage><lpage>342</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2017.04.018</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>R-M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Fatigue-resistant interfacial layer for safe lithium metal batteries</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. -Int. Ed.</source><year>2021</year><volume>60</volume><fpage>25508</fpage><lpage>25513</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.202111199</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>The failure of solid electrolyte interphase on li metal anode: structural uniformity or mechanical strength?</article-title><source>Adv. Energy Mater.</source><year>2020</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>1903645</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/aenm.201903645</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Flexible amalgam film enables stable lithium metal anodes with high capacities</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. -Int. Ed.</source><year>2019</year><volume>58</volume><fpage>18466</fpage><lpage>18470</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.201911800</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>P-F</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Ionic conductive polymers as artificial solid electrolyte interphase films in Li metal batteries-A review</article-title><source>Mater. Today</source><year>2020</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>140</fpage><lpage>159</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.mattod.2020.06.011</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Polymers in lithium-ion and lithium metal batteries</article-title><source>Adv. Energy Mater.</source><year>2021</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>2003239</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/aenm.202003239</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Quartarone</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Mustarelli</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Electrolytes for solid-state lithium rechargeable batteries: recent advances and perspectives</article-title><source>Chem. Soc. Rev.</source><year>2011</year><volume>40</volume><fpage>2525</fpage><lpage>2540</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c0cs00081g</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 21253642?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21253642</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Self-regulated phenomenon of inorganic artificial solid electrolyte interphase for lithium metal batteries</article-title><source>Nano Lett.</source><year>2020</year><volume>20</volume><fpage>4029</fpage><lpage>4037</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.nanolett.0c01400</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 32343592?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32343592</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Polymer-inorganic solid-electrolyte interphase for stable lithium metal batteries under lean electrolyte conditions</article-title><source>Nat. Mater.</source><year>2019</year><volume>18</volume><fpage>384</fpage><lpage>389</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41563-019-0305-8</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 30858569?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30858569</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Deng</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>In situ formation of polymer-inorganic solid-electrolyte interphase for stable polymeric solid-state lithium-metal batteries</article-title><source>Chem</source><year>2021</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>3052</fpage><lpage>3068</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.chempr.2021.06.019</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Adaptive formed dual-phase interface for highly durable lithium metal anode in lithium-air batteries</article-title><source>Energy Storage Mater.</source><year>2020</year><volume>28</volume><fpage>350</fpage><lpage>356</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ensm.2020.03.022</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Agglomeration-free composite solid electrolyte and enhanced cathode-electrolyte interphase kinetics for all-solid-state lithium metal batteries</article-title><source>Energy Storage Mater.</source><year>2022</year><volume>51</volume><fpage>19</fpage><lpage>28</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ensm.2022.06.025</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Tao</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Wei</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Synthesis of multiresponsive and dynamic chitosan-based hydrogels for controlled release of bioactive molecules</article-title><source>Biomacromolecules</source><year>2011</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>2894</fpage><lpage>2901</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/bm200423f</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 21699141?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21699141</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bedair</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name><surname>El-Sabbah</surname><given-names>MMB</given-names></name><name><surname>Fouda</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name><name><surname>Elaryian</surname><given-names>HM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Synthesis, electrochemical and quantum chemical studies of some prepared surfactants based on azodye and Schiff base as corrosion inhibitors for steel in acid medium</article-title><source>Corros. Sci.</source><year>2017</year><volume>128</volume><fpage>54</fpage><lpage>72</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.corsci.2017.09.016</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Reddy</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Kumar</surname><given-names>JS</given-names></name><name><surname>Rao</surname><given-names>US</given-names></name><name><surname>Chu</surname><given-names>PP</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Structural and ionic conductivity of PEO blend PEG solid polymer electrolyte</article-title><source>Solid State Ion-.</source><year>2006</year><volume>177</volume><fpage>253</fpage><lpage>256</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ssi.2005.11.014</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Conformal lithium fluoride protection layer on three-dimensional lithium by nonhazardous gaseous reagent freon</article-title><source>Nano Lett.</source><year>2017</year><volume>17</volume><fpage>3731</fpage><lpage>3737</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.nanolett.7b01020</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 28535068?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28535068</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Nanostructural and electrochemical evolution of the solid-electrolyte interphase on cuo nanowires revealed by cryogenic-electron microscopy and impedance spectroscopy</article-title><source>ACS Nano</source><year>2019</year><volume>13</volume><fpage>737</fpage><lpage>744</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsnano.8b08012</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 30589528?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30589528</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Copper-coordinated cellulose ion conductors for solid-state batteries</article-title><source>Nature</source><year>2021</year><volume>598</volume><fpage>590</fpage><lpage>596</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41586-021-03885-6</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 34671167?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34671167</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Dendrite-free, high-rate, long-life lithium metal batteries with a 3D cross-linked network polymer electrolyte</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2017</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>1604460</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adma.201604460</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A PEGylated chitosan as gel polymer electrolyte for lithium ion batteries</article-title><source>Polymers</source><year>2022</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>4552</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/polym14214552</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 36365545?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36365545</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Battaglia</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Polymer-inorganic nanocomposite coating with high ionic conductivity and transference number for a stable lithium metal anode</article-title><source>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</source><year>2020</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>41620</fpage><lpage>41626</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsami.0c13485</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 32803940?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32803940</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ali</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Apperley</surname><given-names>DC</given-names></name><name><surname>Eley</surname><given-names>CD</given-names></name><name><surname>Emsley</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>RK</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A solid-state NMR study of cellulose degradation</article-title><source>Cellulose</source><year>1996</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>77</fpage><lpage>90</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF02228792</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Imidazole-doped cellulose as membrane for fuel cells: structural and dynamic insights from solid-state NMR</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. C.</source><year>2016</year><volume>120</volume><fpage>19574</fpage><lpage>19585</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b07049</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tan</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Szeto</surname><given-names>Y-S</given-names></name><name><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A novel method to prepare chitosan/montmorillonite nanocomposites in the presence of hydroxy-aluminum oligomeric cations</article-title><source>Compos. Sci. Technol.</source><year>2008</year><volume>68</volume><fpage>2917</fpage><lpage>2921</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.compscitech.2007.10.007</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sarmento</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Ferreira</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Veiga</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Ribeiro</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Characterization of insulin-loaded alginate nanoparticles produced by ionotropic pre-gelation through DSC and FTIR studies</article-title><source>Carbohydr. Polym.</source><year>2006</year><volume>66</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>7</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2006.02.008</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Pranoto</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Rakshit</surname><given-names>SK</given-names></name><name><surname>Salokhe</surname><given-names>VM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Enhancing antimicrobial activity of chitosan films by incorporating garlic oil, potassium sorbate and nisin</article-title><source>LWT-Food Sci. Technol.</source><year>2005</year><volume>38</volume><fpage>859</fpage><lpage>865</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.lwt.2004.09.014</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Hao</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Rapid-forming and self-healing agarose-based hydrogels for tissue adhesives and potential wound dressings</article-title><source>Biomacromolecules</source><year>2018</year><volume>19</volume><fpage>980</fpage><lpage>988</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acs.biomac.7b01764</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 29451778?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29451778</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR42"><label>42.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Surface-based Li<sup>+</sup> complex enables uniform lithium deposition for stable lithium metal anodes</article-title><source>ACS Appl. Energ. Mater.</source><year>2019</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>4602</fpage><lpage>4608</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/acsaem.9b00929</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR43"><label>43.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wan</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Creber</surname><given-names>KAM</given-names></name><name><surname>Peppley</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name><surname>Bui</surname><given-names>VT</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Ionic conductivity of chitosan membranes</article-title><source>Polymer</source><year>2003</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>1057</fpage><lpage>1065</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0032-3861(02)00881-9</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR44"><label>44.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Toward critical electrode/electrolyte interfaces in rechargeable batteries</article-title><source>Adv. Funct. Mater.</source><year>2020</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>1909887</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adfm.201909887</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR45"><label>45.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Busche</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Dynamic formation of a solid-liquid electrolyte interphase and its consequences for hybrid-battery concepts</article-title><source>Nat. Chem.</source><year>2016</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>426</fpage><lpage>434</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nchem.2470</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 27102676?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27102676</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR46"><label>46.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shin</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Sastry</surname><given-names>AM</given-names></name><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>solid electrolyte interphase layer in Li-ion batteries: experimental and computational studies</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2015</year><volume>277</volume><fpage>169</fpage><lpage>179</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2014.11.120</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR47"><label>47.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Shi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Direct calculation of Li-Ion transport in the solid electrolyte interphase</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2012</year><volume>134</volume><fpage>15476</fpage><lpage>15487</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ja305366r</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 22909233?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22909233</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR48"><label>48.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Self-assembled monolayers direct a LiF-rich interphase toward long-life lithium metal batteries</article-title><source>Science</source><year>2022</year><volume>375</volume><fpage>739</fpage><lpage>745</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1126/science.abn1818</pub-id><?supplied-pmid 35175797?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35175797</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR49"><label>49.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A novel organic &#x0201c;polyurea&#x0201d; thin film for ultralong-life lithium-metal anodes via molecular-layer deposition</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2019</year><volume>31</volume><fpage>1806541</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/adma.201806541</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR50"><label>50.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Phenoxy radical-induced formation of dual-layered protection film for high-rate and dendrite-free lithium-metal anodes</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. -Int. Ed.</source><year>2021</year><volume>60</volume><fpage>26718</fpage><lpage>26724</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/anie.202110441</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR51"><label>51.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Adams</surname><given-names>BD</given-names></name><name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J-G</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Accurate determination of coulombic efficiency for lithium metal anodes and lithium metal batteries</article-title><source>Adv. Energy Mater.</source><year>2018</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>1702097</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/aenm.201702097</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR52"><label>52.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>FR</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A new insight into capacity fading of sulfurized polyacrylonitrile composite in carbonate electrolyte</article-title><source>J. Electroanal. Chem.</source><year>2021</year><volume>882</volume><fpage>114964</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jelechem.2020.114964</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>