<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.3 20210610//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-3-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" dtd-version="1.3" xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article"><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName journalpublishing3.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 3.0?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName jats2jats3.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><?properties open_access?><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Chem Sci</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Chem Sci</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Chemical Science</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">2041-6520</issn><issn pub-type="epub">2041-6539</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Royal Society of Chemistry</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">5934741</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">29780474</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">c8sc00041g</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1039/c8sc00041g</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Chemistry</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>A promising bulky anion based lithium borate salt for lithium metal batteries<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>
<fn id="fn1"><p>&#x02020;Electronic supplementary information (ESI) available: Experimental method, synthetic procedure, lithium ion transference number, impedance spectra, equivalent circuit diagram and additional XPS data. See DOI: <uri xlink:href="https://doi.org/10.1039/c8sc00041g">10.1039/c8sc00041g</uri></p></fn>
</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Qiao</surname><given-names>Lixin</given-names></name><xref rid="affa" ref-type="aff">a</xref><xref rid="affb" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Zili</given-names></name><xref rid="affb" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Bingbing</given-names></name><xref rid="affb" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>Gaojie</given-names></name><xref rid="affb" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Zhonghua</given-names></name><xref rid="affb" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Jun</given-names></name><xref rid="affb" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>Huiping</given-names></name><xref rid="affb" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Xiaochen</given-names></name><xref rid="affb" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>Suqi</given-names></name><xref rid="affc" ref-type="aff">c</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>Kun</given-names></name><xref rid="affa" ref-type="aff">a</xref><xref rid="affb" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>Shanmu</given-names></name><xref rid="affb" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Xinhong</given-names></name><xref rid="affa" ref-type="aff">a</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Guanglei</given-names></name><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-5987-7569</contrib-id><xref rid="affb" ref-type="aff">b</xref></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="affa"><label>a</label> College of Chemistry and Molecular Engineering , Qingdao University of Science &#x00026; Technology , Qingdao , 266042 , P. R. China . Email: <email>zxhhx2008@163.com</email>
</aff><aff id="affb"><label>b</label> Qingdao Industrial Energy Storage Research Institute , Qingdao Institute of Bioenergy and Bioprocess Technology , Chinese Academy of Sciences , Qingdao , 266101 , P. R. China . Email: <email>cuigl@qibebt.ac.cn</email> ; Tel: +86-532-80662746 </aff><aff id="affc"><label>c</label> School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering , Qingdao University , Qingdao , 266071 , P. R. China </aff><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>1</day><month>3</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>14</day><month>4</month><year>2018</year></pub-date><volume>9</volume><issue>14</issue><fpage>3451</fpage><lpage>3458</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>4</day><month>1</month><year>2018</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>28</day><month>2</month><year>2018</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>This journal is &#x000a9; The Royal Society of Chemistry 2018</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2018</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbynclicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This article is freely available. This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non Commercial 3.0 Unported Licence (CC BY-NC 3.0)</license-p></license></permissions><abstract abstract-type="toc"><p>
<graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-ga.jpg" id="ga" position="float"/>A promising lithium borate salt for next generation lithium metal batteries.</p></abstract><abstract><p>A new salt of lithium trifluoro(perfluoro-<italic>tert</italic>-butyloxyl)borate (LiTFPFB) which possesses a bulky fluoroalkoxyl functional group in the borate anion has been synthesized for high energy lithium metal batteries. The presence of the bulky fluoroalkoxyl group in the borate anion of LiTFPFB can facilitate ion dissociation and <italic>in situ</italic> generate a protective film on the Li anode. As a result, LiTFPFB possesses a dramatically improved ionic conductivity and LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cells using 1.0 M LiTFPFB/PC electrolyte exhibit improved capacity retention especially upon cycling at elevated temperature (60 &#x000b0;C). <italic>Ex situ</italic> surface analysis reveals that a protective film is formed on the lithium metal anode, which can inhibit further decomposition of the electrolyte. Furthermore, the LiTFPFB based electrolyte also imparts an excellent cycling performance to LiCoO<sub>2</sub>/Li metal cells for 500 cycles. The outstanding performance of the LiTFPFB salt demonstrates that it is a very promising baseline salt for next generation lithium metal batteries.</p></abstract></article-meta></front><body><sec><label>1.</label><title>Introduction</title><p>Current Li-ion batteries (LIBs) are widely used for portable electronics, electric vehicles, and stationary grid-energy storage devices.<xref rid="cit1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="cit2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref> The salt in LIBs plays a critical role in battery performance, being the primary source of free conducting lithium ions, and also mediates the formation of a solid electrolyte interface (SEI) at the electrodes. To date, LiPF<sub>6</sub> has been the most commonly used salt for commercial LIBs due to its optimum combination of ionic conductivity, electrochemical window, and electrode interfacial properties.<xref rid="cit3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref> However, the large-scale application of LiPF<sub>6</sub> has raised safety concerns due to its poor chemical and thermal stability in lithium ion batteries, especially for the promising lithium metal batteries.<xref rid="cit2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref> LiBF<sub>4</sub> (shown in <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="fig">Scheme 1</xref>) is well known for its superior thermal stability, non-corrosivity to the Al current collector, and improved low temperature performance arising from reduced charge-transfer resistance.<xref rid="cit4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="cit5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref> However, it is rarely used as a baseline salt in lithium ion batteries because of the unsatisfactory ionic conductivity resulting from the low dissociation degree arising from strong coulombic interactions between the anion and the lithium ion.<xref rid="cit6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref></p><fig position="float" id="sch1" fig-type="scheme"><label>Scheme 1</label><caption><title>Structures of LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiTFPFB.</title></caption><graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-s1" position="float"/></fig><p>The introduction of a bulky electron-withdrawing group into the anion has been considered as one of the most promising strategies for improving the ionic conductivity of the lithium salt due to its weak coulombic interactions.<xref rid="cit7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,<xref rid="cit8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref> For example, Ue and coworkers prepared lithium pentafluoroethyltrifluoroborate (LiFAB) by substituting one F<sup>&#x02013;</sup> in LiBF<sub>4</sub> by a bulky fluoric group.<xref rid="cit9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref> The ionic conductivity of 1.0 M LiFAB in EC/EMC (30&#x02009;:&#x02009;70 vol%) reaches 8.0 &#x000d7; 10<sup>&#x02013;4</sup> S cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> at room temperature, which is twofold higher than that of LiBF<sub>4</sub> (3.6 &#x000d7; 10<sup>&#x02013;4</sup> S cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>). However, LiFAB displays worse oxidation stability than LiBF<sub>4</sub> and deteriorated battery performance at elevated temperature (higher than 60 &#x000b0;C). Alternatively, Zhang synthesized lithium difluoro(oxalate)borate (LiDFOB) by using one oxalate anion to substitute two F<sup>&#x02013;</sup> in LiBF<sub>4</sub>.<xref rid="cit10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref> The ionic conductivity is enhanced and simultaneously a stable SEI is formed on the graphite anode. However, LiDFOB is less thermally stable than LiBF<sub>4</sub>.<xref rid="cit10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref></p><p>On the other hand, the fluoroalkoxyl functional group, usually existing in fluoric carbonate solvent, can decompose and <italic>in situ</italic> form an elastomeric polymeric matrix SEI on graphite,<xref rid="cit11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref> lithium silicon alloys,<xref rid="cit12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref> and Li metal surfaces.<xref rid="cit13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref> The as-formed SEI can effectively suppress Li dendrite growth and inhibit further decomposition of the electrolyte,<xref rid="cit11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref> making the fluoroalkoxyl functional group very attractive for next generation high energy lithium metal batteries. It is also noted that the introduction of the fluoroalkoxyl group into a lithium or/and magnesium salt anion can significantly improve the oxidation stability of the salt, as observed in Long's<xref rid="cit14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref> and our previous studies.<xref rid="cit15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref> However, to the best of our knowledge, there are relatively few studies devoted to the introduction of the electron-withdrawing fluoroalkoxyl group into the lithium salt anion to protect the lithium metal anode.</p><p>Herein, we for the first time intend to introduce a bulky fluoroalkoxyl functional group to substitute one F<sup>&#x02013;</sup> in LiBF<sub>4</sub> inspired by the aforementioned advantages of the fluoroalkoxyl group in ionic conductivity and oxidation stability improvement as well as its function in lithium metal protection. As a result, a novel lithium salt, namely the trifluoro(perfluoro-<italic>tert</italic>-butyloxyl)borate (LiTFPFB) salt (shown in <xref rid="sch1" ref-type="fig">Scheme 1</xref>), has been synthesized by a one-step reaction. The effective species of the salt have been analyzed by high resolution mass spectrometry (HR-MS), and <sup>7</sup>Li, <sup>11</sup>B and <sup>19</sup>F NMR. The stability of the LiTFPFB salt to the Al current collector as well as the ionic conductivities has been studied. Moreover, the elevated temperature (60 &#x000b0;C) battery performance of LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cells and high-voltage performance of LiCoO<sub>2</sub>/Li cells have also been studied to investigate the feasibility of the salt in high energy lithium metal batteries. Finally, the morphologies and compositions of the cycled Li metal were investigated by SEM imaging and XPS methods to elucidate the compatibility between the LiTFPFB based electrolyte and the lithium metal anode.</p></sec><sec><label>2.</label><title>Results and discussion</title><sec><label>2.1.</label><title>DFT computations</title><p>To screen a suitable lithium salt with both high oxidation stability and high dissociation degree, DFT calculation was conducted at the B3LYP/6-31G(p,d)* level with respect to different anion substituted lithium borates, <italic>i.e.</italic> LiDFOB, Li[R<sub>F</sub>OBF<sub>3</sub>] (R<sub>F</sub> = fluoroalkyl) and LiBF<sub>4</sub>. Two kinds of fluoroalkoxyl substituted lithium borates, Li[(CF<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub>CHOBF<sub>3</sub>] and Li[(CF<sub>3</sub>)<sub>3</sub>COBF<sub>3</sub>] (LiTFPFB), were designed, and the energy (in eV) of the highest occupied molecular orbital (HOMO) and the lowest unoccupied molecular orbital (LUMO) as well as dissociation energy were calculated compared to traditional LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiDFOB (shown in <xref rid="tab1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>). It is possible to estimate the oxidative stability of the molecule from the calculated HOMO energies, as the oxidation reaction involves an electron loss from its HOMO energy level.<xref rid="cit16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref> The values listed here were calculated for the structure optimized species. As predicted, the lower the HOMO energy level is, the greater is the expected stability against oxidation. Of the four anions, TFPFB<sup>&#x02013;</sup> exhibits the best oxidation stability with the lowest HOMO of &#x02013;4.64 eV, while BF<sub>4</sub><sup>&#x02013;</sup> shows the second best value of &#x02013;4.53 eV, making them much more stable than DFOB<sup>&#x02013;</sup> (&#x02013;3.60 eV). With respect to the dissociation energy, the LiTFPFB salt possesses the lowest value of 251.5 kJ mol<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, which is only one-half that of the other three, and thus is highly expected to have an improved ionic conductivity. Based on the calculation results, LiTFPFB with excellent oxidation stability and the lowest dissociation energy was picked out as the optimal lithium salt for further investigation.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="tab1"><label>Table 1</label><caption><title>Summary of the HOMO and LUMO energy levels and dissociation energies of four lithium salts</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><colgroup span="1"><col span="1"/><col span="1"/><col span="1"/><col span="1"/><col span="1"/></colgroup><tbody><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Lithium salts</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">LiBF<sub>4</sub></td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">LiDFOB</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">LiTFPFB</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Li[(CF<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub>CHOBF<sub>3</sub>]</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Anion structures</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<inline-graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-u1.jpg" id="ugr1"/>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<inline-graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-u2.jpg" id="ugr2"/>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<inline-graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-u3.jpg" id="ugr3"/>
</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">
<inline-graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-u4.jpg" id="ugr4"/>
</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">HOMO (eV)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x02013;4.53</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x02013;3.60</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x02013;4.64</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x02013;4.19</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">LUMO (eV)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.39</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.16</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.11</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.21</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">&#x00394;<italic>E</italic> (eV)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">8.92</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.76</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.75</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.40</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dissociation energy (kJ mol<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>)</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">595.8</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">493.5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">251.5</td><td rowspan="1" colspan="1">544.7</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap></sec><sec><label>2.2.</label><title>Synthesis and characterization of LiTFPFB</title><p>The LiTFPFB salt was obtained by a one-step reaction of lithium perfluoro-<italic>tert</italic>-butoxide (Li[(CF<sub>3</sub>)<sub>3</sub>CO]) with (C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>5</sub>)<sub>2</sub>O&#x000b7;BF<sub>3</sub> in THF (see Scheme S1 in the ESI<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>). The successful preparation of LiTFPFB is confirmed using <sup>7</sup>Li, <sup>11</sup>B, and <sup>19</sup>F NMR and HR-MS spectra (<xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Fig. 1</xref> and S1 and S2<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>). In the <sup>11</sup>B spectrum, the characteristic peaks at &#x02013;0.92 ppm are ascribed to the &#x02013;O&#x02013;BF<sub>3</sub> group. Remarkable differences between the <sup>19</sup>F NMR spectra of the reactant Li[(CF<sub>3</sub>)<sub>3</sub>CO] (one peak at &#x02013;75.13 ppm) and the product LiTFPFB (two peaks at &#x02013;71.92 and &#x02013;144.71 ppm) are also well observed. Besides, HR-MS presents further convincing data on the structure in the mass spectrum of LiTFPFB. The peaks at <italic>m</italic>/<italic>z</italic> 234.9810 and 302.9860 are assigned to [(CF<sub>3</sub>)<sub>3</sub>CO]<sup>&#x02013;</sup> and TFPFB<sup>&#x02013;</sup>, respectively, and the peak at <italic>m</italic>/<italic>z</italic> 234.9810 might have resulted from the fragment ions of TFPFB<sup>&#x02013;</sup> in the mass spectrometer. The disappearance of the Li[(CF<sub>3</sub>)<sub>3</sub>CO] species signal in the <sup>19</sup>F NMR spectra (<xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Fig. 1b</xref>) confirms the total conversion of reactants. Therefore, it is concluded that LiTFPFB is successfully synthesized in this study.</p><fig position="float" id="fig1" fig-type="figure"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><title>(a) <sup>11</sup>B NMR spectrum of LiTFPFB in deuterated dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO-d<sub>6</sub>). (b) <sup>19</sup>F NMR spectra of Li[(CF<sub>3</sub>)<sub>3</sub>CO] and LiTFPFB in DMSO-d<sub>6</sub>. (c) <sup>7</sup>Li NMR spectrum of LiTFPFB in DMSO-d<sub>6</sub>. (d) HR-MS spectrum of TFPFB<sup>&#x02013;</sup>.</title></caption><graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-f1" position="float"/></fig></sec><sec><label>2.3.</label><title>Ionic conductivity and electrochemical properties</title><p>
<xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Fig. 2</xref> compares the temperature dependent ionic conductivity of the LiTFPFB salt and LiBF<sub>4</sub> in PC solvent. Both the electrolytes show a typical Arrhenius-type correlation from 25 to 80 &#x000b0;C. The ionic conductivities of 1.0 M LiTFPFB/PC were 5.4 &#x000d7; 10<sup>&#x02013;4</sup> S cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> at 25 &#x000b0;C and 1.1 &#x000d7; 10<sup>&#x02013;3</sup> S cm<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> at 80 &#x000b0;C, respectively. The activation energy was calculated to be 11.17 kJ mol<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, which is lower than that of LiBF<sub>4</sub> (12.64 kJ mol<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>). In the whole temperature range, the ionic conductivity of the LiTFPFB based electrolyte is about three times higher than that of LiBF<sub>4</sub>. This result confirms that the bulky anion TFPFB<sup>&#x02013;</sup> is beneficial for the delocalization of the lithium salt, which can lower the dissociation energy and thus enhance the ionic conductivity.<xref rid="cit17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref> These findings are well in accordance with the DFT results (<xref rid="tab1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>). As a result of the low mobility of the larger anion size, the lithium-ion transference number can attain a value of 0.48 (shown in Fig. S3<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>), which is superior to that of the classical LiBF<sub>4</sub> salt (<italic>t</italic><sub>Li<sup>+</sup></sub> = 0.30).<xref rid="cit18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref></p><fig position="float" id="fig2" fig-type="figure"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><title>Arrhenius plots of the ionic conductivity of 1.0 M LiBF<sub>4</sub> and 1.0 M LiTFPFB in PC solvent.</title></caption><graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-f2" position="float"/></fig><p>The compatibility of LiTFPFB with the Al current collector was characterized by cyclic voltammetry compared with LiBF<sub>4</sub>. As a reference, the fluoroalkyl-containing salt lithium bis(trifluoromethane-sulphonyl)imide (LiTFSI) in PC solvent was also evaluated (<xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3a</xref>). For the LiTFSI based electrolyte, the current increases markedly when the applied potential exceeds 4.5 V <italic>vs.</italic> Li<sup>+</sup>/Li and persists during the negative sweep down to 3.7 V. Hysteresis in the cyclic voltammogram is an indicator of Al corrosion, which is consistent with the result obtained by Evans <italic>et al.</italic><xref rid="cit19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref> The low corrosion potential of Al at around 3.7 V may be due to the strong interaction between TFSI<sup>&#x02013;</sup> and the cation in the passivation film of Al, which may lead to higher solubility of the passivation species. In sharp contrast, the corresponding current responses of LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiTFPFB electrolytes are much smaller than that of LiTFSI. Furthermore, the cathodic current of the LiTFPFB based electrolyte is smaller than that of LiBF<sub>4</sub>, as shown in the inset of <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3a</xref>. These results indicate that LiTFPFB possesses the best compatibility with the Al current collector among the three measured salts. Moreover, chronoamperometry was further used to evaluate the compatibility of LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiTFPFB with Al (<xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3b</xref> and S4<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>).<xref rid="cit20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>,<xref rid="cit21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref> As depicted in <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3b</xref>, the initial rapid decrease of the anodic current on a fresh Al surface indicates instant formation of the passivation layer.<xref rid="cit22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref> The LiTFPFB based cell shows no sign of corrosion until the potential reaches <italic>ca.</italic> 4.5 V, which is consistent with the CV results described above, indicating enhanced Al current collector stability up to 4.5 V <italic>versus</italic> Li<sup>+</sup>/Li.<xref rid="cit21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref> In addition, the corrosion current collected at <italic>t</italic> = 10<sup>3</sup> s <italic>vs.</italic> the applied potential is plotted in the inset of <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3b</xref>. It is noted that the LiTFPFB based electrolyte shows lower current density than that of LiBF<sub>4</sub> even above 4.5 V. These results indicate that the LiTFPFB based electrolyte is more compatible with the Al current collector than that of LiBF<sub>4</sub>.</p><fig position="float" id="fig3" fig-type="figure"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><title>(a) Cyclic voltammogram curves of 1.0 M LiTFSI/PC, 1.0 M LiBF<sub>4</sub>/PC, and 1.0 M LiTFPFB/PC at a scan rate of 5 mV s<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> using Al as the working electrode and lithium foil as both the counter and reference electrodes. (b) Time-decaying current density of LiTFPFB based cells obtained on an Al electrode at varied potentials <italic>vs.</italic> Li<sup>+</sup>/Li (the inset shows the collected current value at 10<sup>3</sup> s <italic>vs.</italic> voltage). (c) Linear sweep voltammetry scans of 1.0 M LiBF<sub>4</sub>/PC and 1.0 M LiTFPFB/PC on a Pt working electrode at a scan rate of 5 mV s<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> using lithium foil as both the counter and reference electrodes.</title></caption><graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-f3" position="float"/></fig><p>The oxidation behaviors of both electrolytes were investigated by linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) using Pt as the working electrode. As shown in <xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3c</xref>, the anodic current of the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based electrolyte is very low below 4.5 V (<italic>vs.</italic> Li<sup>+</sup>/Li) and then increases distinctly when the voltage exceeds 4.6 V corresponding to the known electrolyte decomposition.<xref rid="cit23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref> For the LiTFPFB based electrolyte, the initial oxidation potential is observed at 4.5 V, followed by a slight increase. All these observations above verify that the oxidation decomposition of the electrolyte can be effectively suppressed and the Al current collector can be well passivated with LiTFPFB, which is well in agreement with the calculation result (<xref rid="tab1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>).</p></sec><sec><label>2.4.</label><title>Performance of lithium metal batteries (LMBs)</title><p>Polarization tests of the Li/Li symmetric cells with 1.0 M LiBF<sub>4</sub>/PC and 1.0 M LiTFPFB/PC based electrolytes were performed to investigate the interfacial stability of the Li/electrolyte interface. The Li/Li symmetric cells of both electrolytes were charged/discharged for 1 h during each process at a constant current density of 0.5 mA cm<sup>&#x02013;2</sup> (<xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4a</xref>). The cell with the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based electrolyte shows random voltage oscillations after 300 hours and a large and irreversible voltage drop at around 480 hours, which is attributed to cell failure by a dendrite-induced short circuit.<xref rid="cit24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,<xref rid="cit25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref> The short circuit could be verified by EIS measurements after the charge/discharge process, which show a small impedance of 3.0 &#x003a9; (Fig. S5<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>). In contrast, the plating/stripping of lithium occurred at a low overpotential below 0.1 V until 500 hours for the LiTFPFB based cells, indicating that LiTFPFB plays a positive role in stabilizing the Li/electrolyte interface and ensures a long cycle life because it can form a favorable protective film (further discussed in the next paragraph). In addition, the LiTFPFB based Li/Li symmetric cell also performs better than the LiPF<sub>6</sub> based one (see Fig. S6<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>). Furthermore, the compatibility between Li metal and the electrolyte can also be verified in Li/Li cells with an EIS spectrum. After 45 days, the interface resistance of the LiTFPFB based cell remains stable, while it still increases remarkably for the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based cell (Fig. S7<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>). It can be seen from Fig. S7a and c<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref> that the interface resistance of LiTFPFB electrolyte varies from 95 &#x003a9; to 113 &#x003a9;; however, the interface resistance of LiBF<sub>4</sub> (Fig. S7b and c<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>) is much larger than that of LiTFPFB (from 178 &#x003a9; to 377 &#x003a9;). The better interfacial stability of LiTFPFB mainly arises from the formation of a stable interface between the electrolyte and the Li anode, which prevents further corrosion of Li metal.</p><fig position="float" id="fig4" fig-type="figure"><label>Fig. 4</label><caption><title>(a) Lithium plating/stripping of LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiTFPFB based Li/Li symmetric cells at a current density of 0.5 mA cm<sup>&#x02013;2</sup>. (b) Cycling performance of LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiTFPFB based LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cells at a current rate of 1C (160 mA g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>) at room temperature. (c) Electrochemical impedance spectra of LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiTFPFB based LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cells after 1, 50, 100, and 200 cycles at 1C. (d) The fitted <italic>R</italic><sub>SEI</sub> results of the EIS spectra of LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiTFPFB based LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cells.</title></caption><graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-f4" position="float"/></fig><p>Moreover, coin-type Cu/Li cells were also used to investigate the cycling stability of Li plating/stripping. As shown in Fig. S8,<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref> the coulombic efficiency of the LiTFPFB based cell is 80.6% after 50 cycles, which is higher than that of the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based one (60.3%), indicating improved stability of the LiTFPFB based electrolyte.</p><p>To explore the feasibility of lithium metal batteries with the LiTFPFB based electrolyte, long-term cycling measurements of LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cells using both electrolytes were carried out at room temperature. As shown in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4b</xref>, the initial discharge capacities of the cells using LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiTFPFB at a current rate of 0.2C are 151.4 and 151.9 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>, respectively. The corresponding coulombic efficiencies of the two cells are 98.1 and 97.3%, respectively. These relatively low coulombic efficiencies are apparently due to the significant decomposition of the electrolyte and SEI formation.<xref rid="cit22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref> After the first three cycles for SEI formation, the cells were cycled at a high current rate of 1C (160 mA g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>). As shown in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4b</xref>, after 200 cycles, the LiTFPFB based cell retains nearly 99.3% of its fourth cycle discharge capacity with a smaller overpotential of 0.1 V (Fig. S9a<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>), while the capacity retention of the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based cell is 83.1% with a higher overpotential of 0.12 V (Fig. S9b<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>). Furthermore, an improved rate performance is also observed using 1.0 M LiTFPFB/PC electrolyte at room temperature (Fig. S10<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>). To better understand the excellent cell performance, the impedance spectra of the two cells were monitored during cycling and are shown in <xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4c and d</xref>. In general, the high-frequency intercept is attributed to the bulk resistance (<italic>R</italic><sub>b</sub>), and the two medium-frequency semicircles are associated with the interface resistance (<italic>R</italic><sub>SEI</sub>) and charge transfer resistance (<italic>R</italic><sub>ct</sub>), respectively. The equivalent circuit curve is shown in Fig. S11<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref> and the values of the fitted impedance parameters are listed in Table S1.<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref> Both the <italic>R</italic><sub>b</sub> values of the LiTFPFB and LiBF<sub>4</sub> based cells remain relatively stable after 1, 50, 100, and 200 cycles (<xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4c</xref>). The <italic>R</italic><sub>SEI</sub> of the LiTFPFB based cell is about 3.0 &#x003a9; after one cycle, and then increases to 3.4, 6.5, and 8.5 &#x003a9;, after 50, 100, and 200 cycles, respectively (<xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4d</xref>). As a comparison, the <italic>R</italic><sub>SEI</sub> of the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based cell is about 13.1 &#x003a9; after one cycle, and dramatically increases to 26.0, 31.8, and 41.8 &#x003a9; after 50, 100, and 200 cycles, respectively (<xref rid="fig4" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4d</xref>). The large initial and dramatic increase of <italic>R</italic><sub>SEI</sub> with cycling for the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based cell is because the lithium metal anode is continuously consumed by the electrolyte and a thick SEI layer is formed.<xref rid="cit27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref></p><p>The LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cells with LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiTFPFB were also cycled at elevated temperature (60 &#x000b0;C), respectively. After three SEI formation cycles at 1C, the cells were cycled at a high current rate of 5C. As depicted in <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5a</xref>, the LiTFPFB based battery delivers a superior cycling performance compared to that of the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based cell. After 150 cycles, the former retains 98.3% of the fourth cycle discharge capacity, while the capacity retention of the latter is only 62.5%. It is worth noting that the LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cell also operates well with the LiTFPFB based electrolyte compared with the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based one at &#x02013;5 &#x000b0;C (Fig. S12<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>). The rate performances of the LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiTFPFB based electrolytes were measured at different rates from 0.2C to 10C at 60 &#x000b0;C. As shown in <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5b</xref>, the LiTFPFB based cell shows better rate capability than that of LiBF<sub>4</sub> when the rate is varied from 0.2C to 10C. It is indicated that the former delivers a high reversible capacity of 145.8 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> at 10C, while the corresponding capacity of the latter is only 116.5 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>. Furthermore, the selected charge/discharge curves of a LiTFPFB based LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cell at 1C, 6C and 10C are plotted in the inset of <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5b</xref>, demonstrating clear potential plateaus with a small overpotential, which indicates a highly reversible cycling process. The outstanding cycle and rate performance of the LiTFPFB based cells are closely related to the high ionic conductivity and the as-formed protective film on the Li metal anode, which can suppress further decomposition of the electrolyte. To evaluate the morphologies of the Li anodes after long-term cycling, the LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li batteries after 150 cycles were disassembled inside a glovebox with an Ar atmosphere and the obtained electrodes were washed with anhydrous DMC, dried and further analyzed by field emission scanning electron microscopy (FE-SEM). As shown in <xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5c&#x02013;f</xref>, the Li surfaces of the LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiTFPFB based cells exhibit entirely different morphologies. It is noted that, for the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cell after 150 cycles at 60 &#x000b0;C, the cycled Li metal exhibits dendritic features with a pulverized and porous morphology (<xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5c and d</xref>). A large amount of bulk Li was consumed during cycling due to the repeated breakage/repair of the SEI.<xref rid="cit26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref> In addition, a pulverized layer is also observed on the newly formed Li dendrite (<xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5d</xref>). In contrast, the cycled Li metal in the LiTFPFB based cell shows smooth features and absence of Li dendrites (<xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5f</xref>), although the surface looks rimous (<xref rid="fig5" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5e</xref>). These results indicate that the protective film on the Li anode can effectively suppress the parasitic reactions on the surface of the Li anode, thus improving the battery performance.</p><fig position="float" id="fig5" fig-type="figure"><label>Fig. 5</label><caption><title>(a) Cycling performance of 1.0 M LiBF<sub>4</sub>/PC and 1.0 M LiTFPFB/PC based LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cells at a current rate of 5C at 60 &#x000b0;C. (b) Rate performance of LiBF<sub>4</sub> and LiTFPFB based LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cells at 60 &#x000b0;C; the inset shows the selected charge/discharge profiles using LiTFPFB. (c and d) FE-SEM images of the surface of the Li electrode cycled with LiBF<sub>4</sub>. (e and f) FE-SEM images of the surface of the Li electrode cycled with LiTFPFB.</title></caption><graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-f5" position="float"/></fig><p>In order to investigate the composition of the protective film, the surface chemistry of the cycled Li anodes was surveyed using X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Fig. 6</xref> shows the XPS spectra of B 1s, C 1s, O 1s, and F 1s for the cycled Li anodes with 1.0 M LiBF<sub>4</sub> and 1.0 M LiTFPFB in PC, respectively. As shown in <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Fig. 6a</xref>, the XPS spectrum of B 1s for the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based cell can be deconvoluted into two peaks at 192 and 194 eV, which can be assigned to B&#x02013;O (reaction product of LiBF<sub>4</sub> with ROCO<sub>2</sub>Li) and B&#x02013;F species.<xref rid="cit23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,<xref rid="cit27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref> In contrast, only B&#x02013;O species can be observed in the LiTFPFB based cell, indicating the decomposition of TFPFB<sup>&#x02013;</sup> on the Li anode. <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Fig. 6b</xref> displays the C 1s spectra, and the three peaks centered at 284.8, 286.2, and 287.9 eV correspond to C&#x02013;C, C&#x02013;O, and C<private-char name="DOUBLE BOND, LENGTH AS M-DASH" description="double bond, length as m-dash"><!-- PBM data was replaced with SVG by xgml2pxml:
<glyph-data id="z.dbdJbAgP" format="PBM" resolution="300" x-size="34" y-size="34" xml:space="preserve">
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 1111111111111111111111111111111111
 1111111111111111111111111111111111
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 1111111111111111111111111111111111
 1111111111111111111111111111111111
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
	</glyph-data>
-->
<glyph-data id="z.dbdJbAgP" format="SVG" resolution="300" x-size="34" y-size="34" xml:space="preserve">
<![CDATA[
<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.0" width="16.000000pt" height="16.000000pt" viewBox="0 0 16.000000 16.000000" preserveAspectRatio="xMidYMid meet"><metadata>
Created by potrace 1.16, written by Peter Selinger 2001-2019
</metadata><g transform="translate(1.000000,15.000000) scale(0.005147,-0.005147)" fill="currentColor" stroke="none"><path d="M0 1440 l0 -80 1360 0 1360 0 0 80 0 80 -1360 0 -1360 0 0 -80z M0 960 l0 -80 1360 0 1360 0 0 80 0 80 -1360 0 -1360 0 0 -80z"/></g></svg>
]]>
</glyph-data></private-char>O functional groups,<xref rid="cit27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref> respectively. The higher concentrations of C&#x02013;O and C<private-char name="DOUBLE BOND, LENGTH AS M-DASH" description="double bond, length as m-dash"><!-- PBM data was replaced with SVG by xgml2pxml:
<glyph-data id="z.dbd48GYf" format="PBM" resolution="300" x-size="34" y-size="34" xml:space="preserve">
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 1111111111111111111111111111111111
 1111111111111111111111111111111111
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 1111111111111111111111111111111111
 1111111111111111111111111111111111
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
	</glyph-data>
-->
<glyph-data id="z.dbd48GYf" format="SVG" resolution="300" x-size="34" y-size="34" xml:space="preserve">
<![CDATA[
<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.0" width="16.000000pt" height="16.000000pt" viewBox="0 0 16.000000 16.000000" preserveAspectRatio="xMidYMid meet"><metadata>
Created by potrace 1.16, written by Peter Selinger 2001-2019
</metadata><g transform="translate(1.000000,15.000000) scale(0.005147,-0.005147)" fill="currentColor" stroke="none"><path d="M0 1440 l0 -80 1360 0 1360 0 0 80 0 80 -1360 0 -1360 0 0 -80z M0 960 l0 -80 1360 0 1360 0 0 80 0 80 -1360 0 -1360 0 0 -80z"/></g></svg>
]]>
</glyph-data></private-char>O groups in the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based cell can be attributed to PC solvent decomposition, while the higher concentration of C&#x02013;C combined with lower C&#x02013;O and C<private-char name="DOUBLE BOND, LENGTH AS M-DASH" description="double bond, length as m-dash"><!-- PBM data was replaced with SVG by xgml2pxml:
<glyph-data id="z.dbd1vsYc" format="PBM" resolution="300" x-size="34" y-size="34" xml:space="preserve">
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 1111111111111111111111111111111111
 1111111111111111111111111111111111
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 1111111111111111111111111111111111
 1111111111111111111111111111111111
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
 0000000000000000000000000000000000
	</glyph-data>
-->
<glyph-data id="z.dbd1vsYc" format="SVG" resolution="300" x-size="34" y-size="34" xml:space="preserve">
<![CDATA[
<svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" version="1.0" width="16.000000pt" height="16.000000pt" viewBox="0 0 16.000000 16.000000" preserveAspectRatio="xMidYMid meet"><metadata>
Created by potrace 1.16, written by Peter Selinger 2001-2019
</metadata><g transform="translate(1.000000,15.000000) scale(0.005147,-0.005147)" fill="currentColor" stroke="none"><path d="M0 1440 l0 -80 1360 0 1360 0 0 80 0 80 -1360 0 -1360 0 0 -80z M0 960 l0 -80 1360 0 1360 0 0 80 0 80 -1360 0 -1360 0 0 -80z"/></g></svg>
]]>
</glyph-data></private-char>O concentrations in the LiTFPFB based cells might be related to TFPFB<sup>&#x02013;</sup> decomposition,<xref rid="cit28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref> consistent with the O 1s spectra in <xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Fig. 6c</xref>. These results indicate the decomposition of the TFPFB<sup>&#x02013;</sup> anion and the formation of a protective film on the Li anode, which can inhibit further decomposition of the electrolyte, coinciding with SEM imaging. Furthermore, as for the F 1s spectra (<xref rid="fig6" ref-type="fig">Fig. 6d</xref>), the three peaks located at 684.8, 685.6, and 686.8 eV for the LiTFPFB based cell can be assigned to LiF, C&#x02013;F, and B&#x02013;F compounds, respectively,<xref rid="cit23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref> which originate from the &#x02013;CF<sub>3</sub> (<xref rid="cit13" ref-type="bibr">ref. 13</xref>) and &#x02013;BF<sub>3</sub> groups in the TFPFB<sup>&#x02013;</sup> anion. Similarly, the LiF and B&#x02013;F species in the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based cell originate from the decomposition of LiBF<sub>4</sub>. In addition, comparing the Li anode after 1 and 100 cycles, the dramatic concentration increase of C species (from 8.9% to 45.0%) and sharp concentration decrease of F species (from 35.1% to 9.0%) may further verify the decomposition of the TFPFB<sup>&#x02013;</sup> anion (Fig. S13, Table S2<xref rid="fn1" ref-type="fn">&#x02020;</xref>), in agreement with the mechanism proposed by Abraham <italic>et al.</italic><xref rid="cit12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref> Based on the above results, it can be concluded that the decomposition of LiTFPFB can form a protective film containing a large number of C&#x02013;C groups on the Li anode, which can effectively prevent further corrosion of Li metal.</p><fig position="float" id="fig6" fig-type="figure"><label>Fig. 6</label><caption><title>B 1s (a), C 1s (b), O 1s (c), and F 1s (d) XPS patterns of the cycled Li anode.</title></caption><graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-f6" position="float"/></fig><p>For practical application in high energy lithium batteries, the LiTFPFB based electrolyte should also be compatible with the LiCoO<sub>2</sub> electrode, since it is most commonly used as the standard cathode in state-of-the-art Li ion batteries. To demonstrate the compatibility of LiTFPFB with the LiCoO<sub>2</sub> cathode, LiCoO<sub>2</sub>/Li cells were assembled and evaluated at a current rate of 1C between 2.75 and 4.35 V. <xref rid="fig7" ref-type="fig">Fig. 7</xref> shows the long-term cycling performance of the LiTFPFB and LiBF<sub>4</sub> based cells. The initial discharge capacities of the LiTFPFB and LiBF<sub>4</sub> based cells are 151.7 and 138 mA h g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup> at 0.2C, with the corresponding coulombic efficiencies of 99.6 and 99.2%, respectively. The former also exhibits a remarkably improved cycling performance compared to the latter at a current rate of 1C (140 mA g<sup>&#x02013;1</sup>). The LiTFPFB based cell retains 91.1% of the fourth cycle discharge capacity after 500 cycles with a coulombic efficiency of 99.5%, while the capacity retention of the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based cell is 89.2% with a coulombic efficiency of 99.3%. These results indicate that the LiTFPFB based electrolyte is more compatible with the LiCoO<sub>2</sub> based cathode than the LiBF<sub>4</sub> based one under a high voltage of 4.35 V, making LiTFPFB a promising candidate for practical application in high power and energy density rechargeable lithium batteries.</p><fig position="float" id="fig7" fig-type="figure"><label>Fig. 7</label><caption><title>Discharge capacities and coulombic efficiencies of the LiCoO<sub>2</sub>/Li cells using 1.0 M LiTFPFB/PC and 1.0 M LiBF<sub>4</sub>/PC at a current rate of 1C at room temperature.</title></caption><graphic xlink:href="c8sc00041g-f7" position="float"/></fig></sec></sec><sec><label>3.</label><title>Conclusions</title><p>In summary, a novel lithium salt, LiTFPFB, has been prepared by a one-step Lewis acid&#x02013;base reaction. The LiTFPFB salt with a bulky anion exhibits a <italic>t</italic><sub>Li<sup>+</sup></sub> value as high as 0.48, superior oxidation potential, and non-corrosivity to an Al current collector up to 4.5 V. The ionic conductivity of the LiTFPFB/PC electrolyte is three times higher than that of the LiBF<sub>4</sub>/PC electrolyte over the whole temperature range. Crucially, the fluoroalkoxyl group in LiTFPFB enables the formation of a favorable protective film on the lithium anode, which effectively prevents further corrosion of Li metal with the electrolyte. Together with high ionic conductivity and lithium anode protection properties, LiFePO<sub>4</sub>/Li cells using LiTFPFB/PC electrolyte show superior cycling stability and rate performance compared to those of LiBF<sub>4</sub>/PC electrolyte at room temperature and elevated temperature (60 &#x000b0;C). More importantly, LiTFPFB based LiCoO<sub>2</sub>/Li cells also show improved cycling performance. All of these results suggest that LiTFPFB would be a promising salt for next generation lithium-metal-based batteries with improved safety and electrochemical performance.</p></sec><sec><title>Conflicts of interest</title><p>There are no conflicts to declare.</p></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material id="S1" position="float" content-type="local-data"><alt-text>Supplementary information</alt-text><media xlink:href="SC-009-C8SC00041G-s001.pdf"><caption><p>Click here for additional data file.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material></sec></body><back><ack><p>This work was financially supported by the National Natural Science Foundation for Distinguished Young Scholars of China (51625204), the National Natural Science Foundation of China (51502319), the Shandong Provincial Natural Science Foundation (ZR2016BQ18), and the Youth Innovation Promotion Association of CAS (2016193).</p></ack><ref-list><ref id="cit1"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Goodenough</surname><given-names>J. B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>K.-S.</given-names></name></person-group><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2013</year><volume>135</volume><fpage>1167</fpage><lpage>1176</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23294028</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit2"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Tarascon</surname><given-names>J. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Armand</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Nature</source><year>2001</year><volume>414</volume><fpage>359</fpage><lpage>367</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11713543</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit3"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Petibon</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Madec</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Abarbanel</surname><given-names>D. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dahn</surname><given-names>J. R.</given-names></name></person-group><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2015</year><volume>300</volume><fpage>419</fpage><lpage>429</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit4"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>S. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jow</surname><given-names>T. R.</given-names></name></person-group><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2003</year><volume>115</volume><fpage>137</fpage><lpage>140</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit5"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Chem. Sci.</source><year>2015</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>7274</fpage><lpage>7283</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29861962</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit6"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Tsunekawa</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Narumi</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sano</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hiwara</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fujita</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yokoyama</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group><source>J. Phys. Chem. B</source><year>2003</year><volume>107</volume><fpage>10962</fpage><lpage>10966</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit7"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Meziane</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bonnet</surname><given-names>J.-P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Courty</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Djellab</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Armand</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Electrochim. Acta</source><year>2011</year><volume>57</volume><fpage>14</fpage><lpage>19</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit8"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nie</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Feng</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Armand</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Angew. Chem., Int. Ed.</source><year>2016</year><volume>55</volume><fpage>2521</fpage><lpage>2525</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit9"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Ue</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fujii</surname><given-names>T.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>Z. B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Takeda</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kinoshita</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Solid State Ionics</source><year>2006</year><volume>177</volume><fpage>323</fpage><lpage>331</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit10"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>S. S.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Electrochem. Commun.</source><year>2006</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>1423</fpage><lpage>1428</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit11"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Su</surname><given-names>C.-C.</given-names></name><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Redfern</surname><given-names>P. C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Curtiss</surname><given-names>L. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Shkrob</surname><given-names>I. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source><year>2017</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>900</fpage><lpage>904</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit12"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Shkrob</surname><given-names>I. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wishart</surname><given-names>J. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Abraham</surname><given-names>D. P.</given-names></name></person-group><source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source><year>2015</year><volume>119</volume><fpage>14954</fpage><lpage>14964</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit13"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Qu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cheng</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zuo</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Electrochim. Acta</source><year>2016</year><volume>191</volume><fpage>8</fpage><lpage>15</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit14"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Van Humbeck</surname><given-names>J. F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Aubrey</surname><given-names>M. L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Alsbaiee</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Ameloot</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Coates</surname><given-names>G. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dichtel</surname><given-names>W. R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Long</surname><given-names>J. R.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Chem. Sci.</source><year>2015</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>5499</fpage><lpage>5505</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28757947</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit15"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Qiao</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Guan</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Du</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Adv. Energy Mater.</source><year>2017</year><fpage>1602055</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit16"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Ue</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Murakami</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2002</year><volume>149</volume><fpage>A1572</fpage><lpage>A1577</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit17"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Cai</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source><year>2012</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>5690</fpage><lpage>5693</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit18"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Chem. Rev.</source><year>2014</year><volume>114</volume><fpage>11503</fpage><lpage>11618</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25351820</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit19"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kwon</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Devine</surname><given-names>T. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Evans</surname><given-names>J. W.</given-names></name></person-group><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2000</year><volume>147</volume><fpage>4399</fpage><lpage>4407</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit20"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>K.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>S. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jow</surname><given-names>T. R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Angell</surname><given-names>C. A.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Electrochem. Solid-State Lett.</source><year>2002</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>A26</fpage><lpage>A29</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit21"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kong</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Electrochim. Acta</source><year>2013</year><volume>92</volume><fpage>132</fpage><lpage>138</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit22"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>X.-G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Wan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Guang</surname><given-names>H. Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Reeves</surname><given-names>K. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chi</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name></person-group><source>J. Mater. Chem. A</source><year>2017</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>1233</fpage><lpage>1241</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit23"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>K. S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Baggetto</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hillesheim</surname><given-names>D. A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Custelcean</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>E.-S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bi</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>D.-e.</given-names></name><name><surname>Veith</surname><given-names>G. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Hagaman</surname><given-names>E. W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Brown</surname><given-names>G. M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Bridges</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Paranthaman</surname><given-names>M. P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Manthiram</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dai</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>X.-G.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Adv. Energy Mater.</source><year>2014</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>1301368</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit24"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>He</surname><given-names>Y.-B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kaneti</surname><given-names>Y. V.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yao</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Kang</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>Q.-H.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2017</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>1604460</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit25"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Hu</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name><name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Chem. Mater.</source><year>2017</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>4682</fpage><lpage>4689</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit26"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>N.-W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>Y.-X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>C.-P.</given-names></name><name><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>Y.-G.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2016</year><volume>28</volume><fpage>1853</fpage><lpage>1858</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26698171</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit27"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Dong</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><name><surname>Demeaux</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name><name><surname>MacIntosh</surname><given-names>A. D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Garsuch</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><name><surname>Lucht</surname><given-names>B. L.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source><year>2016</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>1308</fpage><lpage>1319</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="cit28"><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Q.-C.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J.-J.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yuan</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Chang</surname><given-names>Z.-W.</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>Y.-B.</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names>H.-X.</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>Y.-S.</given-names></name><name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>J.-M.</given-names></name><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X.-B.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2015</year><volume>27</volume><fpage>6089</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26487018</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>