<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.3 20210610//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-3-mathml3.dtd"> 
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.3"><?properties open_access?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierValue -//Springer-Verlag//DTD A++ V2.4//EN?><?DTDIdentifier.IdentifierType public?><?SourceDTD.DTDName A++V2.4.dtd?><?SourceDTD.Version 2.4?><?ConverterInfo.XSLTName springer2nlmx2.xsl?><?ConverterInfo.Version 1?><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Nat Commun</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Nat Commun</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Nature Communications</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2041-1723</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Nature Publishing Group UK</publisher-name><publisher-loc>London</publisher-loc></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">8917126</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">28959</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-28959-5</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>A dual-function liquid electrolyte additive for high-energy non-aqueous lithium metal batteries</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Yuji</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>Yuan</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Huiyi</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>Jinghao</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">http://orcid.org/0000-0003-4100-9610</contrib-id><name><surname>Lei</surname><given-names>Danni</given-names></name><address><email>leidanni@mail.sysu.edu.cn</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-8355-6431</contrib-id><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Chengxin</given-names></name><address><email>wchengx@mail.sysu.edu.cn</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.12981.33</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0001 2360 039X</institution-id><institution>State Key Laboratory of Optoelectronic Materials and Technologies, School of Materials Science and Engineering, </institution><institution>Sun Yat-sen (Zhongshan) University, </institution></institution-wrap>Guangzhou, 510275 China </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>11</day><month>3</month><year>2022</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="pmc-release"><day>11</day><month>3</month><year>2022</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2022</year></pub-date><volume>13</volume><elocation-id>1297</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>30</day><month>5</month><year>2021</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>16</day><month>2</month><year>2022</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2022</copyright-statement><license><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons license, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article&#x02019;s Creative Commons license and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this license, visit <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><abstract id="Abs1"><p id="Par1">Engineering the formulation of non-aqueous liquid electrolytes is a viable strategy to produce high-energy lithium metal batteries. However, when the lithium metal anode is combined with a Ni-rich layered cathode, the (electro)chemical stability of both electrodes could be compromised. To circumvent this issue, we report a combination of aluminum ethoxide (0.4 wt.%) and fluoroethylene carbonate (5 vol.%) as additives in a conventional LiPF<sub>6</sub>-containing carbonate-based electrolyte solution. This electrolyte formulation enables the formation of mechanically robust and ionically conductive interphases on both electrodes&#x02019; surfaces. In particular, the alumina formed at the interphases prevents the formation of dendritic structures on the lithium metal anode and mitigate the stress-induced cracking and phase transformation in the Ni-rich layered cathode. By coupling a thin (i.e., about 40 &#x003bc;m) lithium metal anode with a high-loading (i.e., 21.5&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>) LiNi<sub>0.8</sub>Co<sub>0.1</sub>Mn<sub>0.1</sub>O<sub>2</sub>-based cathode in coin cell configuration and lean electrolyte conditions, the engineered electrolyte allows a specific discharge capacity retention of 80.3% after 130 cycles at 60&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> and 30&#x02009;&#x000b0;C which results in calculated specific cell energy of about 350&#x02009;Wh&#x02009;kg<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>.</p></abstract><abstract id="Abs2" abstract-type="web-summary"><p id="Par2">Lithium metal batteries suffer from poor (electro)chemical stability of the electrodes during prolonged cycling. Here, the authors report a dual function liquid electrolyte additive to form protective interphases on both electrodes to produce lab-scale high energy lithium metal batteries.</p></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="npg-subject"><title>Subject terms</title><kwd>Batteries</kwd><kwd>Batteries</kwd><kwd>Characterization and analytical techniques</kwd><kwd>Energy</kwd><kwd>Electrochemistry</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>&#x000a9; The Author(s) 2022</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1" sec-type="introduction"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par3">Lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) with lithium-intercalated graphite anodes have been widely used since their commercialization in the 1990s<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref></sup>. However, with their lower specific capacity (372&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>), graphite anodes can hardly meet the practical needs of highly demanding modern devices such as electric vehicles<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref></sup>. The lithium metal anode (LMA) is considered the most promising since it has a theoretical specific capacity of 3862&#x02009;mAh g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> and the lowest reduction potential (&#x02212;3.040&#x02009;V versus the standard hydrogen electrode (SHE))<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref></sup>. Replacing graphite anodes in LIBs with LMA and combining them with high-capacity cathodes, such as Ni-rich layered cathode would significantly boost their energy density. High specific content lithium metal batteries (LMBs) of over 300&#x02009;Wh&#x02009;kg<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> require an integrated Li anode with a thickness of less than 50 &#x003bc;m, a limited amount of electrolyte (electrolyte weight to cathode capacity ratio (E/C)&#x02009;&#x0003c;&#x02009;4) and a high areal-capacity cathode (&#x0003e;&#x000a0;4&#x02009;mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>2</sup>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref></sup>. However, in practise, the performance of LMBs is often unsatisfactory due to the high reactivity of conventional carbonate-based electrolytes with both Ni-rich cathodes LiNi<sub>0.8</sub>Co<sub>0.1</sub>Mn<sub>0.1</sub>O<sub>2</sub> (NCM) and LMA<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref></sup>. Side reactions between LMA and carbonate-based electrolytes result in an unsatisfactory Coulombic efficiency (CE) and the growth of unfavourable Li deposition morphologies (e.g., dendrites), which significantly decrease battery performance and cause potential safety issues<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref></sup>. In addition, Ni-rich NCM cathodes are impacted by phase transformation, stress-corrosion cracking and transition metal dissolution during long cycling<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref></sup>. Therefore, the design of improved nonaqueous liquid electrolyte solutions to construct a consistent and robust solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) at the anode and a cathode-electrolyte interphase (CEI) at the cathode is critical to the practical utilization of high specific energy LMBs<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref></sup>.</p><p id="Par4">Recently, significant efforts have been made to optimize electrolytes for better compatibility with both Ni-rich NCM cathodes and LMAs<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref></sup>. Highly or locally concentrated electrolytes facilitate the formation of a salt-derived SEI or CEI, potentially improving the cycling stability of Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM batteries<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>&#x02013;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref></sup>. However, certain electrolyte challenges remain to be addressed before commercialization, such as their high viscosity, insufficient separator wettability, low ionic conductivity and high cost. All-fluorinated electrolytes<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref></sup> and fluorinated ether-based electrolytes<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref></sup>, such as those containing LiF, have been demonstrated to form compounds with a preferable SEI or CEI, but evaluation under practical conditions (specific energy &#x0003e;&#x000a0;300&#x02009;Wh&#x02009;kg<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) is warranted. Sulfonamide-based electrolytes<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref></sup> and phosphate-based electrolytes<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref></sup> can stabilize the cycling of high-voltage LMBs, but the use of high-cost lithium bis(fluorosulfonyl)imide (LiFSI) to lower the reactivity of electrolytes with LMAs cannot be avoided<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref></sup>. The dual-additive strategy (utilizes the synergistic effect of two different additives) has been proven to improve the performance of Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM cells by regulating the CEI and SEI structures<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref></sup>, but Li-containing additives are also expensive<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref></sup>. Outside of electrolyte engineering, the application of an Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> surface coating on a high-voltage cathode and Li metal anode is a common approach to improve the stability between active materials and electrolytes. On the cathode, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> coatings can typically scavenge HF, limit transition metal dissolution and regulate the composition of the CEI<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref></sup>. On the anode, Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> thin films prevent side reactions with electrolytes and induce homogeneous Li nucleation<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref></sup>. Commonly, atomic layer deposition<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref></sup>, radiofrequency magnetron sputtering<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref></sup> and wet chemistry<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR34">34</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR35">35</xref></sup> are used to coat an Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> protective film on electrodes. However, these methods require a high temperature; additionally, the process may be rather complex and expensive. Moreover, some of these methods cannot guarantee the uniformity of the coating<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR36">36</xref></sup>. Therefore, a low cost and effective method is needed to realize practical LMBs with a high specific energy.</p><p id="Par5">Herein, we design a nonaqueous electrolyte solution by adding 0.4 wt.% aluminum ethoxide (Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>) nanowires into a conventional LiPF<sub>6</sub>-containing carbonate-based electrolyte solution. Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> is prepared by a selective dealloying method<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref></sup>. With the synergistic effect of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and fluoroethylene carbonate (FEC), Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>-containing interphases that provide robust and high ionic conductivity protection are formed, which is beneficial to both Li metal anodes and Ni-rich NCM cathodes. Indeed, when the Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>-containing electrolyte solution is tested in Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|LiNi<sub>0.6</sub>Co<sub>0.2</sub>Mn<sub>0.2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> (NCM622) coin cell configuration, improved cycling stability and rate performance can be noticed. Also, by pairing the thin Li anode (~40 &#x003bc;m) with the commercial cathode LiNi<sub>0.8</sub>Co<sub>0.1</sub>Mn<sub>0.1</sub>O<sub>2</sub> (NCM811) (21.5&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>), we demonstrate a specific energy of approximately 350&#x02009;Wh&#x02009;kg<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> at the full cell level.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2" sec-type="results"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Physicochemical characterization of the electrolyte solutions</title><p id="Par6">The color of the Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>-containing electrolyte (AFE, 0.4 wt.% Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and 5 vol.% FEC in 1&#x02009;M LiPF<sub>6</sub>/ethylene carbonate (EC) and diethyl carbonate (DEC) (1:1 by volume)) in a polyolefin bottle that was placed in an Ar-filled glove box for five days at 30&#x02009;&#x000b0;C and 60&#x02009;&#x000b0;C turns from transparent to brown and produces an acidic gas (Supplementary Figs.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref> and <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref>), suggesting that side reactions were occurring. All the cells were tested with freshly prepared electrolyte. To explore the reaction mechanism of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and FEC, we prepared Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/LiPF<sub>6</sub>/FEC (3.2 wt.% Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>&#x02009;+&#x02009;1.0&#x02009;M LiPF<sub>6</sub> in FEC) and Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/FEC (3.2 wt.% Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> in FEC) solutions in a polyolefin bottle and placed them in an Ar-filled glove box for five days at 60&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. Then, we took the precipitate and supernatant for further characterization. The <sup>27</sup>Al magic angle spinning solid-state nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectra of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> show several resonance peaks centered at approximately 75, 33, 4 and &#x02212;36 ppm. Among them, the peaks at 75 and 33 ppm correspond to 4- (Al<sup>IV</sup>) and 5-coordinated aluminum (Al<sup>V</sup>), respectively, while the peaks at 4 and -36 ppm correspond to 6-coordinated aluminum (Al<sup>VI</sup>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR38">38</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR39">39</xref></sup>. These results indicate the formation of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> polymer networks. The <sup>27</sup>Al MAS solid-state NMR spectra of the Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/LiPF<sub>6</sub>/FEC and Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/FEC precipitates show a resonance peak centered at &#x02013;12 ppm, which may correspond to 6-coordinated aluminum (Al<sup>VI</sup>) (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1a</xref>). Compared with the Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/FEC precipitate, the Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/LiPF<sub>6</sub>/FEC precipitate shows weaker peaks for C&#x02013;F bonds (100 ppm) and C=O (159 ppm)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR40">40</xref></sup> in the <sup>13</sup>C spectrum, indicating that the LiPF<sub>6</sub> may catalyse the reaction of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and FEC (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1b</xref>). As shown in the solid Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectra, the C=O peaks (1751 cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> and 1825 cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>) of the precipitate of the Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/LiPF<sub>6</sub>/FEC solution are weaker than those of the Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/FEC solution (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1c</xref>). This further confirms the catalytic properties of LiPF<sub>6</sub>. Although the color of the Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/LiPF<sub>6</sub>/FEC solution changes significantly in the supernatant after five days of storage, the C&#x02212;F and C=O signals show no marked changes in the NMR and FTIR spectra (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref>). This may be because most of the reaction products settle at the bottom and their concentrations are low in the supernatant. The possible reaction mechanism of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and FEC is proposed in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1d</xref>. The C=O bond of FEC is broken, and oxygen atoms are directly connected to the Al atom of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>, followed by polymerization of FEC and the loss of HF. With the lowest heat absorption and the highest decomposition temperature, the reaction products of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and FEC catalyzed by LiPF<sub>6</sub> have good thermal stability (Supplementary Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4</xref>). We speculate that the reaction products with a three-dimensional structure and high thermal stability would contribute to the formation of uniform and robust solid-electrolyte interphases at the anode and cathode. Based on the findings discussed above, we schematically illustrate in Figs.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>e, <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1f</xref> the possible SEI and CEI morphologies obtained employing the conventional electrolyte and Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>-containing functional electrolyte (AFE) in Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM cells.<fig id="Fig1"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><title>Physicochemical characterizations of the electrolyte solutions and additives.</title><p><sup>27</sup>Al (<bold>a</bold>) and <sup>13</sup>C (<bold>b</bold>) Solid-state NMR and <bold>c</bold> Solid FTIR spectra of pure Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and the precipitates obtained from two different solutions. <bold>d</bold> Proposed Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/FEC reaction mechanism. Schematic illustration of the protection mechanism of the SEI and CEI formed in BE (<bold>e</bold>) and AFE (<bold>f</bold>).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2022_28959_Fig1_HTML" id="d32e766"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Morphological and mechanical characterizations of lithium depositions on Cu substrates</title><p id="Par7">To better understand the Li deposition behavior in different electrolytes, we assembled Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Cu coin cells and used scanning electron microscopy (SEM) for observation. All Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Cu coin cells were operated at a fixed current density of 0.5&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> with a specific areal capacity limitation of 3 mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> before cell disassembly and postmortem SEM electrode measurements. For the cells with a basic electrolyte (BE, 1&#x02009;M LiPF<sub>6</sub> in EC/DEC (1:1 by volume)), the top views of the electroplated Li metal on the surface of the Cu electrode exhibit a typical dendritic morphology (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2a</xref> and b). The dendritic Li metal increases the reaction area with the electrolyte; thus, the electrolyte is quickly consumed, &#x0201c;dead Li&#x0201d; (i.e., lithium particles that are electronically disconnected from the current collector) is formed, and the cell exhibits a short cycle life. Uneven and loose Li dendrites are observed even when 5% FEC is added to the BE (FEC-containing electrolyte (FE)) (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2c</xref> and d). In sharp contrast, uniform and dense Li deposits without dendrite are obtained with the use of AFE (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2e</xref> and f).<fig id="Fig2"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><title>Micromorphology and SEI properties of Li metal deposited onto a Cu substrate.</title><p>SEM images (<bold>a</bold>&#x02013;<bold>f</bold>), Young&#x02019;s modulus maps (<bold>g</bold>&#x02013;<bold>i</bold>) and force-displacement curves (<bold>j</bold>-<bold>l</bold>) of the deposited lithium metal using the BE (<bold>a</bold>, <bold>b</bold>, <bold>g</bold> and <bold>j</bold>), FE (<bold>c</bold>, <bold>d</bold>, <bold>h</bold> and <bold>k</bold>) and AFE (<bold>e</bold>, <bold>f</bold>, <bold>i</bold> and <bold>l</bold>) at current densities of 0.5&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>2</sup> and 3 mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>2</sup>. &#x0201c;Extend&#x0201d; and &#x0201c;retract&#x0201d; means the direction of motion of the cantilever with respect to the sample.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2022_28959_Fig2_HTML" id="d32e868"/></fig></p><p id="Par8">During lithiation/delithiation, SEI deformation is inevitable. Therefore, toughness and adhesion are essential to ensure the integrity of the SEI film and inhibit Li dendrite formation<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR41">41</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR42">42</xref></sup>. Through atomic force microscopy (AFM) evaluation, the Young&#x02019;s modulus of the SEI formed in the AFE is 767&#x02009;MPa, which is higher than that in the BE (676&#x02009;MPa) and FE (658&#x02009;MPa) (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2g-i</xref>), indicating a tougher SEI film that effectively inhibits the formation of Li dendrites. In the force-displacement curves, the SEI interphase formed in the AFE has the highest adhesion force among the three groups, which effectively enhances the interfacial stability and promotes the rapid transport and uniform deposition of Li<sup>+</sup> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2j-l</xref>).</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Physicochemical characterization of the lithium metal anode</title><p id="Par9">The synergistic effect of dual additives (Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/FEC) on the chemical composition of the SEI film on a cycled Li anode (at a current density of 1&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and an areal capacity of 1&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> for 10 cycles; the voltage of the cell was 0&#x02009;V before disassembly) was studied by using in-depth X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3a-f</xref>). The high-resolution F 1&#x02009;<italic>s</italic> XPS spectra of the SEI film using FE and AFE had peaks at 684.9&#x02009;eV and 687.0 eV<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR43">43</xref></sup>, respectively, and these peaks are assigned to LiF and C&#x02212;F species as the main reduction products of FEC (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3a</xref> and b). With increasing Ar<sup>+</sup> etching time, the content of LiF drops in the AFE, whereas it remains unchanged in the FE. The proportion of F in the AFE is lower than that in the FE. This confirms that the reaction of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and FEC releases HF. The high-resolution Al 2&#x000a0;<italic>p</italic> XPS spectra of the SEI in the AFE show the presence of Al (72.9&#x02009;eV)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR44">44</xref></sup>, which confirms that the reaction product of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and FEC can be reduced to Al metal. In addition, Al-O species are detected based on the peak at 74.9&#x02009;eV (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3c</xref>, Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">5</xref>). To verify the presence of Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> and exclude the influence of Ar<sup>+</sup> on Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>, we conducted in-depth XPS on pure Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> powder under the same conditions. With increasing Ar<sup>+</sup> etching time, the peak at 74.9&#x02009;eV corresponding to Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub><sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR45">45</xref></sup> slightly shifts to a higher binding energy, which confirms that Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> is not be reduced to Al metal by Ar<sup>+</sup> (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">6</xref>). With increasing Ar<sup>+</sup> etching time, the amount of Al-O species decreases while that of Al metal increases, which means that the inner SEI layer contains more Al metal (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3d</xref>). The Al/Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> composite structure can effectively reduce the consumption of Li<sup>+</sup> during SEI film formation<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR46">46</xref></sup>. The total atomic content of Al remains at 1.5% of all elements and does not change with the etching depth as shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3e, f</xref>; this result indicates the uniform distribution of aluminum in the SEI film. A Li metal signal (52.4&#x02009;eV)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR47">47</xref></sup> is detected in the AFE, as shown in the Li 1&#x02009;<italic>s</italic> spectra (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">7a and b</xref>), indicating the high density of the SEI and the intimate contact between the SEI and Li metal anode. The C 1&#x02009;<italic>s</italic> spectra in the two electrolytes are basically the same (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">7c and d</xref>). Time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS) measurements were performed to provide more information about the composition of the SEI (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3g</xref> and h, Supplementary Figs.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">8</xref> and <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">9</xref>). The interphase products, including the aluminum-containing species (represented by Al<sup>+</sup>, AlO<sub>2</sub>C<sub>2</sub>HF<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, AlO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> and AlO<sub>2</sub>C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>), inorganic species (represented by LiF<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> and CO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>) and organic species (represented by C<sub>2</sub>HO<sup>&#x02212;</sup> and CHO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>), appear at the SEI on the Li surface. AlO<sub>2</sub>C<sub>2</sub>HF<sup>&#x02212;</sup> and AlO<sub>2</sub>C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> are representative of the fragments of the reaction products shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1d</xref>, which further indicates that the speculated reaction mechanism of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and FEC (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1d</xref>) is reasonable. Compared to conventional SEI components (such as Li<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>, Li<sub>2</sub>O and LiOH)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR48">48</xref></sup>, the spatial distribution of aluminum-containing species is deeper, indicating that aluminum-containing species are closer to the LMA, which is consistent with the XPS results. Contact with the LMA is conducive to the protective effect of the aluminum-based solid electrolyte interphase on the electrode. In other words, the synergistic effect of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and the FEC provides a robust SEI containing Al metal and Al&#x02212;O species that contributes to the high stability of the LMA during long-term cycling.<fig id="Fig3"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><title>Ex situ postmortem physicochemical characterizations of lithium metal electrodes cycled in symmetrical Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Li cells.</title><p>XPS F 1&#x02009;<italic>s</italic> spectra (<bold>a</bold> and <bold>b</bold>), XPS Al 2&#x000a0;<italic>p</italic> spectra (<bold>c</bold>), Al-O/Al ratio as the XPS sputtering time is increased in the AFE (<bold>d</bold>), atomic ratio of elements in the SEI at different XPS sputtering times (<bold>e</bold> and <bold>f</bold>). TOF-SIMS 3D reconstruction of the sputtered volume (<bold>g</bold>) and the depth profiling of several secondary ion fragments (<bold>h</bold>) of Al<sup>+</sup>, AlO<sub>2</sub>C<sub>2</sub>HF<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, LiF<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>, AlO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>, AlO<sub>2</sub>C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> and C<sub>2</sub>HO<sup>&#x02212;</sup> on the Li surface. Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Li cycling was obtained at a current density of 1&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>2</sup> and an areal capacity of 1&#x02009;mAh&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>2</sup> for each plating or stripping step.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2022_28959_Fig3_HTML" id="d32e1227"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Electrochemical measurements and analyses of Li||Cu and Li||Li coin cells</title><p id="Par10">To further verify that the SEI can improve the reversibility of Li deposition, we assembled Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Cu cells with the BE, FE and AFE. All cells were discharged into a fixed capacity of 1 mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and then charged to 1&#x02009;V to strip the Li off at a current density of 0.5&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>. As shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4a</xref>, the cell with the AFE has the lowest Li deposition potential due to the lithiophilic property of the Al metal in the SEI. Although metallic Li should easily react with elemental Al to form Li-Al alloys, no plateaus of Li-Al alloying/dealloying are observed in the stripping-plating voltage profiles of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Cu cells with the AFE<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR49">49</xref></sup>, which is similar to that with the BE (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">10</xref>). Thus, we speculate that the amount of metallic Al contained in the SEI is insufficient to trigger an alloy reaction with the lithium ions coming from the electrolyte. The initial CE of the cell with the BE is 78.3% and quickly drops to less than 50.0% after 70 cycles (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4b</xref>). In the FE, the CE improves during the initial 40 cycles and then widely fluctuates. In contrast, the CE of the cell with the AFE remains stable for over 100 cycles with an average of 94.0%. The corresponding voltage profiles shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4c-e</xref> indicate that the cell with the AFE has stable polarization without a sharp increase during the Li plating/stripping process, which is improved if compared with the cells assembled using the BE and FE.<fig id="Fig4"><label>Fig. 4</label><caption><title>Electrochemical characterizations of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Cu&#x02009;and Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Li cells with different electrolytes.</title><p>Initial charge&#x02013;discharge curves (<bold>a</bold>), Coulombic efficiency (<bold>b</bold>) and voltage profiles (<bold>c</bold>, <bold>d</bold>, and <bold>e</bold>) of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Cu&#x02009;cells. <bold>f</bold> R<sub>SEI</sub> of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Li cells with an increasing cycle number. <bold>g</bold> Rate capability of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Li cells with different electrolytes. Inset is the enlarged figure of the curves.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2022_28959_Fig4_HTML" id="d32e1291"/></fig></p><p id="Par11">To better understand the stability of the SEI, we measured and simulated the electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) results of Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Li symmetrical cells after different cycle numbers at the current density of 1.0&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup> and capacity of 1 mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>. The semicircle of the Nyquist plots in the high-frequency region represents Li<sup>+</sup> migration through the SEI<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR50">50</xref></sup>. As reported in the literature, Li metal is highly reactive, both chemically and electrochemically, with organic-based liquid electrolytes<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR51">51</xref></sup>. The R<sub>SEI</sub> of the uncycled cell in the BE is as high as 323.4 Ohms, which suggests that the initial SEI is uneven. The R<sub>SEI</sub> is slightly lower in the FE (274.2 Ohms), and markedly lower in the AFE (154.0 Ohms) owing to the reaction between Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and FEC in the absence of an electric field (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4f</xref>). After two cycles, the R<sub>SEI</sub> in the AFE drops to one-third of its original value (49.0 Ohms) and remains stable during subsequent cycles. In contrast, the R<sub>SEI</sub> values in both the BE and FE heavily fluctuate, and the average values are twice that of the AFE (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">11</xref>). This reinforces our conclusion that the product of the FEC/Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> reaction contributes to uniform and robust SEI formation and thus more efficient and uniform Li-ion transport.</p><p id="Par12">We analyzed and compared the cycling stability and high-rate capability of Li&#x000a0;| |Li symmetrical cells in three electrolytes (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4g</xref>). The Li&#x000a0;| |Li cells cycled in the BE and FE quickly fail when the current density is increased from 1 to 3 and 4&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>, respectively. In contrast, the Li&#x000a0;|&#x000a0;|Li cell with the AFE cycles steadily for 550&#x02009;h and exhibits a stable voltage profiles with low electrode polarization even when the current density is increased to 4.0&#x02009;mA&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>2</sup>. This further endorses the fact that the robust SEI that forms in the AFE improves the interfacial compatibility, thus enabling highly reversible Li deposition/dissolution.</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Electrochemical characterization of the Li||NCM coin cells</title><p id="Par13">To evaluate the high-voltage cycling performance of AFE, we assembled Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM622 and Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM811 full cells. Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM622 coin cell with a cathode mass loading of 2.4&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>2</sup> was cycled at 19&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>, 38&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>, 95&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>, 190&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>, 380&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> and 950&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> for 5 cycles and finally stabilized at 190&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>. The cells with the AFE could be cycled up to 1000 cycles delivering a specific discharge capacity of 98.2 mAh g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> while the cell with the BE could be cycled only for more than 400 cycles before failure (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">12</xref>). When the AFE was tested with a commercial cathode with a high mass loading of 21.6&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>2</sup>, the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM622 coin cell show a 72.3% capacity retention after 200 cycles at 95&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5a</xref>). The voltage profiles of different cycle numbers show that the polarization in the AFE is much smaller than that in the BE (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5b</xref> and c). The charge transfer resistance (R<sub>ct</sub>) and cathode electrolyte interphase resistance (R<sub>CEI</sub>) of the fresh Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM622 cell with the AFE are almost the same as that with the BE. But after the 60th cycle, both the R<sub>CEI</sub> (33.9 Ohms) and R<sub>ct</sub> (36.1 Ohms) of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM622 cell with the AFE (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">13a</xref>) dramatically decrease while those with the BE (R<sub>CEI</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;101.8 Ohms, R<sub>ct</sub>&#x02009;=&#x02009;91.8 Ohms) significantly increase (Supplementary Figure&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">13b</xref> and Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">1</xref>). This indicates that the AFE electrolyte may improve the stability of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM cells. To investigate the effect of the environmental temperature on the cycling behaviour of the cells assembled with various electrolytes, we tested several Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM622 cells in the 30&#x02013;60&#x02009;&#x000b0;C range (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">14</xref>). The Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM622 full cell with the BE presents fast capacity attenuation and fluctuations in coulombic efficiency at 40&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. In contrast, the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM622 full cell with the FE can cycle steadily at 50&#x02009;&#x000b0;C but shows a rapid decrease in capacity and coulombic efficiency at 60&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. This behaviour indicates that the addition of FEC can improve the electrochemical energy storage performances of the coin cells at temperatures &#x0003e;&#x000a0;30&#x02009;&#x000b0;C. In addition, the cycling performance of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM622 full cell with the AFE is much better than that with the BE and FE, which confirms that the addition of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> can further promote the thermal stability of carbonate electrolyte. When using a high-loading cathode, lean electrolyte condition and thin lithium metal anode, it is a great challenge to obtain a satisfactory cycle life. In the AFE, full coin cells with a high-loading NCM811 cathode (~4&#x02009;mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;2</sup>), thin Li foil (41&#x02009;&#x003bc;m, N/P ratio of ~2.13) (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">15</xref>) and limited electrolyte (E/C ratio of ~3.4&#x02009;g Ah<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) can stably cycle 130 times at discharge/charge rates of 60&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>/20&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> and 4.5&#x02009;V, while those with the BE rapidly degrade within 60 cycles (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5d</xref>). In addition, the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM811 cells with the BE exhibit an increase in polarization (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5e</xref>). In comparison, the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM811 cells with the AFE exhibit lower polarization and higher capacity retention (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5f</xref>). It is worth mentioning that the charge voltage plateau at 4.2&#x02009;V is an intrinsic property of NCM811<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref></sup> rather than being due to the decomposition of electrolyte. No oxidation current peaks from the 3 to 5&#x02009;V are observed in the linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) results of the BE and AFE (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">16</xref>). The calculated specific energy of the Li|AFE&#x02009;|&#x02009;NCM811 coin cell is 356.23&#x02009;Wh&#x02009;kg<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> without considering the packing material<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref></sup> (Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">2</xref>). To further illustrate the advantages of our technology in practical applications, we calculated the energy density of an 18650 cell with our own parameters (346.1&#x02009;Wh&#x02009;kg<sup>&#x02212;1</sup>) according to a reported method (Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">3</xref>)<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR52">52</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR53">53</xref></sup>. The calculated specific energy values are well aligned with other results reported in the literature (Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">4</xref>).<fig id="Fig5"><label>Fig. 5</label><caption><title>Electrochemical energy storage of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM cells with different electrolytes.</title><p>Cycling stability (<bold>a</bold>) and corresponding voltage profiles of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM622 cells using the BE (<bold>b</bold>) and AFE (<bold>c</bold>) at a 4.3&#x02009;V cut-off voltage. The discharging/charging current were 19&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>/19&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> (0.1&#x02009;C/0.1&#x02009;C) for the first three cycles and 95&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>/95&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> (0.5&#x02009;C/0.5&#x02009;C) afterwards. Cycling stability (<bold>d</bold>) and corresponding voltage profiles of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM811 cells using the BE (<bold>e</bold>) and AFE (<bold>f</bold>) at a 4.5&#x02009;V cut-off voltage, and the discharging/charging current were 60&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>/20&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> (0.3&#x02009;C/0.1&#x02009;C).</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2022_28959_Fig5_HTML" id="d32e1579"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Ex-situ postmortem physicochemical characterizations of the NCM-based electrodes</title><p id="Par14">To understand the cycling stability mechanisms of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM622 full cells, we further characterized the cycled NCM622 cathodes (charged and discharged between 3.0 and 4.3&#x02009;V at 95&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> for 100 cycles, and the voltage of the cell was 3.0&#x02009;V before disassembly) with high mass loading in different electrolytes (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>). Severe cracks are observed in the NCM622 primary particles and many small fragments are observed in the NCM622 secondary particles with the BE (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6a-c</xref>, Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">17a</xref>). The fractured particles in the whole electrode generate a large interfacial area to further facilitate electrolyte decomposition and result in capacity fading during cycling. In contrast, the cycled NCM622 cathode in the AFE remains intact without cracking (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6d-f</xref>, Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">17b and c</xref>). The transmission electron microscopy (TEM) images of NCM622 cycled in the BE show a thick CEI (~25&#x02009;nm) mixed with broken particles (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6g</xref>). In contrast, a much thinner CEI (&#x02009;&#x0003c;&#x02009;10&#x02009;nm) without broken particles is observed in the AFE (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6h</xref>). We therefore conclude that a robust and Al-rich CEI that is formed in the AFE suppresses the cracking of NCM622 particles. We compared the X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns of the cathodes cycled in the BE and AFE. The peaks corresponding to the (003) interplanar crystal interplanar are shifted to a lower 2&#x02010;theta degree in the AFE (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6i</xref>). This means Al<sup>3+</sup> may enter the lattice of NCM622. The electronegativity of aluminum is smaller than that of cobalt; additionally, the substitution of cobalt by aluminum will increase the charge density of oxygen and electrostatic repulsion between oxygen, resulting in an increase in the interplanar spacing<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR54">54</xref></sup>. In addition, the separation of the (006)/(102) and (108)/(110) peaks (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6j</xref> and k) also comes from the influence of Al<sup>3+</sup> on the crystal structure of NCM622<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR55">55</xref></sup>. The XPS (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6l</xref>) and energy dispersive spectroscopy (EDS) (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">17d-f</xref>) results confirm that the Al-O (75.7&#x02009;eV) composition including Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> is evenly distributed on the surface of the NCM622 particles. The total Al content remains at 4.0% of all elements and does not change much with the etching depth (Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">18</xref>), further indicating uniform distribution of Al-O in the CEI film. The detailed C 1&#x02009;<italic>s</italic>, O 1&#x02009;<italic>s</italic> and F 1&#x02009;<italic>s</italic> XPS spectra of the CEI are shown in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">19</xref>. TOF-SIMS was also performed to provide more information about the composition of the CEI (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6m</xref> and n, Supplementary Figs.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">20</xref> and <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">21</xref>). Similar to the LMA, the aluminum-containing species are in close contact with NCM622. More aluminum-containing species and LiF<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> are formed owing to the uniform coating on the NCM622 particles and the decomposition of electrolyte components at high voltage. It could be speculated that the inhibition of the surface morphology evolution and phase transformation is due to the doped Al<sup>3+</sup> forming a robust, Al-rich CEI.<fig id="Fig6"><label>Fig. 6</label><caption><title>Physicochemical characterization of the cycled high-loading NCM622 cathodes with different electrolytes.</title><p>SEM images of the NCM622 cathode surface after 100 cycles in the BE (<bold>a</bold>) and AFE (<bold>d</bold>). SEM images of the NCM622 cathodes cross-sectioned after 100 cycles in the BE (<bold>b</bold> and <bold>c</bold>) and AFE (<bold>e</bold> and <bold>f</bold>). TEM analyses of the NCM622 particles after 100 cycles in the BE (<bold>g</bold>) and AFE (<bold>h</bold>). XRD of the NCM622 cathodes (<bold>i</bold>&#x02013;<bold>k</bold>) before and after 100 cycles in the BE and AFE. XPS spectra of the Al 2&#x000a0;<italic>p</italic> (<bold>l</bold>) spectrum of the NCM622 cathodes in the AFE. TOF-SIMS 3D reconstruction of the sputtered volume (<bold>m</bold>) and the depth profiling of several secondary ion fragments (<bold>n</bold>) of Al<sup>+</sup>, AlO<sub>2</sub>C<sub>2</sub>HF<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, LiF<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>, AlO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>, AlO<sub>2</sub>C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> and C<sub>2</sub>HO<sup>&#x02212;</sup> on the NCM622 surface after 100 cycles. All the cells were charged and discharged between 3.0 and 4.3&#x02009;V at 95&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;1</sup> for 100 cycles, and the voltage of the cell was 3.0&#x02009;V before disassembly.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2022_28959_Fig6_HTML" id="d32e1778"/></fig></p><p id="Par15">The cycled NCM811 cathodes (charged and discharged between 3.0 and 4.5&#x02009;V at 60&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> for 50 cycles, and the voltage of the cell was 3.0&#x02009;V before disassembly) with high mass loading in different electrolytes were also characterized via ex-situ postmortem electrode measurements and analyses to clarify the cycling stability mechanisms of the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM811 full batteries (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref>). Cracks can be observed in the surface and cross-section of the cathode cycled with the BE (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7a-c</xref>). The surfaces of the cathodes with AFE show a protective layer, which can effectively inhibit side reactions at the interphase and reduce the formation of internal cracks (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7d</xref>). It can be seen from the cross-section SEM micrographs that the NCM811 particles remain intact with no cracks (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7e</xref> and f). The TEM image shows that a thick (~17&#x02009;nm) and nonuniform CEI containing broken particles are formed in the BE (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7g</xref>). In contrast, the CEI in the AFE has a thinner and more uniform thickness (~8&#x02009;nm) and does not contain any NCM fragments (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7h</xref>). The structural change of the NCM811 cathode with the BE and AFE after 50 cycles was examined by XRD. As shown in Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7i-k</xref>, the (003) peak in the AFE does not shift to a lower 2&#x02010;theta degree, indicating that the influence of Al-doping on the NCM811 cathode is less than that of NCM622, which may be related to the different crystal structures of NCM811 and NCM622. Correspondingly, the separation of the (006)/(102) and (108)/(110) peaks in the AFE is closer to that in the fresh cathode, showing improved structural stability compared to that in the BE<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR56">56</xref></sup>. Similar to NCM622, XPS confirms that the Al-O (75.7&#x02009;eV) composition including Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>, is evenly distributed on the surface of the NCM811 particles (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7l</xref>, Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">22a</xref>). The detailed F 1&#x02009;<italic>s</italic>, O 1&#x02009;<italic>s</italic>, and C 1&#x02009;<italic>s</italic> XPS spectra of the CEI are shown in Supplementary Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">22b-d</xref>. The TOF-SIMS results show that the inner layer of the CEI is rich in aluminum-containing species, which is similar to that of NCM622. (Fig.&#x000a0;<xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7m</xref> and n, Supplementary Figs.&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">23</xref> and <xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">24</xref>).<fig id="Fig7"><label>Fig. 7</label><caption><title>Physicochemical characterization of the cycled high-loading NCM811 cathodes with different electrolytes.</title><p>SEM images of the NCM811 cathode surface after 50 cycles in the BE (<bold>a</bold>) and AFE (<bold>d</bold>). SEM images of the NCM811 cathodes cross-sectioned after 50 cycles in the BE (<bold>b</bold> and <bold>c</bold>) and AFE (<bold>e</bold> and <bold>f</bold>). TEM analyses of the NCM811 particles after 50 cycles in the BE (<bold>g</bold>) and AFE (<bold>h</bold>). XRD of the NCM811 cathodes (<bold>i</bold>&#x02013;<bold>k</bold>) before and after 50 cycles in the BE and AFE. Al 2&#x000a0;<italic>p</italic> (<bold>l</bold>) XPS spectra of the NCM811 cathodes in the AFE. TOF-SIMS 3D reconstruction of the sputtered volume (<bold>m</bold>) and the depth profiling of several secondary ion fragments (<bold>n</bold>) of Al<sup>+</sup>, AlO<sub>2</sub>C<sub>2</sub>HF<sup>&#x02212;</sup>, LiF<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>, AlO<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup>, AlO<sub>2</sub>C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>2</sub><sup>&#x02212;</sup> and C<sub>2</sub>HO<sup>&#x02212;</sup> on the NCM811 surface after 50 cycles. All the cells were charged and discharged between 3.0 and 4.5&#x02009;V at 60&#x02009;mA&#x02009;g<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> for 50 cycles, and the voltage of the cell was 3.0&#x02009;V before disassembly.</p></caption><graphic xlink:href="41467_2022_28959_Fig7_HTML" id="d32e1947"/></fig></p><p id="Par16">To summarize, we developed a dual-function electrolyte through polymerization reaction between Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and FEC, which facilitates the formation of robust and ionically conductive protective interphases on both the LMA and NCM cathode. On the LMA side, the SEI with its uniform Al metal and Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> distribution, allow a more uniform transport and deposition of Li<sup>+</sup>, and results in the formation of densely packed Li. On the NCM cathode side, the CEI containing Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> mitigates the problem of structural deterioration. Therefore, under practical conditions (NCM811 loading is ~4.0 mAh cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>2</sup>, E/C and N/P ratio are 3.4&#x02009;g Ah<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> and 2.13, respectively), the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM811 cell exhibits a high capacity retention of 80.3% after 130 cycles, and the calculated energy density is approximately 350&#x02009;Wh&#x02009;kg<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Methods</title><sec id="Sec10"><title>Materials</title><p id="Par17">The commercial Li[Ni<sub>0.6</sub>Co<sub>0.2</sub>Mn<sub>0.2</sub>]O<sub>2</sub> (NCM622) electrode (cathode loading is 21.6&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>2</sup> (active material ratio is 96.5 wt.%, the thickness is 70 &#x003bc;m) and the commercial Li[Ni<sub>0.8</sub>Co<sub>0.1</sub>Mn<sub>0.1</sub>]O<sub>2</sub> (NCM811) electrode (cathode loading is 21.5&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>2</sup>, active material ratio is 94.5 wt.%, the thickness is 70&#x02009;&#x003bc;m) were provided by Guangdong Canrd New Energy Technology Co., Ltd. The NCM622 cathode with mass loading of 2.4&#x02009;mg&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>2</sup> was prepared by following steps. The mixture of 80 wt.% NCM622 powder, 10 wt.% acetylene black and 10 wt.% polyvinylidene difluoride (PVDF) was manually grinded in an agate mortar for 30&#x02009;mins and then dissolved in N-methyl-2-pyrrolidone (NMP) by stirring for 4&#x02009;h to form a slurry. The electrode slurry was then pasted on Al foil (99.35%, 16 &#x003bc;m, HF-Kejing Co., Ltd., China) and dried at 80&#x02009;&#x000b0;C under vacuum for 12&#x02009;h. The basic electrolyte (BE) (1&#x02009;M LiPF<sub>6</sub> in ethylene carbonate (EC) and diethyl carbonate (DEC) (1:1 by volume) (H<sub>2</sub>O&#x02009;&#x0003c;&#x02009;10 ppm)) and fluoroethylene carbonate (FEC) (H<sub>2</sub>O&#x02009;&#x0003c;&#x02009;10 ppm) came from Suzhou Qianmin Chemical Reagent Company. All materials were used as received.</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Preparation of the Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>-containing functional electrolyte (AFE)</title><p id="Par18">The production details of the Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> nanowires are as follows<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR37">37</xref></sup>. A graphite crucible with aluminum powder (0.3&#x02009;g) and Li particles (0.085&#x02009;g) (1:1 atom ratio) was heated at 800&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 30&#x02009;min in a muffle furnace and naturally cooled to obtain a Li-Al alloy plate. The alloy plate was polished and reacted with ethanol at 60&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 30&#x02009;h to obtain an Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> nanowire gel. To prepare the AFE, 0.4 wt.% Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> nanowires and 5 vol.% FEC were added into BE and then treated with ultrasonication (DTC-15J, the power of the ultrasound was 150&#x02009;W) at 35&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 3&#x02009;h before use. The Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> nanowires were dispersed in the electrolyte solution. The costs of reagents for preparing Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> are shown in Supplementary Table&#x000a0;<xref rid="MOESM1" ref-type="media">5</xref>. For comparison, an FEC-containing electrolyte (FE) was prepared by adding 5 vol.% FEC in to the BE. To explore the reaction mechanism of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and FEC, two electrolyte solutions with different concentrations were prepared. One sample was made by adding 40&#x02009;mg of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> to 1&#x02009;mL of FEC reagent (Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/FEC), while the other sample was prepared by adding 40&#x02009;mg of Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub> and 152&#x02009;mg of LiPF<sub>6</sub> salt (99.9%, Suzhou Qianmin Chemical Reagent Company) into 1&#x02009;mL of FEC reagent (Al(EtO)<sub>3</sub>/LiPF<sub>6</sub>/FEC). The two solutions were sonicated (DTC-15J, the ultrasound power of 150&#x02009;W) at 35&#x02009;&#x000b0;C for 3&#x02009;h and then allowed to homogenize for five days.</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Fabrication of the cells</title><p id="Par19">The NCM622 cathode (diameter of 12&#x02009;mm, thickness of 70 &#x003bc;m), matching commercial Li metal anode (99.95%, 400 &#x003bc;m, China Energy Lithium Co., Ltd.), the NCM811 cathode (diameter of 12&#x02009;mm, thickness of 70 &#x003bc;m) matching the thin Li metal anode (~40&#x02009;&#x003bc;m, rolled from 400 &#x003bc;m commercial Li metal anode by hand), separator (Celgard 2500 porous polypropylene film) were assembled into CR2032 coin cells in an Ar-filled glove box (Mikrouna) (H<sub>2</sub>O&#x02009;&#x0003c;&#x02009;0.1 ppm, O<sub>2</sub>&#x02009;&#x0003c;&#x02009;0.1 ppm). The amounts of electrolyte injected were 60 and 12&#x02009;&#x003bc;L for the Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM622 and Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|NCM811 coin cells, respectively. The Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Li and Li&#x02009;|&#x02009;|Cu (9&#x02009;&#x003bc;m Cu metal foil with a purity of 99.8% came from Guangdong Canrd New Energy Technology Co., Ltd.) coin cells were assembled using the same method with 30&#x02009;&#x003bc;L of electrolyte. All the cells were tested with freshly prepared electrolyte solutions.</p></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Physicochemical measurements</title><p id="Par20">The morphology and composition of the materials were analyzed using scanning electron microscopy (SEM, Auriga-4523, Zeiss, Germany) and transmission electron microscopy (TEM,&#x000a0;FEI Tecnai G2 F30) at an acceleration of 300&#x02009;kV. The surface chemical state of the cathodes was analyzed through X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS, ESCALab250), and the etching times were 0, 10, 60, 120, 180, 240, 360 and 480&#x02009;s. Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy was performed with a NICOLET 6700 instrument (Thermo, America) at a resolution of 0.2&#x02009;cm<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup>. Solid-state NMR spectroscopy was performed at 25&#x02009;&#x000b0;C and spun at 12&#x02009;kHz on a Bruker AVANCE 400 superconducting Fourier transform nuclear magnetic resonance instrument. Differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) and thermogravimetric analysis (TGA) were performed at a heating rate of 10&#x02009;&#x000b0;C min<sup>&#x02212;</sup><sup>1</sup> in a N<sub>2</sub> atmosphere with a PerkinElmer Pyris Diamond TG/DTA thermal analyzer. X-ray diffraction (XRD) was conducted with an Empyrean powder X-ray diffractometer using a Cu K&#x003b1; radiation source. Atomic force microscopy (AFM) measurements were performed with a Bruker Dimension Fastscan instrument. Time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS) was performed with a PHI nanoTOF II times-of-flight SIMS instrument. Prior to analysis, the cells were disassembled in Ar-filled glove box (Mikrouna) (H<sub>2</sub>O&#x02009;&#x0003c;&#x02009;0.1 ppm, O<sub>2</sub>&#x02009;&#x0003c;&#x02009;0.1 ppm) and the electrode surfaces were rinsed with 1&#x02009;mL of Diethyl carbonate (DEC, 99.98%, H<sub>2</sub>O&#x02009;&#x0003c;&#x02009;10 ppm, Suzhou Qianmin Chemical Reagent Company). After drying at 25&#x02009;&#x000b0;C under vacuum for 3&#x02009;h, the electrodes were transferred by the transfer sample holder (Thermo Fisher Scientific) with an Ar-filled or the vacuum container (in-house produced) to isolate the air.</p></sec><sec id="Sec14"><title>Electrochemical characterizations</title><p id="Par21">To obtain the cycling and rate performance of the fabricated coin cells, they were placed in an incubator to maintain a constant operating temperature of 30&#x000b1;1&#x02009;&#x000b0;C and measured at with a battery test system (LAND CT-2001A, Land Electronic Co., Ltd., Wuhan). Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) was performed at 30&#x02009;&#x000b0;C with an electrochemical workstation (IVIUM Vertex. One. EIS) (potentiostatic mode ranged from 10 mHz to 100&#x02009;kHz at an amplitude of 5&#x02009;mV, 10 data points per decade, and the open-circuit voltage time applied before carrying out the EIS measurements was 30&#x02009;s).</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary information</title><sec id="Sec15"><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1"><media xlink:href="41467_2022_28959_MOESM1_ESM.pdf"><caption><p>Supplementary information</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher&#x02019;s note</bold> Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><sec><title>Supplementary information</title><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41467-022-28959-5.</p></sec><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>This work was supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Nos. 51972351, 51802361) (D.N.L.), Guangdong Basic and Applied Basic Research Foundation (No. 2019B151502045) (D.N.L.), the Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities of China (No. 19lgpy06) (D.N.L.).</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>D.N.L. and C.X.W. conceived and supervised the project. D.N.L. and Y.J.Z. designed the experiments. Y.J.Z. performed the experiments with the help from Y.W., H.Y.L. and J.H.C. Y.J.Z., D.N.L. and C.X.W. discussed the results and wrote the initial paper which was approved by all the authors.</p></notes><notes notes-type="peer-review"><title>Peer review</title><sec id="FPar1"><title>Peer review information</title><p id="Par22"><italic>Nature Communications</italic> thanks the anonymous, reviewer(s) for their contribution to the peer review of this work.</p></sec></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>The data that support the findings of this study are included in the paper and its Supplementary Information.</p></notes><notes id="FPar2" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par23">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Armand</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Tarascon</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Building better batteries</article-title><source>Nature</source><year>2008</year><volume>451</volume><fpage>652</fpage><lpage>657</lpage><?supplied-pmid 18256660?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18256660</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Nitta</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>JT</given-names></name><name><surname>Yushin</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Li-ion battery materials: present and future</article-title><source>Mater. Today</source><year>2015</year><volume>18</volume><fpage>252</fpage><lpage>264</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Layered reduced graphene oxide with nanoscale interlayer gaps as a stable host for lithium metal anodes</article-title><source>Nat. Nanotechnol.</source><year>2016</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>626</fpage><lpage>632</lpage><?supplied-pmid 26999479?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26999479</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tarascon</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Armand</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Issues and challenges facing rechargeable lithium batteries</article-title><source>Nature</source><year>2001</year><volume>414</volume><fpage>359</fpage><lpage>367</lpage><?supplied-pmid 11713543?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11713543</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>JG</given-names></name><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name><surname>Xiao</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Lithium metal anodes with nonaqueous electrolytes</article-title><source>Chem. Rev.</source><year>2020</year><volume>120</volume><fpage>13312</fpage><lpage>13348</lpage><?supplied-pmid 33174427?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33174427</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Han</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>500 Wh kg<sup>(-1)</sup> class Li metal battery enabled by a self-organized core-shell composite anode</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2020</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>e2004793</fpage><?supplied-pmid 32930460?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32930460</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Reviving the lithium metal anode for high-energy batteries</article-title><source>Nat. Nanotechnol.</source><year>2017</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>194</fpage><lpage>206</lpage><?supplied-pmid 28265117?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28265117</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Synergistic dual-additive electrolyte enables practical lithium-metal batteries</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed.</source><year>2020</year><volume>59</volume><fpage>14935</fpage><lpage>14941</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Niu</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>High-energy lithium metal pouch cells with limited anode swelling and long stable cycles</article-title><source>Nat. Energy</source><year>2019</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>551</fpage><lpage>559</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ren</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Enabling high-voltage lithium-metal batteries under practical conditions</article-title><source>Joule</source><year>2019</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>1662</fpage><lpage>1676</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Colossal granular lithium deposits enabled by the grain-coarsening effect for high-efficiency lithium metal full batteries</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2020</year><volume>32</volume><fpage>e2001740</fpage><?supplied-pmid 32390225?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32390225</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Monolithic solid&#x02013;electrolyte interphases formed in fluorinated orthoformate-based electrolytes minimize Li depletion and pulverization</article-title><source>Nat. Energy</source><year>2019</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>796</fpage><lpage>805</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yoon</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Reactive boride infusion stabilizes Ni-rich cathodes for lithium-ion batteries</article-title><source>Nat. Energy</source><year>2021</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>362</fpage><lpage>371</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A dynamic, electrolyte-blocking, and single-ion-conductive network for stable lithium-metal anodes</article-title><source>Joule</source><year>2019</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>2761</fpage><lpage>2776</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Bae</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Polar polymer&#x02013;solvent interaction derived favorable interphase for stable lithium metal batteries</article-title><source>Energy Environ. Sci.</source><year>2019</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>3319</fpage><lpage>3327</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Molecular design for electrolyte solvents enabling energy-dense and long-cycling lithium metal batteries</article-title><source>Nat. Energy</source><year>2020</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>526</fpage><lpage>533</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Lithium nitrate regulated sulfone electrolytes for lithium metal batteries</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed.</source><year>2020</year><volume>59</volume><fpage>22194</fpage><lpage>22201</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Gradient solid electrolyte interphase and lithium-ion solvation regulated by bisfluoroacetamide for stable lithium metal batteries</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed.</source><year>2021</year><volume>60</volume><fpage>6600</fpage><lpage>6608</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yamada</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Ko</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Yamada</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Advances and issues in developing salt-concentrated battery electrolytes</article-title><source>Nat. Energy</source><year>2019</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>269</fpage><lpage>280</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Highly fluorinated interphases enable high-voltage Li-metal batteries</article-title><source>Chem</source><year>2018</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>174</fpage><lpage>185</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>High-voltage lithium-metal batteries enabled by localized high-concentration electrolytes</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2018</year><volume>30</volume><fpage>e1706102</fpage><?supplied-pmid 29575163?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29575163</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>All-temperature batteries enabled by fluorinated electrolytes with non-polar solvents</article-title><source>Nat. Energy</source><year>2019</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>882</fpage><lpage>890</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Amanchukwu</surname><given-names>CV</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A new class of ionically conducting fluorinated ether electrolytes with high electrochemical stability</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2020</year><volume>142</volume><fpage>7393</fpage><lpage>7403</lpage><?supplied-pmid 32233433?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32233433</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Ultra-high-voltage Ni-rich layered cathodes in practical Li metal batteries enabled by a sulfonamide-based electrolyte</article-title><source>Nat. Energy</source><year>2021</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>495</fpage><lpage>505</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zeng</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Non-flammable electrolytes with high salt-to-solvent ratios for Li-ion and Li-metal batteries</article-title><source>Nat. Energy</source><year>2018</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>674</fpage><lpage>681</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name><surname>Lu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Amine</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Bridging the academic and industrial metrics for next-generation practical batteries</article-title><source>Nat. Nanotechnol.</source><year>2019</year><volume>14</volume><fpage>200</fpage><lpage>207</lpage><?supplied-pmid 30778215?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30778215</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Tikekar</surname><given-names>MD</given-names></name><name><surname>Choudhury</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Tu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Archer</surname><given-names>LA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Design principles for electrolytes and interfaces for stable lithium-metal batteries</article-title><source>Nat. Energy</source><year>2016</year><volume>1</volume><fpage>16114</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Schmuch</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name><surname>H&#x000f6;rpel</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Placke</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name><surname>Winter</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Performance and cost of materials for lithium-based rechargeable automotive batteries</article-title><source>Nat. Energy</source><year>2018</year><volume>3</volume><fpage>267</fpage><lpage>278</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Qiao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Visualizing ion diffusion in battery systems by fluorescence microscopy: A case study on the dissolution of LiMn<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub></article-title><source>Nano Energy</source><year>2018</year><volume>45</volume><fpage>68</fpage><lpage>74</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Fan</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Enabling stable lithium metal anode via 3D inorganic skeleton with superlithiophilic interphase</article-title><source>Adv. Energy Mater.</source><year>2018</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>1802350</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Natural SEI-Inspired dual-protective layers via atomic/molecular layer deposition for long-life metallic lithium anode</article-title><source>Matter</source><year>2019</year><volume>1</volume><fpage>1215</fpage><lpage>1231</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Kazyak</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name><surname>Wood</surname><given-names>KN</given-names></name><name><surname>Dasgupta</surname><given-names>NP</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Improved cycle life and stability of lithium metal anodes through ultrathin atomic layer deposition surface treatments</article-title><source>Chem. Mater.</source><year>2015</year><volume>27</volume><fpage>6457</fpage><lpage>6462</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Long lifespan lithium metal anodes enabled by Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> sputter coating</article-title><source>Energy Stor. Mater.</source><year>2018</year><volume>10</volume><fpage>16</fpage><lpage>23</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR34"><label>34.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liao</surname><given-names>J-Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Manthiram</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Surface-modified concentration-gradient Ni-rich layered oxide cathodes for high-energy lithium-ion batteries</article-title><source>J. Power Sources</source><year>2015</year><volume>282</volume><fpage>429</fpage><lpage>436</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR35"><label>35.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Significantly improving cycling performance of cathodes in lithium ion batteries: The effect of Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> and LiAlO<sub>2</sub> coatings on LiNi<sub>0.6</sub>Co<sub>0.2</sub>Mn<sub>0.2</sub>O<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>Nano Energy</source><year>2018</year><volume>44</volume><fpage>111</fpage><lpage>120</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR36"><label>36.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Balaish</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Processing thin but robust electrolytes for solid-state batteries</article-title><source>Nat. Energy</source><year>2021</year><volume>6</volume><fpage>227</fpage><lpage>239</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR37"><label>37.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Lei</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Benson</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name><surname>Magasinski</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Berdichevsky</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Yushin</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Transformation of bulk alloys to oxide nanowires</article-title><source>Science</source><year>2017</year><volume>355</volume><fpage>267</fpage><lpage>270</lpage><?supplied-pmid 28104885?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28104885</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR38"><label>38.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Mechanisms of transformation of bulk aluminum-lithium alloys to aluminum metal-organic nanowires</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2018</year><volume>140</volume><fpage>12493</fpage><lpage>12500</lpage><?supplied-pmid 30189731?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30189731</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR39"><label>39.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name><surname>Baiker</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name><surname>Huang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Pentacoordinated aluminum species: New frontier for tailoring acidity-enhanced silica-alumina catalysts</article-title><source>Acc. Chem. Res.</source><year>2020</year><volume>53</volume><fpage>2648</fpage><lpage>2658</lpage><?supplied-pmid 33090765?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33090765</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR40"><label>40.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Understanding fluoroethylene carbonate and vinylene carbonate based electrolytes for Si anodes in lithium ion batteries with NMR spectroscopy</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2018</year><volume>140</volume><fpage>9854</fpage><lpage>9867</lpage><?supplied-pmid 29979869?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29979869</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR41"><label>41.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Electrolytes and interphases in Li-ion batteries and beyond</article-title><source>Chem. Rev.</source><year>2014</year><volume>114</volume><fpage>11503</fpage><lpage>11618</lpage><?supplied-pmid 25351820?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25351820</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR42"><label>42.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>An artificial solid electrolyte interphase with high Li-ion conductivity, mechanical strength, and flexibility for stable lithium metal anodes</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><year>2017</year><volume>29</volume><fpage>1605531</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR43"><label>43.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Immunizing lithium metal anodes against dendrite growth using protein molecules to achieve high energy batteries</article-title><source>Nat. Commun.</source><year>2020</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>5429</fpage><?supplied-pmid 33110084?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33110084</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR44"><label>44.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Yan</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Architecting a stable high-energy aqueous Al-ion battery</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2020</year><volume>142</volume><fpage>15295</fpage><lpage>15304</lpage><?supplied-pmid 32786747?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32786747</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR45"><label>45.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Jurng</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Heiskanen</surname><given-names>SK</given-names></name><name><surname>Chandrasiri</surname><given-names>KWDK</given-names></name><name><surname>Abeywardana</surname><given-names>MY</given-names></name><name><surname>Lucht</surname><given-names>BL</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Minimized metal dissolution from high-energy nickel cobalt manganese oxide cathodes with Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> coating and its effects on electrolyte decomposition on graphite anodes</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2019</year><volume>166</volume><fpage>A2721</fpage><lpage>A2726</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR46"><label>46.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Porous Al/Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> two-phase nanonetwork to improve electrochemical properties of porous C/SiO<sub>2</sub> as anode for Li-ion batteries</article-title><source>Electrochim. Acta</source><year>2019</year><volume>300</volume><fpage>470</fpage><lpage>481</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR47"><label>47.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Uniform high ionic conducting lithium sulfide protection layer for stable lithium metal anode</article-title><source>Adv. Energy Mater.</source><year>2019</year><volume>9</volume><fpage>1900858</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR48"><label>48.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Electroless formation of a fluorinated Li/Na hybrid interphase for robust lithium anodes</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><year>2021</year><volume>143</volume><fpage>2829</fpage><lpage>2837</lpage><?supplied-pmid 33587623?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33587623</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR49"><label>49.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Ye</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Guiding uniform Li plating/stripping through lithium-aluminum alloying medium for long-life Li metal batteries</article-title><source>Angew. Chem. Int. Ed.</source><year>2019</year><volume>58</volume><fpage>1094</fpage><lpage>1099</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR50"><label>50.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Luo</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Constructing multifunctional solid electrolyte interface via in-situ polymerization for dendrite-free and low N/P ratio lithium metal batteries</article-title><source>Nat. Commun.</source><year>2021</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>186</fpage><?supplied-pmid 33420036?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33420036</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR51"><label>51.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Popovic</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The importance of electrode interfaces and interphases for rechargeable metal batteries</article-title><source>Nat. Commun.</source><year>2021</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>6240</fpage><?supplied-pmid 34716340?><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34716340</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR52"><label>52.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Park</surname><given-names>S-H</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>High areal capacity battery electrodes enabled by segregated nanotube networks</article-title><source>Nat. Energy</source><year>2019</year><volume>4</volume><fpage>560</fpage><lpage>567</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR53"><label>53.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Berg</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name><name><surname>Villevieille</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name><surname>Streich</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name><surname>Trabesinger</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name><surname>Nov&#x000e1;k</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Rechargeable batteries: Grasping for the limits of chemistry</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2015</year><volume>162</volume><fpage>A2468</fpage><lpage>A2475</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR54"><label>54.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Croguennec</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Effect of aluminum substitution on the structure, slectrochemical performance and thermal stability of Li<sub>1+x</sub>(Ni<sub>0.40</sub>Mn<sub>0.40</sub>Co<sub>0.20&#x02212;z</sub>Al<sub>z</sub>)<sub>1&#x02212;x</sub>O<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><year>2011</year><volume>158</volume><fpage>A664</fpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR55"><label>55.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Synthesis and characterization of Al-substituted LiNi<sub>0.5</sub>Co<sub>0.2</sub>Mn<sub>0.3</sub>O<sub>2</sub> cathode materials by a modified co-precipitation method</article-title><source>RSC Adv.</source><year>2017</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>37588</fpage><lpage>37595</lpage></element-citation></ref><ref id="CR56"><label>56.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name><surname>Li</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Mn versus Al in layered oxide cathodes in lithium&#x02010;ion batteries: A comprehensive evaluation on long&#x02010;term cyclability</article-title><source>Adv. Energy Mater.</source><year>2018</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>1703154</fpage></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>